<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-12-14T19:15:48+01:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Sterling Coleman</title><subtitle>A space for my personal projects and thoughts</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">USA at the World Cup</title><link href="/blog/2022/12/usa-world-cup.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="USA at the World Cup" /><published>2022-12-14T09:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-12-14T09:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2022/12/usa-world-cup</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2022/12/usa-world-cup.html">&lt;p&gt;For a long time, I, along with many other American soccer fans, have been watching anxiously as the USA has gone through the qualification phase for the 2022 FIFA World Cup. Every American fan has been looking forward to putting the failure of the 2018 qualification campaign behind them, and to start anew with a young team looking to qualify for the world’s most important soccer tournament.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I actually think that in some ways the qualification process is just as, if not more, fun than the actual World Cup. This is mostly because there are more teams competing, and the qualification phase lasts longer. This makes for pretty interesting discussion. Therefore it was a lot of fun to see Canada master their qualification campaign, never losing a match. The USA also played well, beating out rivals Mexico at home, and playing well at Azteca Stadium in a scoreless draw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The USA qualified on the final day, though not without losing their final match to Costa Rica, and finishing in third place, behind both Canada and Mexico. From there, the American team played in the CONCACAF Nations League in June, beating Grenada, and scoring late in El Salvador to earn a draw. Though these matches were not against teams that would be playing in the World Cup, the USA got an opportunity to play teams at that level in September, facing off against Japan and Saudi Arabia in a pair of friendly matches. Unfortunately, neither game was a success, with a loss to Japan and a draw against the Saudis being the final matches the team would play before playing in the World Cup. The hopes of American fans were slightly diminished heading into the all-important first match against Wales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that match, I rejoiced as I watched Christian Pulisic play a great ball in on goal for Timo Weah, who finished his chance and put us up 1-0 over the Welsh. I later despaired as I watched Gareth Bale convert a penalty kick to even the game up. We failed to close the door on the Welsh, and we left ourselves a lot of work to do to get out of the group phase, which was our goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our second match, we faced a strong opponent in England. Oddly enough, because of the way the math worked out, it would not have been a big deal if we lost the match. Therefore I was surprised to see us put out our best players to start the match, and even more surprised to watch us play just as well as the English, if not better. It was a good feeling to avoid losing to England, keeping alive our streak of never losing to England in a FIFA World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our final group match was Iran. It was win, or go home. Iran had beaten Wales in the final minutes of the match, and only needed a draw to advance. We would have to score a goal on a team that could afford to play as defensively as possible if they liked. It was a great game, with lots of energy and emotion. Christian Pulisic showed his quality and leadership, sacrificing his body to get the ball across the goal line and put us up 1-0 near the end of the first half. We were able to hold on, and beat Iran, advancing out of the group and on to the Round of 16.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next match didn’t go so well. We were up against the Netherlands, a team that many saw as a weaker team than the likes of some of the best teams in the tournament. They were a pretty good side nonetheless. In the game against the Dutch, we seemed worn out after having fought hard for our advancement out of the group stage. We had our chances, but weren’t able to capitalize. The Netherlands punished us for defensive mistakes, and beat us 3-1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see a lot of Americans happy with our performance in the tournament, but talking about how we’re gunning for a semifinal finish or better in the 2026 World Cup, which we are co-hosting with Mexico and Canada. Personally, I’m not ready to talk about 2026 yet, and I think that we have a lot to be proud of in advancing out of our group, which is something plenty of teams failed to do, including every other team from North America, as well as some of the best teams in the tournament, such as Belgium, Germany, and Denmark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This World Cup was a reassuring moment for the USA. We showed that we belong at the World Cup, and that we belong in the list of the best 16 teams in this tournament. Obviously, getting to the quarterfinals would have been amazing, but it is still gratifying to see us consistently getting to the Round of 16 (excluding 2018, when we didn’t qualify). There are a lot of reasons to look forward to the future of this team and of this sport in USA.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">For a long time, I, along with many other American soccer fans, have been watching anxiously as the USA has gone through the qualification phase for the 2022 FIFA World Cup. Every American fan has been looking forward to putting the failure of the 2018 qualification campaign behind them, and to start anew with a young team looking to qualify for the world’s most important soccer tournament.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">La Fête du Muguet</title><link href="/blog/2022/05/la-fete-muguet.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="La Fête du Muguet" /><published>2022-05-15T10:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-05-15T10:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2022/05/la-fete-muguet</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2022/05/la-fete-muguet.html">&lt;p&gt;This weekend has been insanely busy, and it’s not over yet. Over the past week, the large parking lot near the local high school has been filling up with recreational vehicles of all types as well as some big trucks, as the group which is putting on the Fête du Muguet came into town to start setting up for the festival.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Muguet is a lily, and the Muguet Festival is the springtime festival, probably the biggest festival of the year in Rambouillet. There are more events going on than I could even mention, but the main ones which I know of are the parade, topped by the Queen, a local girl chosen every year, I believe by a vote. And of course, there is the carnival.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The carnival takes up the streats all around the central portion of the large park at the Château de Ramobouillet. There are many stands to buy crêpes, coffee, cotton candy, slushies, and other snacks. There are numerous stands to try your luck at winning a PlayStation 5 by performing some sort of impossible challenge, as well as other, easier challenges with smaller prizes. There are bumper cars and many rides which whirl the riders around in various dizzying patterns, all with similar results. Near the town hall there is a swinging ship ride as well as a ridiculously tall version of the pendulum ride wtih just a few people screaming their heads off as they twist and turn in their seats, as their seats reach a hundred meters up in the air before swinging back down to ground level and up again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For us, we are thankfully in the small child phase for another year or two. We send our children to the gentle rides. We haven´t had this festival for the past couple of years due to the COVID pandemic, but same as a few years ago, the favorite is still the multi-level jungle gym. The best one was a jungle-themed tower, three stories high, with a big spiral slide. It’s a perfect ride for us, as we can send our childen inside, and tell them not to come out until they are ready to be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a good thing that our children spent almost an hour in the jungle gym over the couse of the weekend, as each entry is six euros. I realize that the people running the carnival need to turn a profit, but every time we go to this event, I can’t help wondering how much money we will have to spend before we can leave. Ten euros lasts about five minutes if two people go on one of the bigger rides. Of course, it was worth it to watch my wife screaming as she whizzed around in an oval for awhile, but still.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And lastly, the disappointing thing is that as a parent of small children, we will always be subjected to a tantrum when it is time to leave, no matter how much fun has been had. As we walk around the rides, the overwhelming number of teenagers reminds us that someday we can just send our children to the carnival without us, and they can enjoy what appears to be the big social outing of the year to put their arm around someone and buy win an oversized teddy bear. For the moment, we’re still budgeting time in the jungle gym.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">This weekend has been insanely busy, and it’s not over yet. Over the past week, the large parking lot near the local high school has been filling up with recreational vehicles of all types as well as some big trucks, as the group which is putting on the Fête du Muguet came into town to start setting up for the festival.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What I’m Watching: Justin Outdoors</title><link href="/blog/2022/02/watching-justin-outdoors.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What I’m Watching: Justin Outdoors" /><published>2022-02-05T09:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-02-05T09:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2022/02/watching-justin-outdoors</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2022/02/watching-justin-outdoors.html">&lt;p&gt;Considering the amount of time I’ve spent watching video logs of hiking trips online, I was a bit surprised to recently come across a series that I hadn’t seen before: a Great Divide Trail thru-hike, from the American-Canadian border all the way to Kakwa Lake, the Northernmost terminus. I search often for videos on the Great Divide Trail, because of the route it takes through wilderness areas that are rarely traversed, and of course for its natural beauty. The trail is a relatively new trail that traverses the Southern portion of the Canadian Rockies. (See my proposed &lt;a href=&quot;/exploration/northern-divide-trail/&quot;&gt;Northern Divide Trail&lt;/a&gt; that would cover the rest of the Rocky Mountains up to the Liard River).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, given that I’ve already seen many videos on the trail, I was surprised to come across a completely new series by a channel called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/JustinOutdoors&quot;&gt;Justin Outdoors&lt;/a&gt;. And it is a well-done log of the entire trip. Justin put out one video per day, every day, from the beginning to the end of the trip, which lasted over a month. Not only that, but each video is not just a short summary, but rather updates throughout the day, from morning until night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that Justin does differently than most other adventure channels that I’ve followed is that he is quite open and honest about the mental challenges that he faces when completing his quest. He doesn’t simply mention a day later that the previous day was a difficult one. He actually makes the effort to get the camera out and talk about how he’s feeling, while he’s feeling it. I can appreciate the effort that it takes, not just to expose that side of the adventure, but also to overcome the hurdle of filming at the time when you most feel like putting the camera away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, just as a hiker who has been following other hikers on the Great Divide Trail for some time, I appreciate the tenacity of hiking all the way to Kakwa Lake. I must admit that I have been dissapointed in the past to find someone who has made a summary video of their GDT hike, and seeing that the video is of considerable length, hope to see the entire trail, only to find tat the hike ended at Jasper, which leaves a considerable portion of the trail untouched. I understand that hiking out of Kakwa Lake is not easy, which leads me to appreciate all the more a hike such as Justin’s, which accomplished that feat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, I was impressed to see Justin taking on many of the more difficult alternate routes. Many choose to take the official route, which in some sections follows a dirt road through a valley. Justin met the extra challenge of climbing to altitude and tackling the even lesser-traveled alternate routes, despite the added dangers of cliffs and exposed ridge lines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope to see Justin put out more thru-hiking content on his trail. Certainly most trails take longer to complete than the Great Divide Trail, which is an obstacle, but I would be interested to see how he compares the GDT to other trails, especially the Continental Divide. In any case, I can only recommend checking out the GDT thru-hike for a comprehensive take on not only the trail itself, but the mind of a thru-hiker each and every day of a thru-hike.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Considering the amount of time I’ve spent watching video logs of hiking trips online, I was a bit surprised to recently come across a series that I hadn’t seen before: a Great Divide Trail thru-hike, from the American-Canadian border all the way to Kakwa Lake, the Northernmost terminus. I search often for videos on the Great Divide Trail, because of the route it takes through wilderness areas that are rarely traversed, and of course for its natural beauty. The trail is a relatively new trail that traverses the Southern portion of the Canadian Rockies. (See my proposed Northern Divide Trail that would cover the rest of the Rocky Mountains up to the Liard River).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Year of the Tiger</title><link href="/blog/2022/01/year-of-the-tiger.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Year of the Tiger" /><published>2022-01-30T22:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-01-30T22:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2022/01/year-of-the-tiger</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2022/01/year-of-the-tiger.html">&lt;p&gt;We’ve just had one of two of our big meals to celebrate the Chinese New Year. The upcoming year is the year of the Tiger, which must be one of the better-sounding animals. Better than the rat or the snake, at least. The Chinese New Year, like many holidays, is principally a time for families to get together, eat big meals, and spend time together. Being away from family this year, we invited friends over to our house to celebrate with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Celebrating Chinese New Year is a lot of work for my wife. Mostly, she plans many dishes and cooks them all on the day of the big meal. I don’t mean three or four different plates. I think there were almost ten different things on the table at tonight’s dinner. That’s more than just cooking for an hour or two. She spends all day cooking the dinner that we all enjoy. Before the day even arrives, she gathers some of the special ingredients that she is looking for, scouting out various stores. She plans certain dishes to be more spicy for those of us that can handle them, and most to be less spicy. She comes up with some vegetable dishes to balance out the meal, which inevitably has plenty of meat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the main reasons that my wife does all this work is that we both want our children to experience Chinese holidays, the New Year being the most important of them all. This year, my wife took our daughter into Paris to visit the Chinese neighborhood, where decorations had been placed up, and she could get a little taste of the festivities. This is a very important part of the holidays for us, especially Chinese holidays. We haven’t found any opportunities to visit China in recent years, which means we have to work harder to maintain our cultural ties, and ensure that our children grow up with those traditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, my wife is up to the task. Despite not having her parents and other family available to be here with us physically, she maintains the holidays atmosphere well all by herself, most importantly with the big festive meal, but also in the little things, like a little Chinese New Year piggy bank that she gave the children for saving up New Year’s gifts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do hope that in the future we will be able to see another New Year in China, but I have my doubts about the feasability of that. Without being too pessimistic, I think it’s safe to say that the decision to take our children there would be questionable, given that we could be forced to stay for an unknown period of time. Thankfully, Chinese culture can take place elsewhere, and we can still be a multicultural family. I know that I have enjoyed the New Year already, and it’s not even over yet. It’s an event that lasts a couple of weeks, and so we’ll be having another meal to celebrate more in a week. I can’t wait.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">We’ve just had one of two of our big meals to celebrate the Chinese New Year. The upcoming year is the year of the Tiger, which must be one of the better-sounding animals. Better than the rat or the snake, at least. The Chinese New Year, like many holidays, is principally a time for families to get together, eat big meals, and spend time together. Being away from family this year, we invited friends over to our house to celebrate with us.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Versailles in the Coupe de France</title><link href="/blog/2022/01/versailles-coupe-de-france.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Versailles in the Coupe de France" /><published>2022-01-08T09:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-01-08T09:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2022/01/versailles-coupe-de-france</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2022/01/versailles-coupe-de-france.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been following FC Versailles 78 for awhile now. It’s fun to follow a team in the lower leagues, where the results are much less certain, and teams can’t simply throw money at their problems and win games based on a large disparity in talent. Versailles plays in the National 2, the fourth level of the French football leagues, but recently I attended a couple of their Coupe de France matches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Coupe de France is a tournament for teams of all levels in the French football pyramid, similar to the Lamar Hunt US Open Cup in the United States, or the FA Cup in England. Teams from the very lowest levels of the pyramid start play in August, before their league seasons have even begun, in order to start the process of elimination early. In each match, the loser is eliminated from the tournament. The cup games are on certain weekends which are set aside during the season, meaning no league games. This means that teams which are eliminated have extra time to rest compared to those teams who are still playing in the cup in addition to their respective leagues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Versailles is in the National 2, they didn’t have to start playing in the tournament until the fourth round, which started in early October. Their 3-0 win against CS Brétigny, a National 3 team (one level below the National 2 in the pyramid), started them on their current seven-game win streak in the tournament, where they currently sit in the final 16 teams yet to be beaten. That’s right, of 8,506 teams which have participated in this year’s edition of the cup, only Versailles and 15 other teams remain. Of course, Versailles didn’t have to beat all those teams to advance. On the contrary, Versailles had a relatively easy path, only being asked to match up against a team of their own level one time (AS Poissy), and never having to play against a team of a higher level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Versailles’ streak in the cup is composed of the following opponents and scorelines:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CS Brétigny (National 3, 5th level) : 3-0&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CO Cachan (Departmental 1, 9th level): 4-0&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Neuilly-sur-Marne (Regional 2, 7th level): 1-0&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Olympique Lumbrois (Regional 1, 6th level): 3-2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;AS Poissy (National 2, 4th level): 1-0&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;US Sarre-Union (National 3, 5th level): 1-0&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;La Roche VF (National 3, 5th level): 4-0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the games were well won, without too many scares. The exceptions were the game away at Lumbrois, which was equalized and then won near the end of the game. Versailles also gave up a penalty kick at the end of the game against Sarre-Union, which was missed. The streak was also kept alive in part because of a relateively favorable draw, in which teams from the Championnat National, the third division, as well as Ligue 2, the second division, and Versailles never had to play any of them. Of the remaining teams, ten teams are from Ligue 1, four are from Ligue 2, and the remaining two teams, including Versailles, are from the fourth level, the National 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On January 29, Versailles’ path crosses a significantly better team in that of Toulouse FC, a Ligue 2 team who is aspiring to make a return to Ligue 1. Though the match was originally scheduled to be played in Versailles (the smaller team traditionally has the right to host, which is one of the best parts of the cup), the unlighted stadium which FC Versailles calls home was judged to not respond to the necessary criteria, and thus the fixture will be played in Toulouse. The match was always going to be a tough one, but this misfortune makes the matchup that much more difficult. I was able to attend the matches against Poissy and La Roche, both of which were highly entertaining. It’s a shame that I won’t be able to see Versailles play in this new matchup in-person, but whatever happens, it will still have been a great run in the Coupe de France.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">I’ve been following FC Versailles 78 for awhile now. It’s fun to follow a team in the lower leagues, where the results are much less certain, and teams can’t simply throw money at their problems and win games based on a large disparity in talent. Versailles plays in the National 2, the fourth level of the French football leagues, but recently I attended a couple of their Coupe de France matches.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Looking back on 2021</title><link href="/blog/2022/01/looking-back-2021.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Looking back on 2021" /><published>2022-01-01T13:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-01-01T13:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2022/01/looking-back-2021</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2022/01/looking-back-2021.html">&lt;p&gt;We enjoyed a great New Year’s Eve with friends last night, and though we may be a bit sluggish today, it was a symbolic finish to an eventful year for our family. Of course, in some ways similar to our goings-on this year, Daniel whined and whined until he fell asleep in his mother’s arms well before midnight. Certainly this was a fitting end to a year that held plenty of good news for us, as well as some challenges to overcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wouldn’t be a real recap if I skipped over all the difficulties of the year. First and foremost in my mind, I made the decision this year to look for a change in my work environment, which I found near the end of the year. The process of looking for a new job can often be grueling, and the end of the process is not in sight until all of a sudden we receive some good news. Recently, the demand for developers has increased enough that I have had recruiters from many different companies contacting me multiple times per week. Though it is certainly nice to feel that interest from the market, it can also be tiring to be constantly communicating the same sorts of messages over and over again. Thankfully, I’m done with that now, and I’ll be moving on to a new post in February.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daniel clearly deserves his own paragraph. He’s a cute kid, but at the age of 2 or 3, every child can be a pain at times. To be fair, he’s going through quite a lot of changes, and in September he started going to school. Obviously, he was very excited beforehand, but not so after the first day. But I was very proud of him for accepting that he will be going to school, and not crying. Many of the other children in his class were crying for weeks after he stopped, some still continue to resist school. That being said, we are still dealing with the sorts of tantrums that most parents have to deal with when their children are this age. We’re hoping that 2022 brings a definitive end to that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Miriam has also made some big strides in the past year. Her reading and writing has been advancing in leaps and bounds. And I don’t just mean in English. She can read and write at some level in English, French, and Chinese. That’s pretty impressive for a 6 year-old. She also started doing her first extracurricular activity this year: gymnastics. She loves it, and I’m happy to see her training her body as well as her mind. She still has plenty to learn, of course. We’re still working on the idea of trying new things, notably food, and being more social.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After years of hard work raising our children, my wife Alex is finally getting a little rest (but not that much). With both of the children finally in school four days a week, she has some time to work on her own projects, uninterrupted. The biggest change that we can all see in her is her desire to be more active in our church. She has been attending several meetings each week, doing some reading, and thinking a lot about what is most important to her. I’m proud that she is prioritizing this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I would be remiss to not also mention the big news in our extended family: notably that my brother Kevin bravely took on Mont Blanc with me, and also got married! It’s been a year full of mostly good news for us, and I’m hoping that 2022 brings more of the same. Clearly the good doesn’t come without challenges attached, but so far we’ve been up for that. Here’s hoping that 2022 goes just as well.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">We enjoyed a great New Year’s Eve with friends last night, and though we may be a bit sluggish today, it was a symbolic finish to an eventful year for our family. Of course, in some ways similar to our goings-on this year, Daniel whined and whined until he fell asleep in his mother’s arms well before midnight. Certainly this was a fitting end to a year that held plenty of good news for us, as well as some challenges to overcome.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Luxembourg Christmas</title><link href="/blog/2021/12/luxembourg-christmas.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Luxembourg Christmas" /><published>2021-12-26T12:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-12-26T12:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/12/luxembourg-christmas</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/12/luxembourg-christmas.html">&lt;p&gt;This year, we did something very different for Christmas. I found a cheap car rental, and a hotel in Luxembourg over Christmas Eve and Christmas Day. Though the distance limit on the car rental is exactly that of twice the distance to Luxembourg, I was confident that I could stick to the route and not go over the limit. Since public transportation is free in Luxembourg, we planned to take advantage of that, leaving the car at the hotel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The drive from our house to Luxembourg was long. I picked up the car, a brand new, never-before driven Renault Clio, as soon as the rental service opened, and we left the house as soon as we loaded some clothing, food, and our Christmas presents into the small trunk. As we headed East, attempting to circumvent Paris and any holiday traffic, we followed smaller roads. Soon on a national highway, we indeed ran into some traffic. It wasn’t as bad as it could have been, and we did eventually get going, albeit after having made an important mistake that ended up increasing the distance to Luxembourg. We passed through nice countryside, and some interesting villages in Northeastern France. I would describe them as a bit run-down, though still functional. The region seemed to have seen better days, likely when manufacturing or resource extraction used to take place in that area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we finally made it to the hotel, the car had 499 kilometers on the odometer, 1 short of the halfway point. We would have to do better on the way home. In the meantime, we relaxed after the long 6 or 7 hour drive. The next day, we got going and started the day off by walking around Grund, a historical neighborhood. It was beautiful. Big stoneworks everywhere, with even the townhouses on old stone foundations. The old-time feel had been well-preserved, much better than we see in Paris. Afterwards we visited the luxurious city center, which is actually quite small. From there, we made it in a very roundabout way out to the village of Mamer. Out there, we enjoyed free ice skating, though Daniel took a lot of convincing. There was also an artificial sledding hill. We stopped by the playground after a having a great time there. Back on the bus, Daniel of course fell asleep, but we made our way back to the hotel and crashed for the evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We let the children open one present each. The kids both got some great presents this year. Lots of good clothing, which is much-needed, as well as some fun toys for both. Daniel got a bunch of toy cars, and Miriam got Jenga, which she is quite good at. On Christmas Day, we opened more presents, then headed out for more fun in the city. Most things were closed, but the city has a fun little playground with a big wooden pirate ship, that was the main focus of the day. We also visited the Pfaffenthal elevator, which is quite scenic, if a bit of a trigger for my fear of falling from high up. We visited a playground or two, saw the inner city again, including the beautiful Cathedral Notre-Dame, then returned to the hotel room to rest for the rest of our Christmas evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our final day, we visited some rides at one of the Christmas markets. Daniel did the trampoline, and we all did the Ferris Wheel. Again, it was far too high up. Thankfully we survived that, and soon got back on the road home. We took a more direct route this time, though it was still quite a long drive as we took the backroads through villages and countryside. It was beautiful, but Miriam was sick, and had to make use of a bucket that we placed with her in the backseat. We did thankfully make it home by the evening, having thoroughly enjoyed our little Christmas vacation. It was fun to do something as a little family unit, and the short length of the vacation was perfect for Luxembourg, where we felt we had seen a lot of what we wanted to see, and were ready to be back home.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">This year, we did something very different for Christmas. I found a cheap car rental, and a hotel in Luxembourg over Christmas Eve and Christmas Day. Though the distance limit on the car rental is exactly that of twice the distance to Luxembourg, I was confident that I could stick to the route and not go over the limit. Since public transportation is free in Luxembourg, we planned to take advantage of that, leaving the car at the hotel.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Christmas Season in Rambouillet</title><link href="/blog/2021/12/christmas-season-rambouillet.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Christmas Season in Rambouillet" /><published>2021-12-18T12:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-12-18T12:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/12/christmas-season-rambouillet</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/12/christmas-season-rambouillet.html">&lt;p&gt;Today was the day that we really got our Christmas vacation going! With the kids out of school for two weeks starting this weekend, we have a few days in Rambouillet before we head to Luxembourg, and we want to really enjoy whatever we can here before we hit the road. For me, I had been thinking about the Rambolitrain museum that I walk past after I drop the kids off at school during the week. In addition to that, some friends of ours invited us to visit some of the events going on downtown this afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rambolitrain is a small museum that only costs a few euros to visit for an hour. Really, an hour is plenty, as there are only a few rooms. One floor has glass cases full of very old model train pieces of all kinds. The top floor has a big model train set with multiple tracks, and multiple trains running. I had never been before, but it turned out to be the perfect place to take my three-year-old son Daniel. He could see all of the trains, show me stuff that interested him, and spend lots of time watching the trains go back and forth, in and out of tunnels, and all around the room. Overall, it was a great experience for us, and one of the rare times that I have been able to go out and do something alone with Daniel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, Daniel and I met up with Alex and Miriam, as well as our friends, and their three children. We met at the gigantic Christmas tree (actually composed of many trees) at the center of Rambouillet. In previous years, a small ice skating area has been placed there, but because of the COVID pandemic, that hasn’t been set up this year. There was a group there singing carols. From there, we went to a small alley where the kids got their faces painted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main attraction that we found was a small band playing Christmas songs in that very alley. There were trumpets and clarinets, a young and charismatic conductor, and a group of girls singing. It made for a nice little show, and many people gathered around to listen. The last song that the group did was a Claude François song, “Alexandrie Alexandra”, which I had never heard before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, Daniel fell asleep in his mother’s arms, and we walked home together as soon as the mini-concert ended. Our outing on the town was short, but it was perfect for a family with young kids. And again, because of the pandemic, there aren’t quite as many things for kids programmed this year, so we are just happy to have done something in Rambouillet before we travel for Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Today was the day that we really got our Christmas vacation going! With the kids out of school for two weeks starting this weekend, we have a few days in Rambouillet before we head to Luxembourg, and we want to really enjoy whatever we can here before we hit the road. For me, I had been thinking about the Rambolitrain museum that I walk past after I drop the kids off at school during the week. In addition to that, some friends of ours invited us to visit some of the events going on downtown this afternoon.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Beginning to Look Like Christmas</title><link href="/blog/2021/12/beginning-to-look-like-christmas.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Beginning to Look Like Christmas" /><published>2021-12-11T12:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-12-11T12:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/12/beginning-to-look-like-christmas</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/12/beginning-to-look-like-christmas.html">&lt;p&gt;We’re well into December now, and the Christmas season is starting to really show itself. I’ve been busy with other projects, but now I’m starting to get excited for the Christmas festivities which are starting up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although we would love to be with extended family during the holidays, the way that schedules worked out this year had us traveling back to the States in the summer, so we decided to have our Christmas just together as our little family unit. For a long time, I figured that we would just have Christmas at our house, like we did last year. Then, at the last minute, I was able to schedule a short trip to Luxembourg for Christmas! We can’t wait to see another European country, even if it’s only for a few days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, with the Christmas season comes a lot of work. Getting gifts is fun when you know just what to get, but when you are searching and searching without finding something that makes sense as a good gift, it can be quite frustrating. Thankfully, many of the gifts that I found this year came rather naturally. It always feels good to come up with something that isn’t just a generic gift. Hopefully the things I’ve picked out will be well received.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the gift preparation, there is also just the general atmosphere, which is probably the best part of Christmas. This year, it’s all about Christmas music for us. My wife and daughter have both been enjoying playing the piano, so naturally come December, our house has been full of Christmas music, which is wonderful. Between that, and listening to some of the old-time classics that I used to hear around the house at Christmastime when I was younger, our Christmas Spirit is high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, we’re just happy to have another holiday to celebrate as a family. It’s always fun to do things with other family, but it is also important for us to create our own holiday environment, and build our own traditions. Since we find ourselves doing that this year, we’ve decided to enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">We’re well into December now, and the Christmas season is starting to really show itself. I’ve been busy with other projects, but now I’m starting to get excited for the Christmas festivities which are starting up.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Working with Wood</title><link href="/blog/2021/12/working-with-wood.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Working with Wood" /><published>2021-12-05T12:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-12-05T12:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/12/working-with-wood</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/12/working-with-wood.html">&lt;p&gt;Being a homeowner for the first time has been an opportunity to get involved with a lot of improvement projects around the house. One of my more recent projects has been the creation of a couple of drawers in a nook underneath a bedroom window. The space is perfect for a fixture, as it’s a small space between walls, spanning the width of the window. The top of the drawers can be a good spot for sitting and looking out the window, perhaps reading a book. This is a great opportunity to buy some planks of wood, and do a little basic carpentry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My worksmanship is quite low-level, but even I can appreciate the ability to take raw wood and turn it into something functional. In the past, I’ve created some rudimentary shelves for our shoes in a tiny nook by the front door. That project just entailed cutting the shelves to the right size, installing some simple pieces to hold the shelves, and tinting the wood to a darker color. The tint is something that I do for all woodworking projects, as the wood I buy is light-colored pine planks, and I think a darker color suits our house much better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this latest project, I ran into problems pretty quickly, as there was a worldwide shortage of wood once most of the world came out of quarantine to get back to construction in 2021. I’mt not typically very fast to finish a project, but this delay was especially long, as I had to keep checking our local hardware store, in the hopes that some wood might show up. Eventually, some wood did show up, and I hauled it back to our house with the trailer attached to my bicycle to continue the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This particular project involved some basic measurements to get all of the pieces in place. There were only two drawers to create, both quite large. The biggest difficulty was definitely the sliding drawer mechanism. I ordered a bunch of drawer sliders, and they work pretty well. However, there is almost no space at all between the wheel of the outslide slider, and the other slider which is attached to the drawer. This means that when attaching the pieces to the drawer, the heads of the screws which stick out about 1 millimeter often get caught on the outside wheels and wreak havoc. I spent a lot of time repositioning the screws to get them to their current state, which is not perfect, but as good as it can be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project has been the toughest one I’ve taken on when it comes to woodworking, as there are moving parts and the measurements all have to be very precise in order for the drawers to fit and the sliding mechanism to work. I’m proud to say that not only do the drawers fit in the space and slide correctly, but they actually look kind of nice as well. I used decent amount of tint in order to make everything darker, and I like the way it came out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m looking forward to filling these drawers up with stuff to gain some much-needed storage space elsewhere. I also really think it will be fun to sit on the created seat above the drawers, and look out the window or read a book while enjoying the furniture that I’ve created. That it itself is one of the more lasting pleasures that I get from working with wood.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Being a homeowner for the first time has been an opportunity to get involved with a lot of improvement projects around the house. One of my more recent projects has been the creation of a couple of drawers in a nook underneath a bedroom window. The space is perfect for a fixture, as it’s a small space between walls, spanning the width of the window. The top of the drawers can be a good spot for sitting and looking out the window, perhaps reading a book. This is a great opportunity to buy some planks of wood, and do a little basic carpentry.</summary></entry></feed>