<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-06-09T21:13:41+02:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Sterling Coleman</title><subtitle>A space for my personal projects and thoughts</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Welcome to the Redesign!</title><link href="/blog/2020/05/redesign.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to the Redesign!" /><published>2020-05-02T19:18:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-05-02T19:18:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/05/redesign</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/05/redesign.html">&lt;p&gt;Recently I’ve been thinking about updating my personal site. In truth, I’ve been meaning to do something with the site on and off for a year or more, but just never got around to it. This post marks the first post of the complete redesign of the entire site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously, the site was created with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.joomla.org/&quot;&gt;Joomla&lt;/a&gt;, a Content Management System which was easy enough to use. It was never difficult to add posts, create updates, or publish in multiple languages. In fact, the ability to make different versions of the same post in different langugages and link them was one of my favorite feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When considering the redesign, I initially was thinking of a full-fledged website with either Angular or React in the front end. I quickly realized this was not necessary as I wasn’t going to need a back end at all, and therefore really just needed to serve static content. From there I started looking into &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt;, which is by far the market leader of the Content Management Systems. However, WordPress is written in PHP, which was also the case for Joomla and doesn’t hold a lot of interest for me. I found other CMSs which are written in nodeJS, but I decided that ultimately wasn’t what I wanted because most were obscure compared to WordPress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I started looking into popular static site generators. I ended up settling on &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; for a couple reasons. Most importantly, it has been created by a co-founder of Github and interfaces very well with &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;. Using Jekyll is a great opportunity for me to learn more about Github Pages, which I otherwise wouldn’t be able to do with other projects which require a backend and are thus not ideal for Github Pages. I also like being able to submit posts and pages in a simple markdown format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also allows me to learn about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruby-lang.org/&quot;&gt;Ruby&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://yaml.org/&quot;&gt;YAML&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://shopify.github.io/liquid/&quot;&gt;Liquid&lt;/a&gt;. I’m just getting into basic Jekyll subjects such as  front-matter, layouts, and themes, but I’m enjoying the relatively easy learning curve. To me it feels right as an engineer to move away from the Content Management Systems and get into something more akin to a development environment, even for creating simple blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I’m going to enjoy learning how to customize the look of the site. I’d like to explore things like integrating maps, media files, or scripted content. I may get into some Ruby for the more complicated components, and that could be fun too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that you find the new design easy to use. If you see important improvements that could be made, please do contact me. I’m always looking for another perspective in development.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Recently I’ve been thinking about updating my personal site. In truth, I’ve been meaning to do something with the site on and off for a year or more, but just never got around to it. This post marks the first post of the complete redesign of the entire site.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Consequences of Good and Evil</title><link href="/blog/2017/03/consequences.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Consequences of Good and Evil" /><published>2017-03-18T11:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-03-18T11:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2017/03/consequences</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2017/03/consequences.html">&lt;p&gt;In a recent blog post I wrote my thoughts on the concepts of good and evil, and explained why I think it is irrefutable that these things exist, and most importantly, are not merely natural or earthly ideas, but are indeed supernatural. Having laid the foundation for a topic more relevant to my daily life and existence as a human being, I would like to discuss the consequences of good and evil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all, if good and evil have no consequences at all, then they are of little interest. If a human does nothing but good, and their results are the same as another human who does evil, then effectively good and evil have no meaning. Of course we know that this is not the case. In our natural world we know that every action has a consequence. We can see that when we push a rock, it moves, and when we chop a tree, it falls. Actions cause reactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this same vein of thought, we know that human actions have consequences as well. For example, if I do not say anything to my wife on our anniversary, the consequence is that my wife will be unhappy. And in that example the consequence of my actions would affect me as I would be forced to buy extravagant gifts in an attempt to bribe my way back into her good favor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So knowing that our actions have natural consequences, do they have supernatural consequences as well? I believe that I have something ingrained in me by my very nature as a human being which knows that there are indeed supernatural consequences for my actions. I believe that this is an important part of what we often call our “conscience”. This part of me knows that there is such a concept as justice, and that if this justice were able to be evaded, that it would not be an ultimate or perfect justice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, it is conceivable that I could tell a lie that no one else could detect. This lie could end up having absolutely no effect in the natural world, either on others or myself. If that were to happen, would I have successfully committed an action with evil intentions, and not received any form of justice? I believe that the answer must be no, and that the proof lies in my conscience, some part of me given a supernatural design which knows the meaning of good and evil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, my actions in the natural world are done with intentions, which are themselves a supernatural concept. These intentions define whether my actions are good or evil, but these intentions cannot be observed naturally, as we have only supporting evidence and logic to suggest a person’s intentions. Therefore there must be a supernatural observation of these intentions, and supernatural consequences following the result of this observation. Otherwise, justice does not exist, as justice means that every human being is observed and obtains their results equally, with no room for bribery or evasion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As is our nature as humans, we often attempt to avoid the consequences of our actions. A common tactic is to claim that our intentions were not bad. I could try to explain to my wife that I simply forgot our anniversary, and that I wasn’t trying to hurt her feelings. In that way I can hope to classify my actions as some type of benign negligence, and not something more malicious. This tactic is very prevalent because we presume that no one can know our intentions except for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the most important topic regarding the consequences of good and evil is the relation between the two. Specifically, how does good weigh against evil, or do the two concepts not balance each other in some way? Most relevantly to humans, can a human being commit an evil act, and negate the consequences with some type of good act?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a hot topic for human beings. We see that we do evil, and we don’t like it. It is in our nature to want to fix this problem on our own. The idea of being observed and judged supernaturally is uncomfortable and even frightening. From this, humans have written many theories concerning how a good action can negate an evil one. Fasting, self-flagellation, monetary payments and indulgences, specific prayers, and other similar things are all being used by various cultures and religious beliefs in an attempt to undo what we have done, or at least undo the consequences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scary truth is that we cannot undo the consequences of evil, because the consequences of good are not a bonus or some kind of extra credit. Our actions are not a mathematical equation which can be balanced, but rather markings recorded in these two simple categories. The easiest way to understand this is by examining our own laws, which we have created based off of our consciences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do not murder because we know that it is wrong. There is a punishment for murder, but there is no specific reward for not committing murder. Likewise, there is no specific reward for doing extra nice things such as helping an elderly person with their groceries. Following the law is what is expected of us. Breaking the law has consequences. If we break the speed limit, we receive a ticket. We do not receive cash in hand for following the posted speed limit. Similarly, we cannot pay for our evil deeds with our good deeds, as committing an evil deed means breaking a supernatural law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This leaves us in a frightening state. No person can rightly claim to have never committed evil. No one has always had good intentions, and therefore we all ought to be worried about the consequences of our actions. Most frighteningly, there is nothing that we can do, through bribery, evasion, or self-denial that can negate these consequences. This ought to open our eyes to our sad state of affairs, and lead us to seek more information, and hopefully find a solution to this problem.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">In a recent blog post I wrote my thoughts on the concepts of good and evil, and explained why I think it is irrefutable that these things exist, and most importantly, are not merely natural or earthly ideas, but are indeed supernatural. Having laid the foundation for a topic more relevant to my daily life and existence as a human being, I would like to discuss the consequences of good and evil.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Outside the Anglosphere</title><link href="/blog/2017/02/anglosphere.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Outside the Anglosphere" /><published>2017-02-08T11:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-02-08T11:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2017/02/anglosphere</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2017/02/anglosphere.html">&lt;p&gt;This week, I’d like to put down my opinion on the vacation and immigration habits of many of my fellow American citizens. As someone who is highly interested in learning foreign languages and living in other countries, I realize that my opinion and experience and not that of the typical American. I hope that this will bring some value to what I have to say and yet that as an American I give my opinion not to belittle or unnecessarily criticize Americans, but rather to make us better through correction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I scan my social media feeds, I see lots of great photos of beautiful places and sites from around the world. And yet, the sampling that I have comes mostly from English-speaking countries. Don’t get me wrong, I enjoy seeing photos from New York City and London, but after a while I’m hoping that we start venturing outside our comfort zones a bit more than a trip to England.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As English-speakers we have the obvious blessing of natively speaking the language used foremost in global communications. In the business world, and in tourism, and in entertainment media, English is by far the preferred language of use. However, this blessing is an obvious curse in that it gives us a sufficiently large comfort zone that many of use never attempt to break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The topic is easily seen when a large portion of the American populous entertains the idea, whether seriously or not, of immigration. This happens occasionally during crises, but most recently during the presidential election. There were many talking of immigrating, including celebrities. Of course, very few of these people would be able to successfully immigrate in the way that they imagine, but that is another subject. So, what country does the typical American think of immigrating to? Canada!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are reasons to immigrate to Canada, but the obvious reason that so many Americans pick Canada as their first choice is that they are looking for something as similar as possible to their previous experience. And Canada definitely fits that description. In behavior, accent, culture, and almost every observable way, Canadians as people and Canada as a country are very similar to Americans and the United States. And while that makes the move and assimilation process seamless, it removes one of the main benefits of immigration, or even tourism, which is that of expanding one’s horizons and experiencing new things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I consider life experience to be very important in gaining both knowledge and wisdom. Obviously, a person who spends their whole life in one village only knows how things work in their town, and has no real experience outside of it. The same can be said for someone who has spent their whole life in America.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I’m not suggesting that someone who spends their whole life in America is not smart or is somehow below-average, as this is indeed the experience of the typical American. However, if one lives their whole life in America, they are only getting the American viewpoint on everything they do. They experience education in America, an American career, an American family setting, the American healthcare system, etc. How can this person say that the way that business works in America is the best if they have never been abroad? They cannot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, Americans are very lucky because in my opinion, America does most things very well, if not the best in the world. As such, Americans do not need to travel abroad to experience many great things. However, we shouldn’t take this for granted, as nothing is permanent, and the process of globalization has allowed much of the world to catch up in many areas of development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just want to encourage Americans and other English-speakers to realize that the English-speaking world is not the whole world, and the rest of the world is worth a trip at least as a tourist, if you are not interested in immigration. Taking a trip from America to Canada is like switching from CranApple to CranGrape juice, and going to the United Kingdom is very similar. Yes, there are differences between these places, but there is a whole world of options outside of these places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The worst thing that can happen is that you go abroad and realize that you love America the most for what it is. At least at that point, you will know why America is great for you, and you will not take for granted things that you missed in other places. And that is fine. But we can’t say that America is best for us when we haven’t tried anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But you may in fact find that there are things that you appreciate about other countries that America is lacking. Personally, I have really come to appreciate the manner of dress and level of fitness that the French maintain. I don’t feel good wearing sweatpants outside of the house here in France, whereas in America I remember occasionally seeing people out on the town in their pajamas. And for the other point, really it is just more uplifting to be around other people who have no obvious weight issues and seem to be taking care of their health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I should add that I understand that learning another language is hard, and takes dedication. The good news is that for most places, a phrasebook, a good attitude, and sometimes a lot of non-verbal communication are enough. But certainly, for immigration, you have to learn the native language. Don’t be fooled by the fact that many European countries have good levels of English. If you want to assimilate, make friends, understand the humor, and be more like the natives, you need to speak their language. And when you do, you will be very proud of yourself, and will have brightened your own future and perhaps that of your family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that this has not been too discouraging to any Americans getting ready to go abroad to other English-speaking countries. There are a lot of great things to see and do in the English-speaking world, but it has also all been done before by every other English-speaking tourist. Immigration to Australia has been very high lately, as it is a warm Anglophonic country. Enjoy your trip to New Zealand, but do realize that it is not that far off the beaten path, and that that there are other places just as exciting and beautiful out in the non-English speaking world. So let go of your comfort zone and experience something really new.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">This week, I’d like to put down my opinion on the vacation and immigration habits of many of my fellow American citizens. As someone who is highly interested in learning foreign languages and living in other countries, I realize that my opinion and experience and not that of the typical American. I hope that this will bring some value to what I have to say and yet that as an American I give my opinion not to belittle or unnecessarily criticize Americans, but rather to make us better through correction.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Good and Evil</title><link href="/blog/2017/01/goodevil.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Good and Evil" /><published>2017-01-27T11:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-01-27T11:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2017/01/goodevil</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2017/01/goodevil.html">&lt;p&gt;Two weeks ago I discussed the evidence for the supernatural and the origin of God. I would now like to talk about a related topic which is perhaps closer to our daily lives: the idea of good and evil. The notion of good and evil is also self-evident, like the supernatural. We saw that the supernatural can be seen by observing the natural world. Similarly, we can see good and evil in our observation of the natural world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is easiest to start with evil. Its existence is obvious and reminders are around us. Something in the nature of a human being is curious about evil, and leads us to seek it out. This is sometimes just to observe it, as some of us spend hours each day reading the news, which is always full of bad news, catastrophe, and the evil that individuals have committed exposed for others to see. There is something very sad about this desire, but it is the reason there is a show called “Cheaters” that has aired fifteen seasons and almost 300 episodes so far, exposing people committing adultery and betraying their partners or spouses. Incidentally, it has been proven that some of these incidents were indeed fake. The reason that this was hidden in the first place is that the viewers are wanting to see a specific type of evil and the real genuine consequences. They want to see real people, and not acting, as they already know the concepts surrounding adultery and how people generally behave regarding this act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reasons that people watch this program probably often include a sense of self-righteousness in comparison with the cheaters they see, but that is another subject. The popularity of this program and the myriad of other “reality” entertainment media which seek to expose individuals’ actions prove the existence of good and evil. If there was no good and evil, these things would not be interesting at all, but merely a series of events, collectively about as exciting as a dinner recipe. But we watch these programs because we know that the characters are doing wrong, and we want to see them do it. We want to see the consequences of evil. Their reactions while doing it, the reaction of the person who has been wronged once they find out, and the entire fall out. This is good and evil, not merely a matter of personal preference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The matter of good and evil hits closest to home when we are on the receiving end of it. Some people attempt to argue for the existence of good and evil by discussing the idea of a conscience, which is a good idea. Of course, the obvious defense to this argument by those who wish to deny good and evil is an example of some serial killer or other “heinous” figure who they think (or may even claim) has no conscience. At this point the argument becomes a stalemate. A better approach would be to point out that even this person supposedly without a conscious knows when they have been wronged. They know when an evil act has been committed which hurts them. They know that they do not want their property to be stolen, not merely because of the loss of value, but because of the concept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my mind, the best example of understanding the concept of evil is adultery. It is always amusing in a very sad (and perhaps twisted) sort of way when an affair is made public. We can find many example of couples who are both betraying each other. When each finds out, they are both devastated to find out that the other person was cheating on them, despite the fact that they were doing the same. We can also find other cases where a woman finds out she was not the only mistress, and is upset. Why? Because, despite our denial that we have committed wrong, we know when others have wronged us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news is that good exists as well. The mere existence of evil proves this. My favorite band Switchfoot has a song on their fifth album “Nothing is Sound” called “The Shadow Proves the Sunshine” on this topic. There cannot be merely evil, and nothing else, just as we cannot define the concept of “negative” without the concept of “positive”.  So where is the positive? If evil is a shadow caused by the absence of sunlight, where is the sunlight coming from? This source of light does not seem to be temporary or changeable. Indeed, the concept of good and evil seems absolute and permanent, like the laws which rule our natural world. This all points to the supernatural.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason that good and evil must be of supernatural origin is that they do not follow natural laws. We cannot create good or evil as concepts. If we could, then we should be able to destroy them or disable them, yet we cannot. Not only can we not disable the concepts, we also cannot mix them or change any particular act to make it good or evil when it was not before. Adultery cannot be evil now, but previously good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realize that a growing popular idea is that the idea of good and evil are relative to things like culture or time period. This is simply not true, and appears to be a way to explain good and evil using natural means, once one has assumed that the supernatural does not exist. Yet good and evil cannot be both relative and absolute, as that defies the definition of absoluteness. Either adultery is absolutely wrong, or there is some time period, culture, or context in which a spouse can knowingly go behind the other spouse’s back and sleep with a third party without having committed evil. I propose that this is not possible, as that other spouse will always know that they have been wronged when they find out. Will those advocating moral relativism agree that there is some context in which their spouse can knowingly cheat on them without committing evil? I highly doubt it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Two weeks ago I discussed the evidence for the supernatural and the origin of God. I would now like to talk about a related topic which is perhaps closer to our daily lives: the idea of good and evil. The notion of good and evil is also self-evident, like the supernatural. We saw that the supernatural can be seen by observing the natural world. Similarly, we can see good and evil in our observation of the natural world.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">French Transportation</title><link href="/blog/2017/01/transportation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="French Transportation" /><published>2017-01-18T11:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-01-18T11:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2017/01/transportation</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2017/01/transportation.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent a decent amount of time complaining about France and Paris to friends, family, and occasionally social media. So I think that I should take a step back and highlight one of the things that I really appreciate about Paris. The reality is, even though I can always find something to whine about, life in Paris is really quite good, and so the city deserves some praise in areas that it shines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, one of these areas is public transportation. As an American, my life never included very much public transportation until I moved abroad. Here in Paris, my family doesn’t own a car, so we use various other means to get around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should first explain the reasoning behind not owning a car. First, I should explain that my wife does not drive yet. In China, many young people do not drive as often as their American peers, so it was never necessary for her. That’s fine, because there are so many other reasons that owning a car is not for us right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For starters, the price of gas in France is very high. Brief research shows that the price in France in 2016 was about twice that of the price in the USA. Buying a car in France would also be costly. I had a car in America, but obviously can’t use it in France. If I did buy a car, then I would have to sell it were I ever to leave France, so it’s not a very flexible plan. Also, parking anywhere near Paris is a nightmare. I would have to be an expert in parallel parking, and comfortable constantly blocking traffic lanes in order to position myself to park. The whole point of driving is that it is supposed to be convenient; yet finding a parking place is often very inconvenient and sometimes costly. Cars also have to be maintained. Even if you have a good car, occasionally Paris restricts traffic due to pollution or events. Perhaps most importantly, we can’t divide a single car, so it isn’t a great solution for a family that has different places to go. Multiple cars is out of the question due to the expense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s not to say that there would be no advantages to having a car. Cars are great when the whole family is going somewhere together, especially with a lot of children that can be put in the backseat. If we were to travel around Europe, a car would be perfect. Vacations in the French countryside and mountains would be fantastic for a car that can travel the scenic routes. Perhaps most obviously, a car would let us leave the house on our own schedule, instead of constantly checking bus and train schedules. We would also be able to load up groceries and other things and not have to carry bags onto a bus or train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though a car would be a nice convenience, there are many great advantages to using public transport in the Parisian region. Perhaps most importantly, I consider the wait times to be short. For the metro system inside Paris itself, trains arrive at a given station about every four or five minutes. For my family, we’ve always just outside Paris, meaning we take the RER trains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chaville actually has three different train stations, so we can get to anywhere in Paris within an hour and most places within forty minutes. The RER C and Line N trains that I took for two years to get to school have two levels of seating, meaning they are rarely crowded. Though the RER trains are not as frequent as the Parisian Metro, they still arrive about every fifteen minutes, depending on the station and route. For example, in Chaville we receive trains coming from various different endpoints farther away from Paris, giving us more frequent trains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, we can use any bus or train in the Ile-de-France region with a single rechargeable pass. Recently the system was reformed so that the entire region operates on a single price for those with a weekly or monthly pass, so we only pay 73 euros each a month and our children will ride for free until they turn 4 years old, at which points their passes would be half price until they are in their 20’s. A majority of my pass is covered by job, which is about 20 euros more per month than I would receive than if I did not use public transport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately we make our transportation decisions based on the commutes we make each day. For me, I am looking at possibly taking a direct train from Rambouillet, which is out near the edge of the Ile-de-France region, to Versailles, and then a bus to my job in Vélizy. This would be less than 1 hour and 15 minutes from the door of my house to my office chair, which is the same travel time of people driving their cars for half that distance. The key is the direct train to Versailles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This covers our daily life. When we go on vacation, France has a good train network that covers most of its cities. It’s not as ideal as packing up the car and being free to drive wherever we want, but it makes vacations possible for a decent price and comfortable train rides. The trains also connect to the rest of Europe, of course, including the United Kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To conclude, I would like to praise Paris and the Ile-de-France region for having cheap and frequent public transportation with a wide coverage area. I sometimes compare Paris unfavorably to my life in America, but in this case I can say without hesitation that Paris has the best public transportation system of any city I have lived in. You can walk the streets of the city and come across a Metro station very often. Outside of Paris, nearly every town has a train station, and some have several. With the growing population of the area, I am happy to not be investing in a car, but rather to be taking the more flexible option.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">I’ve spent a decent amount of time complaining about France and Paris to friends, family, and occasionally social media. So I think that I should take a step back and highlight one of the things that I really appreciate about Paris. The reality is, even though I can always find something to whine about, life in Paris is really quite good, and so the city deserves some praise in areas that it shines.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Supernatural</title><link href="/blog/2017/01/supernatural.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Supernatural" /><published>2017-01-09T11:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-01-09T11:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2017/01/supernatural</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2017/01/supernatural.html">&lt;p&gt;I would like to take a minute to address a fundamental question that I’ve heard and seen discussed, argued, and debated many times: “Where did God come from?” To an unbeliever, the concept of God’s origin may seem difficult to understand. This is a normal feeling to have, as God’s origins are indeed difficult, if not impossible, to understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To talk about this, we must set the context of our discussion: the natural world. Whenever we have a conversation in this universe, it’s important to remember that we are doing so in the natural world. We speak, write, type, or even use sign language within the limits of our universe. Or rather, we could say that the natural world allows us to do many things, but not all things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a key point to understand before discussing God, because God by definition is not a natural being. His origins are not natural. This is not a concept original to New Testament Christianity, but indeed spelled out in the Old Testament, as well as shared by almost every other notable religion on Earth. We know that it is natural to think about this, after all the historic writings, art, and excavated sites which we have up until know discovered, showing us many different cultures, each in their own search for meaning inside themselves as individuals, as a community, and outside their natural world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This understanding lays the groundwork for the concept of the word “supernatural”. This word of course is used to describe something beyond natural, and something beyond scientific understanding. Science is a way to study and understand the natural world. Science by definition is not a way to study the supernatural. And yet, science still has its purpose. It is important to test notions that every weather phenomenon, every force acting upon us is a supernatural force beyond our understanding. We know now the natural explanations of many things which we previously considered purely specific divine actions, like natural disasters. However, it should also be mentioned that using science with the hope of disproving the very existence of the concept of “supernatural” is not only in bad faith, but also foolhardy, given science’s natural limitations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And though we are naturally limited by our language, our lifespans, and our intellectual capacity, we still have enough of these resources to understand the basic concept that the supernatural exists outside of the natural. I believe that we can know that from our consciences, as well as basic observation of the world around us. This can be seen in a study of all the many human civilizations, each admitting the existence of the supernatural. But even if you would deny that, we cannot deny that up until now, we have not found any substance which can create itself from nothing. We can make more of us; we can combine animals to make a new animal, and we can observe the break-up and fusion of elements. But it seems quite clear that in our natural world, things do not create themselves from nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the notion of God. God is the entity that exerted a force to create the natural. He must exist based on the mere fact that the natural world is temporary, and cannot create itself. That is simple logic. It is also simple logic to say that we don’t know where He came from. How can we know the origin of something supernatural? We cannot use any of our natural resources to give us the answer. More importantly, how can we know that something supernatural has an origin?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re exiting our natural world here, meaning that all bets are off. We know nothing of the subject in and of ourselves. The only way we could possibly know would be if the answer arrived in our natural world from the supernatural. If something supernatural passed us information in natural form, we might be able to know something of the supernatural world. Fully understanding any of this information might be difficult, given our natural limitations, but we would have some answers to our many questions, assuming the information given to us was correct, of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, the only definitive answer to the question “Where did God come from?” is “We don’t know”. That’s the reality of living in the natural. Though the answer is simple, it is important to understand the logic behind the arrival at this conclusion, as it is the fundamental nature of our world.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">I would like to take a minute to address a fundamental question that I’ve heard and seen discussed, argued, and debated many times: “Where did God come from?” To an unbeliever, the concept of God’s origin may seem difficult to understand. This is a normal feeling to have, as God’s origins are indeed difficult, if not impossible, to understand.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2016 in Review</title><link href="/blog/2017/01/newpost.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2016 in Review" /><published>2017-01-02T11:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-01-02T11:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2017/01/newpost</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2017/01/newpost.html">&lt;p&gt;With 2016 now having ended with only one blog post written, I have realized that I would like to resurrect this blog and write more often. In order to do so, I should write a post which gives a brief summary of 2016. Though I can only touch on the highlights, I would like to show off a little of our year 2016, and what we have been up to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a few goals going into 2016. As a goal-oriented person, it makes the most sense to me to discuss the year in the frame of those objectives. My major career goal was to get and have a good internship, followed by finishing my degree and starting full-time work. This was a big deal to me, as it was the key point on which our stay in France hinged. During my studies, I had a student visa, allowing me to stay and study, while working doing intermittent internships. But the real goal has always been to get to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting to work in France as a non-European foreigner is not as difficult as a few other countries, like the United Kingdom, but nevertheless it is not easy. I read posts daily from Americans and other foreigners hoping to get to work in France. They usually have completed a degree back home, and are hoping to get hired directly by a French company. The responses they receive are almost all negative. The best way to find a job in France is to have a French degree. I knew this when I first started studying how I could live for the long-term in France as a family, which is why I did an engineering degree there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2016 brought this engineering degree to an end. And while my time at school did not feel very valuable and was indeed expensive, it allowed me to connect with good French companies looking for intern developers. In 2015 I did a good internship at one such company, and in March 2016 I was able to return and do a second internship at the same company, though not in the same exact team or role. It was a good experience, but I was worried that it wouldn’t be impressive enough to negotiate a full-time position. As it turns out, my worries were unfounded, as I found a good team looking for a new web developer. I started full-time work in the beginning of October 2016, and am really enjoying it. This has been a big relief for my family, as we feel much more secure knowing that we have an income and a home here for the foreseeable future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my family, the next important subject has been Miriam’s development. As I mentioned in my sole 2016 post, Miriam is our first child, and she is cute, smart, and basically just everything that parents could want from their child. I’m sorry to be the one to tell you this, but your child is not as cute as ours. It’s just not possible, because Miriam is the cutest, most intelligent child in the whole wide world. She brings us so much joy and laughter each day, and though she is often much more energetic, and thus energy-consuming, than us, we can’t imagine our lives without her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Miriam started crawling in the beginning of the spring, and then pretty soon she was standing up and moving around on her feet with the help of railings and furniture. By her first birthday in the summer, she was walking. Now she is almost one and a half years old, and is starting to talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have been preparing ever since the pregnancy for her speaking abilities. Being an American myself, I speak English to Miriam. My wife speaks Mandarin with her. Of course, Miriam spends much more time with her mother each day, and perhaps as a result her Mandarin is dominant so far. I do try to push her to speak English, and I believe that she will improve rapidly. Mandarin words are just so much easier for a baby to pronounce, as they are short and usually only incorporate one consonant sound and one vowel sound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could go on about Miriam, but suffice it to say that she can do many things all by herself. Perhaps most of all, she likes having books read to her, and she likes to dance to music. She asks us to sit down beside her, and she pulls every last one of her many toys out of her toy bins and hands them to us. Our next big goal for her is potty training. Once she has finished that, I think we will be breathing much easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, 2016 was not an overly exciting year, but it was a year securing our future and making important advancements. Alex and Miriam got to visit with our family in China for a period of weeks, which was good for them. For us, scheduling vacations is a bit of a game of compromises. We have to balance many things and make sure that both sides of the family get to see Miriam as she continues to grow. While we have these obligations from China as well as America, our most immediate concerns come from our situation in France. My 2016 was spent meeting our basic needs. Now we are working for a 2017 that builds on these accomplishments.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">With 2016 now having ended with only one blog post written, I have realized that I would like to resurrect this blog and write more often. In order to do so, I should write a post which gives a brief summary of 2016. Though I can only touch on the highlights, I would like to show off a little of our year 2016, and what we have been up to.</summary></entry></feed>