<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-09-19T09:32:58+02:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Sterling Coleman</title><subtitle>A space for my personal projects and thoughts</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">What I’m Watching: Jim and Ted Baird</title><link href="/blog/2020/09/watching-jim-baird.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What I'm Watching: Jim and Ted Baird" /><published>2020-09-19T09:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-09-19T09:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/09/watching-jim-baird</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/09/watching-jim-baird.html">&lt;p&gt;Now that I’ve finished the first version of the route for the Northern Divide Trail, and have updated all the associated resources, I’ve turned to other things. I’ve always been interested in navigating rivers via canoe and kayak as a form of exploration, which is how I came across Jim Baird’s YouTube channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jim and his brother Ted were on the fourth season of the television show “Alone” on the History Channel. They won the first prize of $500,000 for that season by surviving by themselves for 75 days, longer than the 6 other pairs of contestants. Jim and Ted both have channels which showcase the different adventures that they have been on. Jim is married, Ted is engaged, and the brothers sometimes go on adventures with their significant others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adventures that Jim has been on include trekking across the snow and ice from Qikiqtarjuaq to Pangnirtung with sleds and his faithful dog Buck, who has now sadly passed. Most of Jim and Ted’s adventures are canoeing and kayaking. Often, they will get a bush pilot with a seaplane to fly them out into a very remote section of wilderness, and they will paddle back to an outpost of civilization. That was the case when Jim did the Hess River in the middle of the Yukon territory, and when both brothers and their partners did the Mountain River in the Northwest Territories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I like the most about the content that the Baird brothers put out is that it is lengthy. I can get a good sense of the lifestyle they are living when they are out in the bush, because they have over thirty minutes of coverage per day, sometimes almost an hour even. Most other adventure and exploration content that I have seen would put out about 5 minute to 10 minutes maximum per day, and would fit a trip of a week or two into about an hour. Jim and Ted actually have playlists of hours of video for most of their trips. I like this longer content. I can always skip ahead if I really want to, but I never find myself bored by watching an hour of exploration, even if the distance covered is less on average.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In these long videos, Jim and Ted showcase their skills on longer expeditions. They are good fishermen, and often fish just for enjoyment, releasing their catch. They spend a lot of time showing the maintenance of their campsites, complete with the collection of wood for campfires, the cooking process, and all the other tasks which they perform while camping. It is a very different style to an ultralight trip. The Baird brothers bring lots of gear, which can make for difficult hauls in the event of a portage, but also gives them the ability to do a lot more things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The style of their expeditions is definitely not a fast-based race from beginning to end. It’s more of a slower, canoe camping adventure in which the brothers spend time eating breakfast, packing up camp, and making their way downriver to the next campsite. That’s not a knock on their style, it’s just a big difference in planning compared to my backgrand in ultralight hiking. Watching their adventures has definitely made me think about the difference between the two, and how both styles have validity in certain situations. Certainly, I can see that when out in the deep wilderness, more gear ensures more safety and more ability to deal with unforeseen issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It takes time to plan and execute an expedition. There is also a lot of time needed to edit film and publish the content. As such, it was easy for me to watch most of the content Jim and Ted have put on their channels in just a few weeks. I’ll be checking back in regularly to see what they are doing. I’m looking forward to seeing new adventures from them. If you enjoy a realistic look at wilderness adventure, I would definitely recommend checking out their stuff.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Now that I’ve finished the first version of the route for the Northern Divide Trail, and have updated all the associated resources, I’ve turned to other things. I’ve always been interested in navigating rivers via canoe and kayak as a form of exploration, which is how I came across Jim Baird’s YouTube channel.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Updating the Northern Divide Trail</title><link href="/blog/2020/09/updating-northern-divide.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Updating the Northern Divide Trail" /><published>2020-09-12T18:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-09-12T18:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/09/updating-northern-divide</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/09/updating-northern-divide.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s been a few weeks since I highlighted my work on the Northern Divide Trail. During this time I’ve been busily reviewing the route, reviewing the resources, and making small changes. Right now, the trail is complete. The resources have been updated to their latest version, and a new resource, a textual guide, has been added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The text guide is useful as a secondary resource. Broken down into days, the guide gives step-by-step directions for walking the trail. Each day includes directions which explain in plain text how to hike the trail, based on compass directions and geographical features such as streams, creeks, rivers, valleys, mountains, and passes. In addition, each day has an abbreviated table of the notable geographical features. Finally, at the bottom of the page for each day, there is an elevation profile. This gives the reader a realistic look at the hike for the day, and gives an estimate as to what to expect in terms of difficulty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides the addition of this lengthy text file, I’e also updated the KMZ (Keyhole Markup) file, created in Google Earth. This is the file which serves as the definition of the trail’s route. I was able to shorten the trail a little bit, and reduce the number of days recommended to hike the trail by increasing the distance for each day up to 40 kilometers, whenever possible. I also took a considerable amount of time to shorten parts of the trail that were more winding. The end result is that the trail is now just 1000 kilometers long, and is divided into just 26 days. While this certainly increases the average distance planned for each day, it allows for more time to spend resting in the few resupply points along the way. The reduced timeframe also helps to finish the trail by the end of the best season for hiking, which is probably September.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the topographical maps are updated to accompany the updated route. This file is large, and can be downloaded directly from the drive. With maps at 1:20000 specification, this resource is good for finding the route in relation to geographical features. The route is traced, and the recommended end of each day is also marked. There are enough maps that each day is covered by about two maps on average. The maps are taken directly from the provincial governmen of British Columbia. Very often, the map at the edges of two connecting pages overlap, so it should be easy to trace the route from page to page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All three of these resoures have been updated with proposed side trails to Pink Mountain, Tsay Keh Dene, and Kwadacha. These are the only place to replenish supplies between the Pine and Toad Rivers, which is the biggest haul of the trail if done without resupplying between the two. Reduced now to 15 days, this stretch can theoretically be traversed without taking a four (or more) day detour to one of the above options, but it is still long, and contains some tall mountains which must be climbed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Toad River, I played with several differetn attemps to avoid the steep climbs and descent around Nonda Peak, without any success. Alternatives involved just as much cumulative elevation change, and passed outside of the core of the mountain range. As such, this area near the Northern end of the trail may be the most tricky to navigate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve had a good time making the plan for this trail. Planning and calculating logistics is a big part of hiking. Planning a trail is entirely about that same type of preparation, which I enjoy. Though I may not get an opportunity to attempt this route anytime soon, I hope that others who are interested in hiking the Northern Rocky Mountains will take a look at it and give their feedback.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">It’s been a few weeks since I highlighted my work on the Northern Divide Trail. During this time I’ve been busily reviewing the route, reviewing the resources, and making small changes. Right now, the trail is complete. The resources have been updated to their latest version, and a new resource, a textual guide, has been added.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What I’m Watching: Disc Golf</title><link href="/blog/2020/09/watching-disc-golf.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What I'm Watching: Disc Golf" /><published>2020-09-04T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-09-04T23:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/09/watching-disc-golf</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/09/watching-disc-golf.html">&lt;p&gt;I have the type of personality that leads me to get hung up on a subject for a few weeks and dive into it for awhile, before moving on to the next thing. The things that really interest me deeply endure more than just a few weeks, and become bigger than just a passing interest. There are other things that I find interesting for awhile, but after a few weeks I feel I’ve pretty much exhausted the material available or my initial interest has not developed into anything more. With that in mind, I thought I would create a series of posts that I can come back to occasionally, highlighting my latest interest, usually marked by the kind of videos I’ve been watching lately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, it’s Disc Golf. I got into disc golf a little bit after playing a few times on vacation this summer. I don’t think I ever came close to shooting under par, but I still enjoyed it. I’m not really able to throw the disc straight. Instead, my best shot curves to the left, which is probably very common for right-handed people. Therefore, any hole that has obstacles on the right side is a big problem, since I need to throw a bit to the right to account for the left curve. I still had fun, but definitely wished I could be better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow, I ended up finding professional disc golf videos on the internet. In truth, I don’t know how lucrative playing disc golf is. I would guess that many of those who play it are not making a lot of money, but are able to make a little bit, and play just because they love the game. There are definitely a select few who are well-paid, though. The players that play in the professional tour seem to be really good. On average, I would guess that the holes demand about 150 feet per stroke on average to make it to the hole. When you consider that the limit for most players to make a putt is around 40 feet, that means that players often need to throw three hundred feet off the tee, without hitting obstacles or going out of bounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Distance isn’t the only issue. Disc golf players have a whole set of different methods of throwing the disc. These are needed to be ready for different wind conditions or terrain features. The classic frisbee throw that I know, called a backhand, is merely one way. There is also the forehand. Then there is the Hyzer, which is when the disc angles left, or Anhyzer, when it angles right. There are many other ways to throw the disc, and there are many types of disc as well. Just like golf, there are drivers, mid-range discs, putters, and many other types in between. For someone like me who basically just knows frisbees, it’s all a bit much to take in, but the pros are able to pick out the right disc for the right situation, depending on distance and risks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The videos I’ve been watching have almost all been by a channel called JomezPro. I have to give this channel a lot of credit. The production value is really high for these videos. It feels like I’m watching the sport on cable television. In a sport where it’s critical to get not only a view of the throw but also the landing spot, which is often over a hundred yards away, JomezPro manages to switch seamlessly between takes to make the experience make sense to the viewer, and keep a global view of the hole while still getting all the action in close-up shots. The rounds are well-filmed, and the graphics clearly track the players’ progress. The fact that all this content is available on the internet really highlights the advantage of internet video channels over television, where there are many more hoops to getting content to prospective viewers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think what is great about disc golf is that everyone knows about frisbees, and everyone knows about golf. But watching golf can be a bit boring, because many people like me have never hit a golf ball, and don’t really understand how difficult it is. Watching disc golf is a bit more down-to-earth, and it is much easier to understand the challenges of putting together a series of disc throws to perfectly place the disc in the basket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By now, I’ve seen a lot of rounds of disc golf, so I may dial back my time spent watching a little bit. Sadly there really isn’t much of any disc golf in France, so I can’t really play the game myself. I haven’t really lost interest, though I do think I may have outpaced the amount of disc golf being played, and may need to wait a bit for new tournaments to be played and uploaded to the channel. It isn’t often that I’m interested enough in a sport to get into it this much, so I’m just enjoying this.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">I have the type of personality that leads me to get hung up on a subject for a few weeks and dive into it for awhile, before moving on to the next thing. The things that really interest me deeply endure more than just a few weeks, and become bigger than just a passing interest. There are other things that I find interesting for awhile, but after a few weeks I feel I’ve pretty much exhausted the material available or my initial interest has not developed into anything more. With that in mind, I thought I would create a series of posts that I can come back to occasionally, highlighting my latest interest, usually marked by the kind of videos I’ve been watching lately.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Back to School</title><link href="/blog/2020/08/back-to-school.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Back to School" /><published>2020-08-29T11:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-08-29T11:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/08/back-to-school</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/08/back-to-school.html">&lt;p&gt;Now that it is the end of August, the Back to School season is upon us. We’re lucky to be in France for this period, where the COVID-19 pandemic is under control and children are able to go to school without too many disruptions. After our vacation in the United States this summer, it was obvious that this was not going to be the case there. I’ve seen images of children as young as 5 years old in front of a computer screen at their house for their first day of Kindergarten. As a parent I can’t imagine that situation, and am so happy it won’t be the case for our family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heading back to school is a fun time. It’s the moment when we get all new school supplies, with that new Back to School smell. The pencils are sharp, the folders are unblemished, and the papers are all blank, ready for work to be done. Our daughter Miriam loves getting that stuff. In addition, as fall approaches, it’s a nostalgic time when we think back to previous Back to School moments, and how much we have to look forward to this school year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The French school year starts the first week of September, and never before. In fact this year, Miriam goes to school on the 1st of September, which is a Tuesday. French children start later than many Americans, who are already in school by mid or late August, but they end much later, typically the first week of July. Even more different, this year Miriam’s school has removed those last few days in July and has replaced them with Saturday mornings. This is not completely unheard of in France. I’m not sure how well it would go over back in the States.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;French kids get a lot of vacations to keep them in school until the end of June. They get two weeks off for Halloween, Christmas, Winter, and Easter, respectively. That divides the year up into periods of about six or seven weeks, with two week vacations between them. In elementary school, and perhaps middle school, French schoolchildren also stay home on Wednesdays. As parents it’s not really ideal, and many mothers who work have either negociated a schedule on which they don’t work on Wednesdays, or have found a caretaker for Wednesdays, and often other days as well, to pick the kids up from school. It’s definitely a complaint I have with the French system, which I see as hurting the family, as well as creating a sort of underclass of immigrant or poor babysitters. We’re lucky to have my wife at home to deal with this schedule, but it definitely isn’t ideal to constantly have the schoolyear be broken up by two week periods of vacation, after which Miriam is more reluctant to go back to school, or for her to be home every Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be Miriam’s third and final year of Ecole Maternelle, which is like Preschool. This year, Grande Section, is the equivalent of Kindergarten in the USA. On the one hand, I think it’s exciting that she’s finally the same age I was when I first went to school, but on the other hand, it’s a little anticlimatic since she has already been going to school for two years, and is still in Maternelle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, we’re excited to start the school year, partly because it will mean Miriam will get back to school to interact more in French, and will leave my wife a bit more peace and quiet at the house. Obviously with the COVID-19 pandemic and schools being out for much of last year, she has dealt with two little kids at the house for months extra. This will be a nice break for her, albeit not a real break since she still has our son Daniel with her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know the first day is always difficult. No matter what Miriam says in the days leading up to the First Day of School, she is reluctant to the point of tears to leave the house on that morning. As the week progresses, she is quickly reminded of how much she enjoys school, and is okay to leave the house. We’re looking forward the most to that time.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Now that it is the end of August, the Back to School season is upon us. We’re lucky to be in France for this period, where the COVID-19 pandemic is under control and children are able to go to school without too many disruptions. After our vacation in the United States this summer, it was obvious that this was not going to be the case there. I’ve seen images of children as young as 5 years old in front of a computer screen at their house for their first day of Kindergarten. As a parent I can’t imagine that situation, and am so happy it won’t be the case for our family.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Paris Saint-Germain: First Time in the Final</title><link href="/blog/2020/08/first-time-final.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Paris Saint-Germain: First Time in the Final" /><published>2020-08-22T14:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-08-22T14:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/08/first-time-final</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/08/first-time-final.html">&lt;p&gt;When we first arrived in Paris, I was happy to support the local soccer team, Paris Saint-Germain (PSG). The team was on the upswing, having just started a streak of winning their domestic league, Ligue 1, twice in a row. Since then, the team has won every year except 2016-17, when they were runners up to Monaco. And while this was a cause for celebration, it was also a sign that perhaps the team should be looking beyond Ligue 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All those Ligue 1 results never brought a really successful result in the UEFA Champions League. The two legs of the quarterfinals proved to be the impassable stage which stopped PSG from reaching its European aspirations time and time again. Several times, the team found itself up against top teams in the Round of 16, and were stopped there before even making it to the next round. This includes the infamous two legs played in 2017 against Barcelona, in which PSG won the first match 4-0, but then lost the second 6-1. All of these performances served as fuel for critics of the French league, which they describe as a league much lower in competition or ability compared to the other top leagues in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a relative newcomer to Paris, I have to agree with the critics. Ligue 1 is not at all competitive. Each year, Paris Saint-Germain is determined as the winner well before the end of the season. This is in large part because of the new Qatari owners of the club, who are able to invest a lot of money into the team, especially in the form of world-class players, the most famous of which would be Neymar and Kylian Mbappé.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I agree that the French league is not competitive. It’s the main reason that I don’t follow PSG very closely. There isn’t really a point in watching Ligue 1 matches, because the result is a foregone conclusion. Sadly, Ligue 1 is not alone in this aspect. Juventus has won Serie A every year since 2011-12, Bayern Munich has won the Bundesliga every year since 2012-13, and La Liga has been a contest between Barcelona and Real Madrid for years. The Premier League stands out as being very competitive in comparison, with only Manchester City able to successfully defend their title in 2018-19.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution is obvious to me. Paris needs more than one big team. Of all the big leagues, most have divided their biggest cities into several clubs. Madrid has both Atletico and Real, Rome has Lazio and Roma, Berlin has Hertha and Union, and London has a plethora of teams currently in the Premier League: Arsenal, Chelsea, Crystal Palace, Fulham, Tottenham, and West Ham. If you have a country with one main city, it doesn’t make sense for that city to have just one team, eating up all that market share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;France is definitely such a country. Paris is by far the biggest city in France. More importantly, the Île-de-France region which makes up the Paris metropolitan area, is growing, and there are no big football clubs in the whole region besides Paris Saint-Germain. If I were to pick two other locations suitable for a team, I would pick the Seine-Saint-Denis department North of Paris, with a rising immigrant population. I’m not sure what ticket sales would look like in a poorer immigrant community, but the area definitely has the population to support a decent-sized fanbase. I would also propose another team in the suburbs south of Paris, a place like the Massy-Palaiseau area. There is a large population there and it is a hub. There could be even more teams, but those are some basic options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are actually a couple of smaller teams in the area. Currently, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.redstar.fr/&quot;&gt;Red Star&lt;/a&gt; plays in Saint-Ouen, but they recently moved down from Ligue 2 to the Championnat National. &lt;a href=&quot;https://parisfc.fr/&quot;&gt;Paris FC&lt;/a&gt; also narrowly avoided relegation from Ligue 2 this season, and now has the Kingdom of Bahrain as a minority shareholder, so it appears that there are investors who feel that the Paris area can handle multiple big teams. Hopefully they can use that as fuel to make a run at a top Ligue 2 finish and a move to Ligue 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At any rate, this year Paris-Saint Germain have carried the hopes of the entire city to the UEFA Champions League Final, after coming from behind to beat Borussia Dortmund as well as Atalanta. The semifinal match against Leipzig was a good showing for them, but they will have their hands full against a very powerful Bayern Munich side which is almost impossible to defend. The French will be ecstatic if they manage to win the championship, but even getting this far is a new record for the club, and Parisian fans are already happy with their club. Whatever the outcome, I hope that Ligue 1 becomes more competitive, and that the Parisian area can bring more top clubs into the mix.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">When we first arrived in Paris, I was happy to support the local soccer team, Paris Saint-Germain (PSG). The team was on the upswing, having just started a streak of winning their domestic league, Ligue 1, twice in a row. Since then, the team has won every year except 2016-17, when they were runners up to Monaco. And while this was a cause for celebration, it was also a sign that perhaps the team should be looking beyond Ligue 1.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Back to Work</title><link href="/blog/2020/08/back-to-work.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Back to Work" /><published>2020-08-15T18:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-08-15T18:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/08/back-to-work</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/08/back-to-work.html">&lt;p&gt;One thing that I’ve been putting off as much as possible is all the work that needs to be done on our house. We bought this house back in 2017 and it was in need of remodeling. Some rooms had orange paint on two walls, and purple paint on the other two. Others had old wallpaper. The kitchen still has teal paint. The whole place was a mishmash of colors and wallpapers that didn’t look good by themselves, let alone together. I was prepared to make those changes, and within a few months of our move-in date we had most walls repainted white, and a few small improvements made such as updating electrical sockets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there was still much more to do, and I didn’t feel overly confident in diving into a big project and possibly making a big mistake. Thankfully, our neighbor JB does lots of work on his house, and he came over numerous times to help me out. I’m grateful for everything he’s done for us. But this was supposed to be my work, and so I’ve taken on the vast majority of it alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main improvement that I have made is adding a small bathroom upstairs. When we moved in, there was a small space at the top of the stairs which didn’t really serve any purpose. It was merely space between bedrooms. The realtor had suggested that this could be a bathroom, and I realized that he was right. The only other bathroom was downstairs, not at all convenient for trips in the middle of the night, especially for small children. Even baths for the children would be a nuisance transferring them from the downstairs bath up to their beds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so one summer I embarked upon the upstairs bathroom project. I took hand tools and smashed a hole through a basement cement brick wall big enough for pipes to pass through, then did the same in the cement block basement ceiling, which is also the ground floor. That in itself was a big achievement for me, but just the beginning. After that, there was setting the pipes (both in and out) in place from the basement up through the ground floor to the upstairs space. There was a new ceiling window, ventilation, flooring, water-resistant walls, and tiles. The bath and shower, toilet, and sink. All measured to perfectly fit in a small space (small enough that tall men have their head in the ceiling window space in front of the toilet).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was a ton of work, but the bathroom still wasn’t quite finished. But I basically was. I was exhausted and a little burned out on doing things that I had never done before. I don’t necessarily find it as fun to learn something new as I find it scary to consider the consequences of flooding the house with a bad pipe joint, or just making something very ugly which I won’t enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so for a time I didn’t put in the finishing touches. The kids can take a bath upstairs, but I don’t shower there because there’s no rod for a curtain. There is a light, but no plug for a hair dryer. The hallway between the bedrooms has no finished floor, it’s down to the plywood. And the exterior bathroom wall is not done yet because the electric plug is not done, so I still can’t do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a nice long vacation, I’m refreshed and ready to finish the project. I’m ready to find out how to do things I don’t need to do, and try to do them without overly worrying about a bad result. That doesn’t mean that I am expecting a great result, but rather that I don’t think the quality of my work is vastly inferior to that of an average contractor. My parents have paid contractors to do work on their house, and almost without fail the contractor needs to come back and redo something. So if I have to do the same, I can live with that while I do the job for a quarter of the cost of paying someone else to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I figured out how to connect a new plug to a junction box in the attic. I doubt that whoever previously worked in that junction box organized it in a standard way, but I’m not going to let that bother me today. There will always be another project to reorganize the electrical system, but not today. Today I am finishing the bathroom.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">One thing that I’ve been putting off as much as possible is all the work that needs to be done on our house. We bought this house back in 2017 and it was in need of remodeling. Some rooms had orange paint on two walls, and purple paint on the other two. Others had old wallpaper. The kitchen still has teal paint. The whole place was a mishmash of colors and wallpapers that didn’t look good by themselves, let alone together. I was prepared to make those changes, and within a few months of our move-in date we had most walls repainted white, and a few small improvements made such as updating electrical sockets.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Back Home</title><link href="/blog/2020/08/back-home.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Back Home" /><published>2020-08-12T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-08-12T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/08/back-home</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/08/back-home.html">&lt;p&gt;After three weeks in the United States, our little family is back home. We’re happy to be back to our routine, but also sad to have finished a wonderful vacation. The saying “All good things come to an end” is very appropriate to how we feel about finishing a vacation at Higgins Lake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There aren’t many places that can hold our interest for three full weeks, but Higgins Lake does. This year, we had many of our extended family members come at the same time, which made the trip so fun. From my parents, my brother, my grandmother, and my aunt and uncle’s family of five, and even my cousin and her little family, we had so many people at the lake that there was always something happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course it is the people that really make the vacation. We had the cabin to ourselves for a few days, which was fun, but the atmosphere definitely picked up when the rest of the family showed up. We were really happy to have my grandma there, who is of course our children’s great grandmother. With my parents there, that made four generations all together! We enjoyed this opportunity for her to see our youngest child, and for our older child to form a real memory of her, as she is now old enough to recollect this event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our children of course latched on to my cousins, who are in their teenage years. It was a happy moment for me to see them grown up, as I remember when I was their age and they were just infants. Now we are the family with young children, looking forward to having children who are old enough to do more things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They were very gracious, and spent many hours playing with our children, who just wanted to do little kid things. My cousins were great with them, which made us so happy as parents. But after three weeks, it was time for us to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That moment provides a good opportunity for us to evaluate our home life, and how that compares to vacation. I love vacation, and there’s no better place I love to spend my days off than at Higgins Lake, so I had been looking forward to it for a long time. And yet, after three weeks at the lake, I was ready to go home. Higgins Lake is special because we don’t spend all our time there. If we did, over time it would just be a routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We already have a good routine in Rambouillet, and it provides the feeling of home for us. It definitely sets us apart as the family that flies back to France, while many of our extended family drives home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year I made a bit of a mistake by taking long layovers in New York City in both directions of our return trip. We were tired in both instances, and I found that when I am focused on getting to Higgins Lake or home, I can’t enjoy New York City, especially with two little children in tow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we were the only part of our extended family eligible to cross the Atlantic this summer, with the global pandemic leading European countries to ban American tourism for the time being. As French residents, we were still eligible to travel. We’re happy to be back in our residence where we belong.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">After three weeks in the United States, our little family is back home. We’re happy to be back to our routine, but also sad to have finished a wonderful vacation. The saying “All good things come to an end” is very appropriate to how we feel about finishing a vacation at Higgins Lake.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Destination: Higgins Lake</title><link href="/blog/2020/07/destination-higgins-lake.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Destination: Higgins Lake" /><published>2020-07-27T03:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-07-27T03:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/07/destination-higgins-lake</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/07/destination-higgins-lake.html">&lt;p&gt;Higgins Lake is my favorite destination for a family vacation. I’m currently looking out onto the beautiful lake right now. My family has been coming up here for generations, after an ancestor bought a plot of land up here and built a small cabin about ninety years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the lack of serious improvements made on the property in the near century which followed, I love being here with family in the summer. The most important reason is that my family is here, and that’s something that is not specific to any one place. However, the history of the family coming here almost once a year for many years has built up a lot of great memories and nostalgia in this place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next most important reason, is the water. Simply put, being on the shore of the lake makes all the difference. There is a very soothing breeze which comes right in the window. The water is clear here, and that is something specific to this lake in particular. It’s a beautifully clear lake, not clouded by mud or silt, with a sandy bottom, fed by springs. Obviously, a wonderful lake like that offers opportunities to do every kind of lake boating, fishing, and swimming. I personally love taking a Sunfish sailboat out on windy days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the thing that sets Higgins Lake apart as a top vacation destination for our family is its relative remote location. If this place were in California, Texas, or Florida, it would be swamped with visitors all summer long. The fact that it is instead in Northern Michigan means that it receives mostly weekend boaters coming up from Detroit, and that’s about it. There are plenty of tourists, but it is still a very calm location, a bit of a “hidden gem”. In addition, despite being remote, it is very accessible, right next to an Interstate and a US highway, and not far from towns for groceries or restaurants. Perhaps the only real problem is its distance from major airports: the closest options are Saginaw or Traverse City, the latter having decent seasonal options to arrive from farther away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of all the things that are great about Higgins Lake, meeting up with family is the most important. The pleasure of spending time on the lake is the thing that brings us all together here to spend time with each other. My ideal of a great family vacation is a relaxing time, not necessarily a visit to a big city with a full sight-seeing agenda. Higgins Lake perfectly matches that, which is why I had been looking forward to this trip for so long, and why I have been enjoying my time here.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Higgins Lake is my favorite destination for a family vacation. I’m currently looking out onto the beautiful lake right now. My family has been coming up here for generations, after an ancestor bought a plot of land up here and built a small cabin about ninety years ago.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Development Guide</title><link href="/blog/2020/07/development-guide.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Development Guide" /><published>2020-07-11T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-07-11T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/07/development-guide</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/07/development-guide.html">&lt;p&gt;As a software engineer, one of my pet peeves is dealing with the almighty developer guide. This document exists at almost every software company as an aid for developer writing code. Among other things, it outlines rules for the formatting of code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These guides are important, and necessary, if mainly as a learning tool for developers to recognize features of the tools and languages used. The guide also serves as a warning against potentially undesirable side effects or pitfalls which may not be obvious at first glance. Used in the right way, developers can learn and debate the merits of developing a certain way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, too often the developer guide becomes a way for one person to decide every detail of how the code should look. The guide then goes beyond merely avoiding bad code construction, and delves into enforcing the spacing of the code, the format, and many tiny details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have actually heard people defend developer guide rules such as “The code should be self-evident and have minimal comments”. The next day I’ll be attempting to understand several portions of code which appear to me to be hopelessly tangled. After 30 minutes spent analyzing 50 lines of code, I opt to ask the developer who wrote the code three months ago what it does, and he will spend another thirty minutes deciphering it all over again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The silly developer guide rules don’t help. To me, the developer guide should primarily be used to avoid problems. Very few projects suffer from too many comments in the code. This rule just served to pump our egos up in thinking we were putting out code so good it didn’t need comments, which was not true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intertwined in the developer guide are the tools which are often used to enforce good coding practices. This could be a helpful thing to have in the project, but it all depends on the tool used, and how it is used. I once worked on a project that used a project called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/standard/standard&quot;&gt;standard&lt;/a&gt;. I had a real problem with it. The philosophy behind it was that instead of debating the merits of one way of doing things over another, this tool would simply set the terms. At best, we could ignore a rule in certain cases. There was no customization beyond that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of this centralized dictatorship of code formatting, consider the well-known tool &lt;a href=&quot;https://eslint.org/&quot;&gt;ESLint&lt;/a&gt;, which allows for extensize configuration, as well as having an option to use a list of recommended rules, to facilitate a quick start when desired. I think that the time spent discussing these points is important. It gets developers in the mindset of developing in an abstract, flexible fashion that allows a team to work on the same code seamlessly. The goal shouldn’t be to remove individual creativity, but rather to encourage it when it makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the age-old debate of Tabs vs Spaces is an example of this difference of philosophy. It makes no sense to me that there seem to be more developers who prefer to indent their code using spaces as opposed to tabs. This might have made sense over ten years ago, when some text editors didn’t have proper configuration options for indentation. Now I can configure any respectable editor to display a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;TAB&lt;/code&gt; character as a certain number of columns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what is the debate? If I want my editor to use 17 columns for every &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;TAB&lt;/code&gt; character, that’s my business. When I commit the code to the repository, someone else can grab it and use their own configuration to determine how many columns a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;TAB&lt;/code&gt; character uses. That’s the flexible option. Using spaces just means that we can mandate 2-space indentation, and use that to attempt to develop code with too many nested levels of logic to be easy comprehensible. Let’s stop micromanaging developers and instead just mark the danger areas and let them be free otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">As a software engineer, one of my pet peeves is dealing with the almighty developer guide. This document exists at almost every software company as an aid for developer writing code. Among other things, it outlines rules for the formatting of code.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">End of the 2020 School Year</title><link href="/blog/2020/07/end-of-school.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="End of the 2020 School Year" /><published>2020-07-04T18:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-07-04T18:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/07/end-of-school</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/07/end-of-school.html">&lt;p&gt;Today is July 4th, Independence Day in the United States. As an American abroad, I hadn’t even realized it was Independence Day, as it is not a holiday here in France. One of the more minor problems of living abroad is that you miss out on your usual holidays, and you don’t have the same habit of celebrating new national holidays in your place of residence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before July 4th was Friday, July 3rd, the last day of the tumultuous 2019-2020 school year. When I look back on the school year, I can see that we were luckier than most, in having a mere two months (not including the French Easter holiday of two weeks) cut from the school calendar because of COVID-19. In some states in the US, schools didn’t meet at all for the remainder of the school year once initially suspended in-school classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, we stopped sending our child to school in the middle of March, but were able to send her back at the beginning of June for two days a week, and then had a full French schedule of four days a week for the final two weeks, until July 3rd. Having our four-year-old Miriam at home during that whole time probably didn’t help to foster her independence, but she grew a lot during the year nevertheless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In France, there are three years of what Americans might call preschool, which are actually part of the public school system. For the 2017-2018 school year, &lt;a href=&quot;https://fr.statista.com/statistiques/499756/taux-scolarisation-france-par-age/&quot;&gt;97.2% of 3-year-olds&lt;/a&gt; were in school in France. Since then, school has become mandatory for 3-year-olds. This first year was a difficult period for our child, as she had to learn to fully communicate in French for the first time. This past year, the second, was much easier, and turned out to be a huge period of growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of constantly being worried about school and being away from her mother, we got to see Miriam be happy to go to school in the morning, and more willing to talk about her day once she got home. This is in part thanks to two consecutive years of hard work by great teachers, who take in 30 small children and somehow develop each one during the course of the year. Our teacher was fluent in both English in French, which was a big boost for us, and helped Miriam cope with the separation of her best friend from the previous year, who was in a different class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, our decision to put Miriam in a private French Catholic school has turned out well. Though not specifically Catholic ourselves, Miriam gets the opportunity to learn about Christianity from her teachers and the school priest, and surprises us with how much she knows when she gets home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She is still a young child, but now she has left infancy behind for good. She does a great job taking care of her younger brother, and is starting to accept our authority as parents. She can understand basic logic and can see that accept that she can be wrong sometimes, and changes her attitude and apologizes accordingly. This is a big step from the stubborn behavior she naturally exhibited in the prior year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been a pleasure to watch her grow up, and we look forward to even bigger changes next year, as she starts the final year of preschool, equivalent to Kindergarten in the United States. It is difficult to believe that all the work we have put in as parents and all the growth we have seen has been in a portio of her life that she may not remember much at all as an adult. And yet, if she can do so much now as she nears her fifth birthday, we can only imagine the development that will come to pass in the years to come.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Today is July 4th, Independence Day in the United States. As an American abroad, I hadn’t even realized it was Independence Day, as it is not a holiday here in France. One of the more minor problems of living abroad is that you miss out on your usual holidays, and you don’t have the same habit of celebrating new national holidays in your place of residence.</summary></entry></feed>