<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-11-03T09:38:32+01:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Sterling Coleman</title><subtitle>A space for my personal projects and thoughts</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot; =&gt; nil, &quot;avatar&quot; =&gt; nil, &quot;bio&quot; =&gt; &quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot; =&gt; &quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot; =&gt; &quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot; =&gt; [{&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;Eastern Continental Trail&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fas fa-fw fa-mountain&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://easterncontinentaltrail.com/&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Thanksgiving with Friends</title><link href="/blog/2024/11/thanksgiving-with-friends.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thanksgiving with Friends" /><published>2024-11-30T09:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-11-30T09:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2024/11/thanksgiving-with-friends</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2024/11/thanksgiving-with-friends.html"><![CDATA[<p>This year I had a few extra vacation days that I needed to use before the end of the year, so I took a long weekend off of work in order to celebrate Thanksgiving. It was nice to have a day off, and I spent some time preparing for a big meal in the evening with friends. Though of course Alex cooked the meal without much input from me, I cleaned up a bit and brought some things back from the store.</p>

<p>The children and I had taken some time Wednesday to do some Thanksgiving crafts. I bought some colored paper and silly eyes that can be glued on, and we made little turkeys. Miriam is quite good at creative arts, and after just watching a video of a craft, she can pretty much duplicate the whole thing. I showed the children a wreath made of a cardboard ring with leaves of colored paper glued on, and she made that herself from a cereal box and colored paper. Each leaf had something she was thankful for.</p>

<p>When it came time for Thanksgiving dinner, Alex had outdone herself yet again. She prepared a whole chicken as well as wings, as well as a sweet potato dish, some seafood, and various other things which completely filled the table. I enjoyed talking with friends from church that we have not spoken to in some time. We caught up over the latest news, and discussed their upcoming move to Switzerland.</p>

<p>The children of all our families played together, running all over the house and enjoying themselves quite noisily. After the dinner, Miriam showed the other kids how to make a pilgrim hat out of colored paper. There must have been at least eight children in total, making for a lively night.</p>

<p>I myself enjoyed getting the fire going earlier in the day to create a warm space for our meal. It’s nice to host people and fill up our large dining space with everyone. We brought up an extra table for the children.</p>

<p>Though Thanksgiving is an American holiday, it is one many of our French friends appreciate for its simplicity and relatability. We all have things to be thankful for, including each other, and we all enjoy sharing a meal together. Each year, Alex tells me that this year she won’t have time to prepare anything for Thanksgiving. And each year, she decides that actually she would like to celebrate with friends, even though it is a lot of work. I’m hopeful that we will do the same again next year.</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot; =&gt; nil, &quot;avatar&quot; =&gt; nil, &quot;bio&quot; =&gt; &quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot; =&gt; &quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot; =&gt; &quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot; =&gt; [{&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;Eastern Continental Trail&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fas fa-fw fa-mountain&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://easterncontinentaltrail.com/&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This year I had a few extra vacation days that I needed to use before the end of the year, so I took a long weekend off of work in order to celebrate Thanksgiving. It was nice to have a day off, and I spent some time preparing for a big meal in the evening with friends. Though of course Alex cooked the meal without much input from me, I cleaned up a bit and brought some things back from the store.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Guide to Hiking the GR56 with Kids</title><link href="/blog/2024/11/guide-hiking-gr56-kids.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Guide to Hiking the GR56 with Kids" /><published>2024-11-02T09:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-11-02T09:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2024/11/guide-hiking-gr56-kids</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2024/11/guide-hiking-gr56-kids.html"><![CDATA[<p>This past August our family took on our second hike as a family. I had been looking forward to this summer as an opportunity to access some wild and remote, high-altitude place that would not be a reasonable hike during the Spring or Autumn seasons. Therefore, I selected the GR56, the “Tour de l’Ubaye”, in the Ubaye valley of the southern Alps, very close to Italy. It turns out, this was not the perfect choice for our family, as we had no experience hiking in the mountains together, and would have benefited from a less strenuous experience for our first. I did not realize that the path would be along the edge of a cliff or serious drop for large portions of the trail. My wife was obviously not pleased with this, and I wasn’t either. Nevertheless, we completed the trail, and I would like to detail how a family could hike the GR56 together, and under what conditions one should consider taking on this trail with their children.</p>

<h2 id="planning">Planning</h2>

<p>The idea which I want to repeatedly drive home is that a family must be full of capable hikers to do this trail. You need to extensively plan this hike in order to accomplish it, and during that planning you will discover the various challenges. The first and most obvious is that in order to complete the hike, you will need to climb up a total of 8700 meters. Secondly and more importantly to me, there are very few places to get food on this hike. My main issue is that I’m not interested in eating out at restaurants or paying for the expensive refuges along the trail, but really that’s almost all there is. My plan for food resupply worked out, but it made for a difficult hike. Finally, besides the aforementioned cliff edges which form quite a lot of the trail, the terrain is just basically quite difficult, with several portions on which you need to hold onto a wire for safety. You also need to climb up by hand several times. This can be hazardous when done in the rain or high winds.</p>

<p>If you have already done a hike with your family, then you know to start planning months in advance. I won’t go into the budget you should set aside, because in my view your health and happiness are the most important, and this hike being what it is, you should not prioritize savings over your hiking experience. Ultimately if you don’t stay at refuges and don’t eat at restaurants, then you aren’t going to spend much at all. If you spend every night in a refuge, that will drastically increase your spending.</p>

<p>Your family’s hiking ability is the most important factor to consider. If you can’t hike continuosly for most of the day, then you risk being in a difficult position. You could alternatively hike at a faster pace than we did, but I would caution against unwarranted optimism when it comes to hiking fast with your children in the Alps. For us, we are a determined bunch, and with good planning we were able to meet our goals and keep enough food to get us to where we needed to be each day. This, in turn, allowed us to resupply when we no longer had food to eat, and find good spots to sleep each night.</p>

<h3 id="dates">Dates</h3>

<p>This is a summer hike. In my experience, the hottest month of the year in France is August, and so I wanted to hike the Ubaye when our home would probably be too hot to be comfortable. I knew that being up at high altitude, the heat of August would be well-tempered by the cold air of the Alps. I’m happy with our choice to do the hike in the middle of August, as it made for beautiful sunny days in the mountains for most of our trip, and those times that we experience rain and cloud-cover were acceptable given the higher base temperatures.</p>

<h3 id="travel">Travel</h3>

<p>For public transportation, the launching point is the city of Gap. From there, you take a bus towards Barcelonette, getting off just before at La Fresquière in Méolans-Revel. I think I may have made a minor mistake in our travel plans, as I bought cheap tickets from Paris to Marseille, then took a regional train back North to Gap. I didn’t realize that a night train exists from Paris to Gap, and that we could have used that instead of spending a full day to travel to the start of the trail.</p>

<p>Not having a train station in the vicinity was a new experience for us, but it all worked out fine. The bus travels between Gap and Barcelonnette several times a day, and we were able to travel to and from the area without issues. That being said, there were no good opportunities to quit the hike and find public transportation in the middle of the hike. Certainly options can be found off-trail, but the most sensible thing to do is simply finish the hike if at all possible at La Fresquière.</p>

<h3 id="clothing">Clothing</h3>

<p>I suffered a little bit because I did not bring a jacket or raincoat. I only had a very light T-shirt and shorts. In August, I did fine with that for the most part. There were a couple of occasions in the early mornings or at high altitude where I started to get rather cold and needed to hike faster to get out of a bad situation. My decision was based on a backpack chock-full of food for my family, but that was an extreme case. For a summer hike, I think a T-shirt and shorts should be fine, with the addition of a raincoat.</p>

<h3 id="gear">Gear</h3>

<p>I have already spoken about our gear on our first hike, but the summary as a hiking family is that we share as much as we can. Me being a bit more experienced, it was convenient for me to carry our 4-person tent, and relieve any extra weight from our children and my wife as much as possible. This is an important point if this is your first time hiking in the Alps, as the altitude gains will increase the difficulty enough that you won’t want to be carrying any unnecessary gear.</p>

<p>Our 4-person tent once again worked out very well, and basic 3-season sleeping bags were fine for a summer hike in the Alps. It got chilly at night, but we did not normally sleep at very high altitude. As previously stated, the adults carried 35-liter packs, and the children carried very small childrens’ backpacks. Our basic strategy remained the same, and the children carried food and very lightweight items.</p>

<p>We carried extra fuel (alcohol) because we knew we wouldn’t find any to buy along the way. Though it was heavy at first, over time it became lighter as we continued to cook our meals, and we used it all up by the end of our hike. Cooking meals worked well for us because dry noodles are quite light, and are acceptable for our children plain, and with some basic sauce for us.</p>

<p>We didn’t carry the children’s cameras, enjoyable as they were on the first hike. There were very few opportunities to recharge them, and we wouldn’t have gotten much use out of them before they became dead weight. I only was able to recharge my own phone one time, and barely used it except to take photos and write my daily journal entries.</p>

<p>This hike really enforces the ultralight principles if you are bringing children, as they will not be able to carry much weight, and yet require food and sleeping gear for days of hiking. My backpack never really got much lighter as the hike went on, as I continually replaced eaten food from my pack with other things taken from the rest of our family.</p>

<h3 id="test-hike">Test Hike</h3>

<p>We did a short test hike, not to train specifically for mountain hiking, but rather to get in the rhythm of walking together, and preparing to cover a good amount of distance each day. We hiked back to Rambouillet from another town along the GR1. The test hike showed us we needed new shoes, and prepared us a little bit mentally for the challenge of the GR56, just in terms of hiking together as a unit. The real physical challenge of the Alpine terrain was something we could not have seen in our region of France.</p>

<h2 id="hiking">Hiking</h2>

<p>Given the difficulty of this hike, I really recommend planning everything in detail. Have your goals each day, knowing that you want to get a certain distance in order to not run out of food. For us, we hiked over four days before resupplying in Larche. Before that, the only other food we got was bread in Bayasse, and a galette in Bousiéyas. The fact that there was not much to eat between those two points determined much of our hike.</p>

<p>The walk itself was quite challenging, with over 1000 meters of elevation gain each day. We found that we were a bit stronger in the mornings, with the children being less motivated in the afternoons. Of course, it was also colder in the mornings, so I was pushing us to keep moving as we hiked through high Alpine passes in a chilly breeze before the sun had warmed us.</p>

<p>Going in to the hike, I thought that it would be a lot of fun to sleep in the cabins that are strung out along the trail. And indeed it was, but we were only able to do that on the first two nights. After that, the cabins were all locked and private, and the few cabins that were public were in poor condition and not necessarily in the right spots for us to stop.</p>

<p>We were once again amazed at the resilience of our children, who laughed and played at night in the tent, despite having hiked all day and up at high elevation. They did their fair share of complaining, but they accomplished the feat of the GR56 nonetheless, and we are quite proud of them. Once again, I don’t recommend doing this hike with young children because the level of difficulty may make it unenjoyable for them, and for you as well. We definitely crossed that line at times during our hike, when the hike became a task instead of an adventure.</p>

<p>It was still a positive experience all things considered, and it gave me another reason to be proud of our family as we held hands at the finish line, back where we started after completing the GR56 loop.</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot; =&gt; nil, &quot;avatar&quot; =&gt; nil, &quot;bio&quot; =&gt; &quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot; =&gt; &quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot; =&gt; &quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot; =&gt; [{&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;Eastern Continental Trail&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fas fa-fw fa-mountain&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://easterncontinentaltrail.com/&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This past August our family took on our second hike as a family. I had been looking forward to this summer as an opportunity to access some wild and remote, high-altitude place that would not be a reasonable hike during the Spring or Autumn seasons. Therefore, I selected the GR56, the “Tour de l’Ubaye”, in the Ubaye valley of the southern Alps, very close to Italy. It turns out, this was not the perfect choice for our family, as we had no experience hiking in the mountains together, and would have benefited from a less strenuous experience for our first. I did not realize that the path would be along the edge of a cliff or serious drop for large portions of the trail. My wife was obviously not pleased with this, and I wasn’t either. Nevertheless, we completed the trail, and I would like to detail how a family could hike the GR56 together, and under what conditions one should consider taking on this trail with their children.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Replacing a Porch Roof</title><link href="/blog/2024/10/replacing-porch-roof.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Replacing a Porch Roof" /><published>2024-10-12T09:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-10-12T09:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2024/10/replacing-porch-roof</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2024/10/replacing-porch-roof.html"><![CDATA[<p>Back in May, I headed to the United States for a short trip. The main objective of my visit was to replace the porch roof of a house that I own in Memphis. The house itself needs a lot of work which I don’t plan on doing quite yet, but I was under a bit of pressure from the local inspector to fix up the house a bit. Given that the porch roof was a glaring issue, I decided to tackle that in order to make a visual improvement that didn’t require me to get into the actual structure of the house.</p>

<p>When I first arrived, I quickly surveyed the roof, which was completely rotten. It was missing several sections, and I didn’t want to save any of it. I immediately got to work tearing it down. I’m a complete amateur do-it-yourselfer when it comes to repairs, so I took my time and relied on working long hours to keep the project moving forward. The first day, I removed each piece of wood by hand, slowly removing nail after nail, and tearing down the roof while not endangering myself too much. Mostly, I didn’t feel comfortable climbing up on top of the rotten porch roof, so I worked from a ladder, which slowed me down.</p>

<p>By the second day, I was tired of working from the ladder, and I worked up the courage to climb up on top of the rotten porch roof. It was a huge time-saving decision. The second half of the porch roof came down much faster as I was able to pull off pieces of wood more quickly and easily. Near the end of the demolition work, I simply pushed the remains of the entire structure out onto the lawn, where it busted apart.</p>

<p>Throughout the entire process, I was going back and forth to The Home Depot many times. During one of these trips, I bought lumber which was designed to replace the large square pillars holding up the porch roof. The pillars available were not as tall, and so I decided to salvage the existing pillars. What really surprised me was that I found the existing pillars to be completely unattached to the porch itself. It took some time and trial and error, but eventually I was able to rent the equipment required to anchor those pillars into the concrete and I was satisfied with the stability of the pillars.</p>

<p>Perhaps the most enjoyable part of the process was the framing. I like working with wood, because it’s relatively easy to work with and mistakes are easy to correct. Though I did a good job making the framing secure, I made a mistake in my measurements by not considering how much I was going to have to cut the plywood boards I was placing on top of the frame.</p>

<p>Another of the many challenges I faced was the curve in the wraparound porch. I was able to find some flexible pseudo-boards that could be used for this curve. I attached a series of boards along these in order to keep the right shape for the curve, and though it was a time-consuming process, I got the result I was looking for.</p>

<p>With the frame done, I just had a few more days to add the plywood layer and finally the actual roof shingles. The plywood took me some time because I had to cut each piece because of the nature of my framing. As with all the other steps before, I got the result I wanted after working hard for long hours. The roof shingles themselves was another story as I unknowingly placed down a roll of very sticky roof shingle material, not realizing that it would negate the need for shingles themselves.</p>

<p>Though I had not envisioned it that wasy, I stuck with the rolls, and covered the whole porch roof with those. The result probably isn’t much to look at, but it should keep the roof from sustaining water damage like its predecessor.</p>

<p>This was a tough project for me which took about 10 days of hard work. Doing the project alone meant that I was constantly losing time by going to the store, and I had to carefully plan how to handle the heavier materials. I probably adujsted my ladder upwards of five hundred times. I’m proud to have finished the project in the allotted time, and all for a budget of less than four thousand dollars. I was quoted fifteen thousand by a carpenter over a year prior, and I’m not sure that would include everything.</p>

<p>It’s not the end of the work I will have to do on this house by any means, but it4’s a good start that radically changes how the house looks from the street.</p>

<figure class="half ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/images/blog/2024-10-12-replacing-porch-roof/large/20240518_191646.jpg" title="Big hole in rotten roof">
          <img src="/assets/images/blog/2024-10-12-replacing-porch-roof/small/20240518_191646.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/images/blog/2024-10-12-replacing-porch-roof/large/20240518_191715.jpg" title="Demolition of the porch roof has begun">
          <img src="/assets/images/blog/2024-10-12-replacing-porch-roof/small/20240518_191715.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/images/blog/2024-10-12-replacing-porch-roof/large/20240518_191726.jpg" title="A section of the old roof removed">
          <img src="/assets/images/blog/2024-10-12-replacing-porch-roof/small/20240518_191726.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/images/blog/2024-10-12-replacing-porch-roof/large/20240519_203127.jpg" title="Only the edge remains">
          <img src="/assets/images/blog/2024-10-12-replacing-porch-roof/small/20240519_203127.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/images/blog/2024-10-12-replacing-porch-roof/large/20240521_200910.jpg" title="The new porch roof frame is started">
          <img src="/assets/images/blog/2024-10-12-replacing-porch-roof/small/20240521_200910.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/images/blog/2024-10-12-replacing-porch-roof/large/20240523_194855.jpg" title="The curve of the wraparound porch is complete">
          <img src="/assets/images/blog/2024-10-12-replacing-porch-roof/small/20240523_194855.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/images/blog/2024-10-12-replacing-porch-roof/large/20240524_200456.jpg" title="Framing on the curve took time and careful measurements">
          <img src="/assets/images/blog/2024-10-12-replacing-porch-roof/small/20240524_200456.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/images/blog/2024-10-12-replacing-porch-roof/large/20240524_200512.jpg" title="View of the new porch roof frame with the old roof sitting in a heap on the lawn">
          <img src="/assets/images/blog/2024-10-12-replacing-porch-roof/small/20240524_200512.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/images/blog/2024-10-12-replacing-porch-roof/large/20240524_200534.jpg" title="The new porch roof frame looks good">
          <img src="/assets/images/blog/2024-10-12-replacing-porch-roof/small/20240524_200534.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/images/blog/2024-10-12-replacing-porch-roof/large/20240601_161827.jpg" title="The project complete, the porch is painted">
          <img src="/assets/images/blog/2024-10-12-replacing-porch-roof/small/20240601_161827.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot; =&gt; nil, &quot;avatar&quot; =&gt; nil, &quot;bio&quot; =&gt; &quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot; =&gt; &quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot; =&gt; &quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot; =&gt; [{&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;Eastern Continental Trail&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fas fa-fw fa-mountain&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://easterncontinentaltrail.com/&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Back in May, I headed to the United States for a short trip. The main objective of my visit was to replace the porch roof of a house that I own in Memphis. The house itself needs a lot of work which I don’t plan on doing quite yet, but I was under a bit of pressure from the local inspector to fix up the house a bit. Given that the porch roof was a glaring issue, I decided to tackle that in order to make a visual improvement that didn’t require me to get into the actual structure of the house.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Guide to Hiking the GR21 with Kids</title><link href="/blog/2024/07/guide-hiking-gr21-kids.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Guide to Hiking the GR21 with Kids" /><published>2024-07-20T09:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-07-20T09:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2024/07/guide-hiking-gr21-kids</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2024/07/guide-hiking-gr21-kids.html"><![CDATA[<p>In April, we set out to hike the GR21 from Le Tréport to Le Havre. It was to be our first ever thru-hike as a family, and we were all a little unsure of what to expect. Miriam was still eight years old, and Daniel had just reached six years old. As a family of four, we stepped off the train in Le Tréport, took a couple of pictures, and hit the trail. 11 days later, we finished at Le Havre, feeling very accomplished. I want to share with others how you might have a successful hiking trip with your children in France, and I believe that the GR21 is one of the best trails to hike as a family. It’s a beautiful trail, with lots of great views of the English channel, plenty of options to eat and rest, and it can be done during school vacation. There are even several convenient places along the way to stop the hike and go home if needed.</p>

<h2 id="planning">Planning</h2>

<p>Two to three months before the hike is set to begin, you should start the planning. This gives time to locate gear, organize transportation, and ensure that you are ready for your hike. In order to ensure that money is not an issue, set aside a budget of 1000 euros for the trip. The actual cost may be a little more than half of that.</p>

<p>Before you start investing a lot of time and money into planning and preparation, test your family’s walking ability. You should be able to walk together at an average of at least three kilometers per hour on flat ground, for multiple hours. We found that this was quite attainable for our children, especially if we held hands.  Once that has been assertained, you can be sure that completing the hike is a possibility.</p>

<h3 id="dates">Dates</h3>

<p>The dates of your hike will probably be shaped by your normal work and school constraints. With children in France, you have several two-week holidays which are perfect for short hiking trips, in addition to the longer summer break. We did our hike during the spring vacation in mid-April. I recommend this period if your school vacation is not in early April, as it is less crowded on the Normandy coast. Being the beginning of the hiking season in this region, it can get a little chilly at night, and though we did meet some high winds, I was happy that we weren’t exposed to the higher temperatures of summer on our hike.</p>

<h3 id="travel">Travel</h3>

<p>When you have decided on your hiking dates, I highly recommend buying train tickets. The GR21 is a hike between two train stations. I recommend starting the hike at Le Tréport and finishing at Le Havre. It’s better to finish your hike in a place with more frequent transportation options, and Le Havre is a big city with many trains. There are other good reasons to start in Le Tréport, such as following the FFRandonée’s Topoguide and saving Étretat for near the end of the hike, but it certainly also makes travel back home after the hike more flexible. If you are coming from Paris like us, it is easy to get to Le Tréport, with just one change in Beauvais. The train home from Le Havre was direct to Saint-Lazare with few stops.</p>

<h3 id="clothing">Clothing</h3>

<p>When it comes to clothing, it depends a bit on the season, but I recommend bringing rain jackets that also serve to keep warm in case of high winds. That is the heaviest piece of clothing. Otherwise, we were all wearing long sleeves and pants. Since it was spring, we brought some items to keep warm as well, such as a knit cap and sweatshirts. The main issue we had with the weather and temperature was cold winds, so long sleeves and pants were necessities. The children each had an extra layer to ensure they were warm enough, and I feel that they did need that.</p>

<h3 id="gear">Gear</h3>

<p>It is useless to give you links to a bunch of gear that won’t be on sale when you read this guide. In addition, I don’t like proposing specific pieces of gear. Instead, I will just give you the basic strategy of any hiking family: share gear. I recommend sharing one four-person tent and one cooking set. The parents carry 35 liter backpacks, and the children carry little daypacks. It is important to have the children participate in some way by having a backpack, but it should be small.</p>

<p>I think the tent is the hardest piece of gear to find. There was only one 4-person tent that I could find at an acceptable weight for hiking (2.8 kilograms), for a decent price (150 euros). I had to have it shipped from a store in the Netherlands that seemed to be the only place that had it in stock. It served us well, and even though it was a little heavy for me to carry by myself, it allowed us to lighten everyone else’s backpacks, which is critical.</p>

<p>After that, most of the gear came from Decathlon. If you are in France, Decathlon is a great box store with some fairly lightweight gear for great prices. The gear we bought was a lot of Quechua (a French branch sold mostly by Decathlon) stuff which was super cheap. All of our backpacks, sleeping pads and iking poles were all shipped to us from Decathlon’s online store. I balanced good prices with lightweight items. Nothing we had was ultralight, it was simply run-of-the-mill box store hiking gear. Our adult backpacks were each 60 euros and less than a kilogram each. The children’s gear was extremely cheap. I highly recommend Decathlon.</p>

<p>For the sleeping gear, normal 3-season sleeping backs which are rated to be comfortable at 5 degrees Celsius should be fine. That was as low as the temperature got at night in April 2024 on the Normandy coast. I wanted to share sleeping pads, but couldn’t find anything affordable. I ended up going with cheap foldable foam sleeping pads, and they were fine.</p>

<p>For cooking, I invested in a large Toaks pot and pan set, and an alcohol stove. Many hikers prefer to use fuel cannisters with gas, and I’m sure that would work fine as well. I just prefer being able to go to refill my fuel at any grocery store if needed. The downside of sharing cooking gear is that it can take a lot longer to cook for four people. I consider this to be a sacrifice worth making, as we have more time in camp with younger children who can’t hike for long hours every day. To compensate, I carried other things for myself to eat that didn’t need to be cooked.</p>

<p>The other things that we brought were two headlamps, a trowel, tissues, a small microfiber towel, phones with charging cables, and the Topoguide. These items were all extremely light, and each more than earned their place in our packs. We really limit extra things, but many small lightweight items are very useful on a hike. Your list may vary, but it will probably be quite similar to ours.</p>

<p>Most importantly for the children, we brought a few things to make the experience fun. Cheap little cameras that they could take pictures with (although they soon found the cameras could play games and we had to limit their playing time). Tiny playing cards were a lightweight option to pass the time in the tent.</p>

<h3 id="test-hike">Test Hike</h3>

<p>About two or three weeks before the real hike, take your family out for a hike and camp together in the tent. This is invaluable experience if you have never camped and hiked together, and even if you have, I would still do it to be sure to be prepared. Our test hike was much more difficult than the GR21 due to months of rain leaving high water and heavy mud along the section of the GR1 that we hiked. We learned what worked for us, how the children liked to hike, and what strategies to use to make the experience fun.</p>

<h2 id="hiking">Hiking</h2>

<p>When it comes to the actual hike, my advice is to plan well in advance the daily distance and give yourself plenty of time. I meticulously planned stopping points which were close to twenty kilometers each day, allowing us to complete the trail in 11 days. Each day, we tried to find good spots to take long breaks of at least thirty minutes. The only real obstacle to this was strong winds and chilly temperatures which made stopping for long uncomfortable for us. Our children loved playing on the many beach playgrounds found along the trail.</p>

<p>By getting up and starting our hike between 8 and 9 in the morning, we had plenty of time to do twenty kilometers at our own pace, with long breaks included, and arrive at a good spot to camp by dinner time. Some days, we didn’t take long breaks, and ended up finishing our hiking by early afternoon. I still insisted that we stop at the planned point in order to give our children a break and not wear them out.</p>

<p>During the day, we kept our children motivated by feeding them with a steady stream of snacks. In this way, we make hiking more enjoyable by presenting it as an opportunity to eat all the things which are usually more restricted at home. Oreos, candy, lollipops, crackers, and all sorts of snacks were constantly being handed out while we walked.</p>

<p>Camping at the end of the day was the favorite part of hiking for our children. It was important to pick out possible spots ahead of time, as there aren’t too many good spots to stealth camp on the GR21. The trail is constantly near a village or on a road, so the best spots for camping are near the cliffs or near farm fields, if possible. Having one tent for all four of us to share was key. In the tent, the children laughed together and relaxed after hiking. They ate noodles and other snacks, I wrote in my journal, Alex cooked, and we all organized our things. Occasionally we would play a card game, and the children might be allowed to play with their cameras.</p>

<p>The children found things that they enjoyed about the hike as well. Both kids enjoyed looking for the next blaze and calling them out, especially Daniel. Following the path of the trail with its turns, and looking forward to the next milestone were simple ways that our children stayed engaged.</p>

<p>For myself, planning everything for my family kept me busy. There weren’t a lot of great opportunities to filter water from a good source, so I planned where to buy large bottles and how far they needed to last until the next opportunity to refill. I was able to balance our nights camping in the tent with a few nights in rented rooms in town. Dieppe, Fécamp, and Le Havre were the places we paid to sleep in comfortable beds and relax for a night in town. I recommend these town stops, because it gives opportunities to take more time in the cities to wash clothing and resupply.</p>

<p>Together, we supported each other through the various little challenges of thru-hiking, and we got a first taste of hiking together in France. It was a memorable experience for all of us, and it introduced the idea of doing more hikes together. I hope that the GR21 can be that for other families looking to get into hiking together as well.</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot; =&gt; nil, &quot;avatar&quot; =&gt; nil, &quot;bio&quot; =&gt; &quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot; =&gt; &quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot; =&gt; &quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot; =&gt; [{&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;Eastern Continental Trail&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fas fa-fw fa-mountain&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://easterncontinentaltrail.com/&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In April, we set out to hike the GR21 from Le Tréport to Le Havre. It was to be our first ever thru-hike as a family, and we were all a little unsure of what to expect. Miriam was still eight years old, and Daniel had just reached six years old. As a family of four, we stepped off the train in Le Tréport, took a couple of pictures, and hit the trail. 11 days later, we finished at Le Havre, feeling very accomplished. I want to share with others how you might have a successful hiking trip with your children in France, and I believe that the GR21 is one of the best trails to hike as a family. It’s a beautiful trail, with lots of great views of the English channel, plenty of options to eat and rest, and it can be done during school vacation. There are even several convenient places along the way to stop the hike and go home if needed.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Geography of French Football Teams</title><link href="/blog/2023/09/french-football-map.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Geography of French Football Teams" /><published>2023-09-30T09:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-09-30T09:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2023/09/french-football-map</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2023/09/french-football-map.html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently completed a map of all the teams in the top five leages in the French Football pyramid. It took quite a bit of time, as though there are only about 20 or fewer teams in each of the top three leagues, the fourth and fifth divisions have about 64 and 160 teams, respectively. Searching for each team, finding their logo, and adding it to the map took some time, but I’m proud of the resulting <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/d/edit?mid=1KC-087sgP0igiLpJvNpaGj88BWSWNvQ">map</a>.</p>

<p>The map reveals some interesting trivia. Things like, the Southwest of France which is now missing a Ligue 1 team since Bordeaux, the ninth most populous city in France, was relegated to Ligue 2. Looking at the map with all the teams on it, the entirety of France is quite full, except for the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Empty_diagonal">Empty Diagonal</a>, which is quite noticeable in its lack of teams.</p>

<p>I find it interesting to see which little towns have a team in the fifth division, or which cities don’t have any teams at all, such as Aix-en-Provence. As I created the map for the teams in the Championnat National 3, the fifth division of French football, I came across teams whose logos were difficult to find, and often had little information online, Facebook being sometimes their official channel of communication.</p>

<p>Some day perhaps I will create a simple tool which allows me to input a location and calculate the nearest team. Even better, I could give multiple options, and give more weight to teams in better leagues. I would be interested in encouraging support for more local teams in the lower levels of French football by allowing people to search for teams close to them.</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot; =&gt; nil, &quot;avatar&quot; =&gt; nil, &quot;bio&quot; =&gt; &quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot; =&gt; &quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot; =&gt; &quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot; =&gt; [{&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;Eastern Continental Trail&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fas fa-fw fa-mountain&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://easterncontinentaltrail.com/&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I recently completed a map of all the teams in the top five leages in the French Football pyramid. It took quite a bit of time, as though there are only about 20 or fewer teams in each of the top three leagues, the fourth and fifth divisions have about 64 and 160 teams, respectively. Searching for each team, finding their logo, and adding it to the map took some time, but I’m proud of the resulting map.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Fallen Oak Branch</title><link href="/blog/2023/09/fallen-oak-branch.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Fallen Oak Branch" /><published>2023-09-23T09:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-09-23T09:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2023/09/fallen-oak-branch</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2023/09/fallen-oak-branch.html"><![CDATA[<p>This year, we had a bit of a nasty surprise when a large branch of the big oak tree in our back yard split partially at the trunk and fell. I wasn’t home when it split, but apparently the break was quite loud. I feel sad, as I love that oak tree, and I would imagine that it is well over a hundred years old. I suppose that I should have been trimming some of the farther extremities being held by the large branch in order to reduce the weight. In truth, I had never even considered the idea of trimming the tree, as it is so massive that I suppose I had assumed that it could handle itself.</p>

<p>When I say that a branch split off the trunk, that is technically correct. However, the branch in question has a diameter larger than many people, and even the extremities of the branch ten yards from the trunk is over a foot thick. There must be about ten different secondary branches, each of significant size and length.</p>

<p>The branch fell onto other smaller trees in the area both on our property and on the other side of the fence where the train tracks are. Thankfully, the branch was far from the tracks and there was no issue there. The smaller trees bent but did not break, and in between the part of the branch still attached to the trunk and the support of these other trees, the gigantic oak branch never actually reached the ground. This posed quite a problem for me, a software engineer with little landscaping experience and no chainsaw.</p>

<p>I let the branch sit for about half a year while I mourned the loss of part of our beautiful oak tree. I then got to work with my little hand saw, and starting removing branches bit by bit. Always making sure to stay out of harm’s way, I slowly reduced the weight strain on the supporting trees and removed many of the outlying branches. Dutifully sawing them into firewood-sized bits, they were stored in the basement in a growing pile. I attacked the tree almost every day for a couple weeks, and as I got rid of more and more wood, I kept close eye on the gigantic oak branch.</p>

<p>Though I had to slide under our fence and cut from the property belonging to the train tracks, I have finally succeeded in bringing this behemoth to the ground. When I finally cut the final big branch supporting the weight, the fallen oak branch completed its six-month journey to the ground, and split completely from the trunk. I was very relieved to have the branch on the ground, instead of looming in the air where it was a real safety hazard. It would have surely been a fatal accident had it fallen on someone.</p>

<p>I am really proud of my work on the tree, having avoided the expense and trouble of hiring a crew to deal with this thing, and having done the whole project with a handsaw. I estimate I spent a total of twenty hours working on it, sawing bits off the tree, then sawing the bits into smaller bits for storage in the basement. Now all that is left is the large branch on the ground. I think I will leave it there for awhile. I’ve had enough of sawing for quite awhile.</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot; =&gt; nil, &quot;avatar&quot; =&gt; nil, &quot;bio&quot; =&gt; &quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot; =&gt; &quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot; =&gt; &quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot; =&gt; [{&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;Eastern Continental Trail&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fas fa-fw fa-mountain&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://easterncontinentaltrail.com/&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This year, we had a bit of a nasty surprise when a large branch of the big oak tree in our back yard split partially at the trunk and fell. I wasn’t home when it split, but apparently the break was quite loud. I feel sad, as I love that oak tree, and I would imagine that it is well over a hundred years old. I suppose that I should have been trimming some of the farther extremities being held by the large branch in order to reduce the weight. In truth, I had never even considered the idea of trimming the tree, as it is so massive that I suppose I had assumed that it could handle itself.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Chinese Wedding</title><link href="/blog/2023/07/chinese-wedding.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Chinese Wedding" /><published>2023-07-16T12:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-07-16T12:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2023/07/chinese-wedding</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2023/07/chinese-wedding.html"><![CDATA[<p>This summer, we are finally getting a chance to see my wife’s family in China. We were originally scheduled to visit in February 2020, but needless to say COVID ruined those plans. This time, our trip has coincided perfectly with my wife’s sister’s wedding, so we have been doing that for the past few days.</p>

<p>A Chinese wedding is not a simple affair, even by modern Western standards of expensive and overcomplicated weddings. The amount of preparation that goes into the event is enormous. Months in advance, both families organize events together and separately. There are outfits, haircuts, house decorations, car decorations, copious amounts of fireworks, and of course, lots of alcohol.</p>

<p>I didn’t do very much myself in terms of preparation, I simply helped put up some decorations around the house, and some other small things. My wife did more, but as we arrived just a week before the wedding day, we only did a little compared to my wife’s parents.</p>

<p>On the first day of the multi-day affair, my wife and her parents got up at 5:00 in the morning and went to a restaurant near their house to start preparations for the wedding meal. I wasn’t quite so helpful, but I was there at 9 in the morning after spending an hour learning how to tie a bow-tie.</p>

<p>I wore the same outfit that I wore to my brother’s wedding a couple of years ago, a shirt, bow-tie, and vest with pants to match. I was a tad overdressed compared to many people, who showed up in T-shirts, shorts, and sandals. My main job on the wedding day was to offer a special wedding cigarette to each wedding guest as they arrived. Needless to say, I was not too heartbroken when many people kindly refused my offer. Of over a hundred guests, I think I gave out ten cigarettes in two hours.</p>

<p>The kitchen was not big enough to serve everyone, so we waited for a long time to eat after the first half of guests had finished their meal. I tried lots of food not typically found back home, such as eel and turtle. As with all important meals, all the men had to drink alcohol, and I was no exception. Chinese alcohol is basically gasoline as far as I can tell, but I survived.</p>

<p>In China, a wedding is a bit more than a marriage of two people. Many Chinese people will tell you that a marriage is a joining of two families. The second day was my wife’s sister’s husband’s family’s turn to host, and there was a lot of ceremony to accomplish.</p>

<p>Early in the morning, the groom and many men from his family showed up to the hosue to make a big racket and coax his bride to come with him. I believe the idea behind this pretend play is that the woman should want to stay with her parents, and only come with the groom after much heckling.</p>

<p>Next, we all got in cars and drove to the groom’s parents’ house. But we couldn’t drive straight there, as that would be return path for them, and taking such a path would symbolize reversing cours on the marriage, since it would be a direct reversal of the course on the road. Therefore we took a roundabout way which took longer.</p>

<p>After visiting briefly at the house for photos (did I mention that the bride and groom are wearing specialy red outfits, and that the bride had to be carried from her house to the car, then to the groom’s parents house? Her feet of course cannot touch the ground in between the two), we made it to the restaurant, where there were not enough seats for everyone.</p>

<p>We watched a nice little wedding ceremony which symbolized the joining of the two families. It was not a religious ceremony at all, but rather hosted by a Master of Ceremonies who then did some karaoke at the end.</p>

<p>After lunch, rest, and then dinner there, the wedding was done for me, though I believe that there were more things to do for the newlywed couple. In any case, I was more than ready to not eat anything and most importantly not drink anything for a day or two afterwards. I was pretty close to being sick on the second day, but I made it through.</p>

<p>Overall it was interesting, but I’m glad that I didn’t have a Chinese wedding when I got married, and I’m also glad that my wife only has one sibling. This was hopefully my first and last full Chinese wedding.</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot; =&gt; nil, &quot;avatar&quot; =&gt; nil, &quot;bio&quot; =&gt; &quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot; =&gt; &quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot; =&gt; &quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot; =&gt; [{&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;Eastern Continental Trail&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fas fa-fw fa-mountain&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://easterncontinentaltrail.com/&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This summer, we are finally getting a chance to see my wife’s family in China. We were originally scheduled to visit in February 2020, but needless to say COVID ruined those plans. This time, our trip has coincided perfectly with my wife’s sister’s wedding, so we have been doing that for the past few days.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">In Memory of Jonathan</title><link href="/blog/2023/06/in-memory-jonathan.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="In Memory of Jonathan" /><published>2023-06-11T19:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-06-11T19:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2023/06/in-memory-jonathan</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2023/06/in-memory-jonathan.html"><![CDATA[<p>When I was little, my parents didn’t send me to pre-school regularly. I didn’t really play with other children very regularly or make a friend until I went to kindergarten. In my first year of school, I made a couple friends. My first friend was Jonathan. Like many boys, we shared an interest in running fast and playing games, and that was enough to form a solid friendship. While my parents were at to the hospital for several days for my brother’s birth, I was doing my first sleepover at Jonathan’s house. Those first few years of school, we played so many games together. I remember playing with Legos in Jonathan’s room. I remember eating pizza by the pool as we celebrated Jonathan’s birthday. I remember running around his house playing with a home laser tag kit.</p>

<p>While we had fun playing, there emerged quickly signs that I can look back on now and see that Jonathan was different than many of the other kids that we played with. Something about his mental state was different. He always had a fierce attitude, and while he always defended his friends to all extremes, that same energy would sometimes manifest itself in small acts of violence. Hitting girls, even a teacher, was a recurring disciplinary issue from what I remember. Eventually, Jonathan left our elementary school and I didn’t hear from him for a couple years.</p>

<p>In seventh grade, I was transitioning to a young adult and I was not at the top of the social hierarchy, though I had a good group of friends. One day, Jonathan showed up at our school, visiting for a day in order to prepare to return the next year. The change in him was astounding. Gone was the athletic and fiesty boy who frequently got into trouble. Jonathan wore suits and ties, and had his hair heavily gelled back. I was mortified to be the object of ridicule as he tagged along with me.</p>

<p>He came back to our school the next year and wore those suits and ties for several years. I was one of his few friends, but I was still embarassed to hang out with him at school. It was clear that a transition had occurred from elementary to middle school and in some sense Jonathan was on a different path. We were discovering new social situations, popularity, girls, and puberty. He was wearing suits and ties, greasing his hair back, and reading history books. He didn’t do anything athletic, the school allowed him to consider walking his dog as his sports credit.</p>

<p>In high school, video games was what we had in common. Jonathan’s approach to growing up was to acquire new things. When he discovered something new, he bought it. He had an enormous TV with a nice sound system. He had many, many Xbox games, many hard rock CDs, and a big DVD collection. As a teenager you would never have as much stuff at your disposal as when you were hanging out with Jonathan.</p>

<p>One thing remained constant about the Jonathan that I knew from kindergarten: if you were his friend, he would do anything for you. I had a LAN party when Halo 2 came out and Jonathan brought two televisions over to my house, including his gigantic flatscreen. I didn’t need to ask him for things, he wanted to share his latest interests with me. DVDs and Xbox games were loaned, and when I got my own Xbox, he gave me an old TV so that we could play together. Jonathan was indeed a person who made extreme choices, and nothing was more extreme than his willingness to share.</p>

<p>Sadly, as high school progressed, some people took advantage of Jonathan’s kindness to ask him for favors under the pretense of false friendship. With his desire to be accepted, he got involved with whatever was proposed to him, namely marijuana. He ended up crashing his BMW while under the influence and severely injured himself, requiring metal plates and screws in his legs, and was out of school for months. Nearing the end of school, his grades were poor and he didn’t get accepted to many universities.</p>

<p>As our high school friend groups separated to go to different colleges, Jonathan didn’t complete orientation at his new school before he was arrested on a drunk driving charge and kicked out of school before it had even begun. We didn’t have much contact as I was off at university. I believe he eventually joined another university, but after I graduated I saw in the news that he had been arrested for various mischief.</p>

<p>It’s been 16 years since we graduated high school together. That wasn’t the end of Jonathan’s story, but it was the end of our time together. Over the years I occasionally scanned social media and the internet to see how he was doing, but there was no trace. I hoped that someday we would have a class reunion and that I could shake his hand. Perhaps he would be a completely different person than the teenager led astray that I last knew. That reunion never happened. Recently I received news that Jonathan had just ended his own life.</p>

<p>To say that I am sad does not adequately describe my feelings. Jonathan was my first friend. It pained me to see him different than his peers, and it pains me to think about our time together and wonder if I was a good friend to him. I wish that we had remained in contact. I can’t imagine his feelings, seeing that his path was different than so many of his classmates and peers, and dealing with that into adulthood.</p>

<p>I want to cry but I can’t. It seems like I shouldn’t feel much of anything since I have not heard from Jonathan in so many years, but the fact remains he was my first friend, and one of a very few people who I have known throughout my school years. I shouldn’t feel guilty since we have been out of contact so long. And yet, I believe few people have known Jonathan as long or as well as I. It makes me sick to think that he spent his last moments alone. It was a privilege to have gotten to know him, despite his flaws, but I wish there were more good times to come.</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot; =&gt; nil, &quot;avatar&quot; =&gt; nil, &quot;bio&quot; =&gt; &quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot; =&gt; &quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot; =&gt; &quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot; =&gt; [{&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;Eastern Continental Trail&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fas fa-fw fa-mountain&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://easterncontinentaltrail.com/&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[When I was little, my parents didn’t send me to pre-school regularly. I didn’t really play with other children very regularly or make a friend until I went to kindergarten. In my first year of school, I made a couple friends. My first friend was Jonathan. Like many boys, we shared an interest in running fast and playing games, and that was enough to form a solid friendship. While my parents were at to the hospital for several days for my brother’s birth, I was doing my first sleepover at Jonathan’s house. Those first few years of school, we played so many games together. I remember playing with Legos in Jonathan’s room. I remember eating pizza by the pool as we celebrated Jonathan’s birthday. I remember running around his house playing with a home laser tag kit.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Trimming the Hedges</title><link href="/blog/2023/06/trimming-hedges.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Trimming the Hedges" /><published>2023-06-04T09:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-06-04T09:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2023/06/trimming-hedges</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2023/06/trimming-hedges.html"><![CDATA[<p>With the arrival of Spring my mood has picked up considerably, and I have the energy to do a lot of things that I have been putting off for a long time. One of those things is attending to the hedges that separate us from our neighbors. I had taken care of own side of our property a couple of months ago, and had thought that I would do the next side the following weekend. Two months later, I finally got the courage on a Saturday morning to get up early and do it.</p>

<p>We are lucky to have wonderful neighbors who are happy to share a few tools with us. One of those things that we don’t own is a hedge trimmer. Not only did our neighbor lend me his hedge trimmer, but he also lent me a platform on which to stand to trim the top of the hedge. It took me several conversations with him to learn how to start the troublesome gas-powered hedge trimmer. Even with the trimmer on and the choke valve open, the trimmer would start upon pulling the cord, then stop immediately. This sort of experience is one of the more frustrating parts of house projects, as it requires a process to learn how to use troublesome tools that won’t be necessary for another year. Finally I found that I could pull the cord with the choke closed, let the trimmer idle for a bit, then open the choke halfway and rev the engine a few times. After that I could fully open the choke and get to work.</p>

<p>The work itself is very tough. The trimmer is heavy and chopping through the tops of thick hedges is hard work. After a few minutes of that, my forearms were shot and I spent some time collecting and disposing of the hedge trimmings as a way to rest my arms. It has been a few years since I trimmed the hedges, so there was a lot to do, and in total I filled up more than half of the big organic disposal container dedicated to our neighborhood.</p>

<p>Not only did I do my side of the hedge, but I also did my neighbor’s side as technically the hedge is entirely on our property. That effectively doubled my work, as I can only reach half of the hedge from each side, as it is wide. My neighbor is elderly and so I appreciated him moving a few things so that I could access the hedge from his side, but I didn’t ask him to help with the collection of branches or the painful trimming.</p>

<p>I started working before 10 in the morning, and didn’t finish until almost 4 in the afternoon. One day later, my arms are covered in scrapes, but thankfully the rashes are mostly gone. There is a reason that I haven’t trimmed the hedges in a few years, and I’m not sure I’ll have the courages to do it all again next year.</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot; =&gt; nil, &quot;avatar&quot; =&gt; nil, &quot;bio&quot; =&gt; &quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot; =&gt; &quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot; =&gt; &quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot; =&gt; [{&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;Eastern Continental Trail&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fas fa-fw fa-mountain&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://easterncontinentaltrail.com/&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the arrival of Spring my mood has picked up considerably, and I have the energy to do a lot of things that I have been putting off for a long time. One of those things is attending to the hedges that separate us from our neighbors. I had taken care of own side of our property a couple of months ago, and had thought that I would do the next side the following weekend. Two months later, I finally got the courage on a Saturday morning to get up early and do it.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">An Alabama Dirt Roadwalk</title><link href="/blog/2023/05/alabama-dirt-roadwalk.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An Alabama Dirt Roadwalk" /><published>2023-05-27T09:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-05-27T09:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2023/05/alabama-dirt-roadwalk</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2023/05/alabama-dirt-roadwalk.html"><![CDATA[<p>Lately, I’ve been doing a lot of work on the website that I’ve created for the Eastern Continental Trail. As I continue to think about the subject, one of the things which comes to the forefront of my mind is the Alabama Roadwalk, which sticks out as the only portion of the ECT between Key West and Québec where a thru-hiker is continuously on paved roads for almost 200 miles. While pondering this, my curiosity got the better of me when I had the question “How much of the Alamaba roadwalk could be done on dirt roads?”. This Google Earth <a href="/assets/resources/exploration/eastern-continental-trail/ar-dirt-alternative.kmz">file</a> is the result.</p>

<p>The two main appeals of dirt roads for hikers is that the dirt is softer than a paved road and therefore causes fewer problems for the feet, and there are fewer people in the area in general, meaning fewer cars passing by. The areas that dirt roads travel through are of course more remote as well, which is often a desirable aspect for thru-hikers. That being said, this same remoteness comes with the disadvantage that there are very few services in the area. Most importantly, issues like uncontrolled dogs and suspicious homeowners would be more of a problem in remote areas where people are not used to seeing thru-hikers.</p>

<p>Mapping out a dirt roadwalk took considerable time, as I needed to have a global sense of which regions of Alabama had plenty of dirt roads going North-South. I also had to backtrack several times as I found myself mapping a section that led into an area with no dirt roads at all. My goal was to put the roadwalk on dirt roads as much as possible, while still keeping it generally in line with the route between the Florida and Pinhoti trails.</p>

<p>The result is a 50 mile increase over the original 200 mile roadwalk, as dirt roads are much less direct. In total, I would estimate that about 200 of these miles are on dirt roads. Certain portions of the state have no dirt roads, and as Montgomery and the Alabama River form a big obstacle that must be bypassed on either the East or West. My choice was to head West and go through Selma, then come back East across the Coosa River and take the path on the Coosa Trail as the current Alabama Roadwalk does.</p>

<p>On its winding path, the Dirt Roadwalk avoids any cities or towns, with the exception of Selma, which must be traversed to cross the Alabama River to the West of Montgomery. It specifically goes through sparsely-populated areas and rarely passes by a store of any kind. It would make for an intesting walk in theory, though in practice it’s unclear how encounters in the deep backcountry of Alabama would play out for a thru-hiker.</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot; =&gt; nil, &quot;avatar&quot; =&gt; nil, &quot;bio&quot; =&gt; &quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot; =&gt; &quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot; =&gt; &quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot; =&gt; [{&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot; =&gt; &quot;Eastern Continental Trail&quot;, &quot;icon&quot; =&gt; &quot;fas fa-fw fa-mountain&quot;, &quot;url&quot; =&gt; &quot;https://easterncontinentaltrail.com/&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lately, I’ve been doing a lot of work on the website that I’ve created for the Eastern Continental Trail. As I continue to think about the subject, one of the things which comes to the forefront of my mind is the Alabama Roadwalk, which sticks out as the only portion of the ECT between Key West and Québec where a thru-hiker is continuously on paved roads for almost 200 miles. While pondering this, my curiosity got the better of me when I had the question “How much of the Alamaba roadwalk could be done on dirt roads?”. This Google Earth file is the result.]]></summary></entry></feed>