<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-01-30T11:23:18+01:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Sterling Coleman</title><subtitle>A space for my personal projects and thoughts</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">The Sequelize Saga</title><link href="/blog/2021/01/sequelize-saga.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Sequelize Saga" /><published>2021-01-30T11:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-01-30T11:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/01/sequelize-saga</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/01/sequelize-saga.html">&lt;p&gt;Recently I found the source to a very befuddling problem that I had been grappling with on and off again for weeks. As a warning to other developers, I’d like to recount my tale of woe. The subject here is Sequelize, which is an ORM (Objet Relational Mapping) tool which can be used to query a database from the backend of a web application. Sequelize is quite versatile, being available for use with Postgres, MySQL, MariaDB, SQLite and Microsoft SQL Server. In this saga, Sequelize is querying a Postgres database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The utility of a tool like Sequelize is that it can abstract the database to models and functions. Models can be defined, and these models represent tables. These models then expose simple functions, which represent types of queries. One of the more useful examples is the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bulkCreate&lt;/code&gt; function, which can insert multiple records into a table in just one function call. This type of function is especially useful when performing operations on large sets of data, such as a data migration. We can simply construct an array of models and pass that array to the function. The function inserts each model as a record in the specified table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what does it return? In Postgres, the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;RETURNING&lt;/code&gt; keyword can be used to define what values are returned from the query. Therefore, Sequelize has the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;returning&lt;/code&gt; option, which activates this option. Postgres even has extra functionality for this feature, allowing an array of fields to return to be passed instead of a simple boolean if desired. But when I search the internet for “bulkCreate”, I can see that there may be issues, based on the fact that the top five results are all for Sequelize, and two of those results are for issues. One of these stemmed from a simple lack of knowledge of this option, and the other is a real issue logged on the site for the GitHub repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of GitHub issues, the Sequelize currently has over a thousand opened issues. That speaks partly to the popularity of the tool. The GitHub repository has over twenty thousand stars. It also demonstrates that the application has some issues. Currently, there are almost fifty open issues related to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bulkCreate&lt;/code&gt;. One of the main topics is the same issue that I ran into: namely, that on one environment, Sequelize returned the IDs of newly-created records from &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bulkCreate&lt;/code&gt;, while on another environment, the exact same line of code did not. The call did not pass &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;returning: true&lt;/code&gt;, meaning that according to the current &lt;a href=&quot;https://sequelize.org/master/class/lib/model.js~Model.html&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;, the default value used is &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;false&lt;/code&gt;. So why did one instance of the code magically return the ID anyway?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, according to this &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sequelize/sequelize/issues/12711&quot;&gt;issue&lt;/a&gt;, the documentation is wrong! The default value is actually &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;true&lt;/code&gt;. But if that is the case, why does one version of the code not return the newly-created IDs? To explain that, we first have to acknowledge that the code should explicitly pass &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;returning: true&lt;/code&gt;, as the documentation suggests, if it expects to use these IDs. Expecting the function to return these IDs by magic is unacceptable, despite it being the admitted behavior as stated in the GitHub issue. Next, we have to examine our use of package versions to be sure that we are using the same version of Sequelize in both cases. Given that we performed an &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;npm install&lt;/code&gt; on both environments, we would hope that the same version would be installed in both cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alas, the way that we have defined our package dependencies leaves room for error. If we define the Sequelize dependency as &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;^5.1.0&lt;/code&gt;, then an &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;npm install&lt;/code&gt; will check to see if we have at least that major and minor version, and if we do, it won’t upgrade the package. In the case that it does need to upgrade, it will get the latest minor version, such as 5.22. Unfortunately, version 5.22 works as explained in the GitHub issue, whereas version 5.3 works as the documentation describes. Whether or not this is a breaking change is debatable, given that it is difficult to imagine a scenario in which we are creating multiple records, and expecting to not have the IDs returned, and that having them returned breaks our logic. But it certainly should be documented behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is that combining mistakes in our version logic, the code, and the Sequelize repository leads to a big headache. If we want to allow our application a margin of error for these types of things, it may be better to use an ORM which at least behaves as documented. Ultimately, the application should define specific version of packages, especially in the case of Sequelize, such that extra steps such as removing the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;node_modules&lt;/code&gt; directory are not needed to ensure that two different environments have the same packages. And finally, we have to write code that makes sense. If we expect &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bulkCreate&lt;/code&gt; to return something, then we need to tell it to do that.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Recently I found the source to a very befuddling problem that I had been grappling with on and off again for weeks. As a warning to other developers, I’d like to recount my tale of woe. The subject here is Sequelize, which is an ORM (Objet Relational Mapping) tool which can be used to query a database from the backend of a web application. Sequelize is quite versatile, being available for use with Postgres, MySQL, MariaDB, SQLite and Microsoft SQL Server. In this saga, Sequelize is querying a Postgres database.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On the Trail: Matthew Hengst</title><link href="/blog/2021/01/matthew-hengst.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On the Trail: Matthew Hengst" /><published>2021-01-24T20:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-01-24T20:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/01/matthew-hengst</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/01/matthew-hengst.html">&lt;p&gt;During a recent conversation with my parents, I mentioned that it was a shame that no one had recently surfaced on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://trailjournals.com&quot;&gt;Trail Journals&lt;/a&gt; site with a journal of a hike on the Eastern Continental Trail. Ever since I hiked the ECT in 2012, I’ve been keen to read other people’s experiences. Sadly, very few seem to take on the challenge of a hike covering the length of the East Coast in the United States as well as a portion of Canada. Of course, I know that not everyone publishes their hiking efforts online, and of those who do, not everyone uses the same website which I used when I hiked the trail. So, I did a quick search on the internet to see if by chance I could find information elsewhere, and I happened to come across Matthew Hengst!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matthew started hiking North on the Eastern Continental Trail just before New Year, which is about the same timing as the beginning of my own hike, way back in 2012. He is already an experienced thru-hiker, having just finished the Pacific Crest Trail last year. He also has a nice &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.firstchurchofthemasochist.com/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;, with links to his Instagram and YouTube accounts, both of which have good content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s rare to find someone hiking the Eastern Continental Trail at all. It’s even more rare to find someone doing the trip and simultaneously putting out good content. When I did the trail, I personally struggled to write down my thoughts into journal entries, often having to take time to write entries for the past several days all at once. For that reason, I’m impressed that Matthew is able to compile videos of a decent length every few days. I’m sure it takes a lot of work. I have been enjoying the videos, as I know the trail and I understand a bit of what a hiker experiences on this trail. Through the videos, I can see that Matthew is going to do well on his thru-hike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first portion of the hike, from the Southernmost Point in the Continental United States to the beginning of the Florida Trail, can easily discourage hikers and get them to quit the hike before it has really begun. There were few good spots to camp in the Florida Keys back in 2012, and it can only have gotten more difficult since then. Increased traffic and COVID-19 can only made hiking harder, but Matthew has taken it all in stride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He has not started out doing needlessly ambitious days of more than thirty miles like I did, and he seems to have done a better job planning his stopping point for each night well in advance. Hiking in the Keys, while a unique experience, can be uniquely frustrating, so from my perspective the fact that Matthew can just accept these frustrations and move on shows that once he gets onto more secluded trails in Florida, there won’t be much stopping him from succeeding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think Matthew is going to enjoy the trail, and I hope that others enjoy his videos and photos. I’m a big advocate of the Eastern Continental Trail, and the best way to advocate for it is to show off all the cool stuff there is on this trail, in places like Florida. Even the unique experience of hiking along the Overseas Heritage Trail in the Florida Keys is something many people in the hiking community haven’t seen. Matthew is doing a great job of showing off what the ECT has to offer, and I’ll definitely be following along with this journey and rooting for him all along the way.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">During a recent conversation with my parents, I mentioned that it was a shame that no one had recently surfaced on the Trail Journals site with a journal of a hike on the Eastern Continental Trail. Ever since I hiked the ECT in 2012, I’ve been keen to read other people’s experiences. Sadly, very few seem to take on the challenge of a hike covering the length of the East Coast in the United States as well as a portion of Canada. Of course, I know that not everyone publishes their hiking efforts online, and of those who do, not everyone uses the same website which I used when I hiked the trail. So, I did a quick search on the internet to see if by chance I could find information elsewhere, and I happened to come across Matthew Hengst!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Snow Weekend</title><link href="/blog/2021/01/snow-weekend.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Snow Weekend" /><published>2021-01-17T17:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-01-17T17:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/01/snow-weekend</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/01/snow-weekend.html">&lt;p&gt;On Saturday morning, my wife left the house early to head into Paris and get some specific items from a Chinese grocery store. Given the time it takes to get there and back, and also knowing that she would be going with a friend, I knew that I had the children all to myself for the entire morning, until noon or even a little after. Little did I know that this Saturday morning would be an especially exciting time for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought I might get lucky and be able to sleep in, but less than ten minutes after my wife had left the house, our son Daniel found me, and was upset that his mother was not there. Pretty soon his sister arrived as well, and we were all in bed together. I let them watch an old Asterix movie, which is a classic French cartoon, as well as a Wallace and Gromit film. I went to work on my computer, but after awhile was ready to get up, so I finally opened up the shutters, which is when I realized it had been snowing for awhile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Opening up the shutters to a world of whiteness is a special feeling. It harkens back to childhood, waking up to a snow day, seeing that it had snowed overnight and the ground was no longer visible, being instead covered with a white blanket of snow. The children of course noticed the snow just as quickly. Once they saw that it, they were very excited, and immediately wanted to go out and play. Daniel, being just two years old, enjoyed simply staring out the window to watch the snow fall lightly into our back yard. Miriam preferred to pester me in constantly asking when we were going to go out to play. Daniel quickly joined in to make it a chorus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preparing children to go out in the snow is a pain. They have to have a lot of clothing on, but they don’t want it. Once they get outside and fall down, they complain that they are cold and wet. I was lucky in that the children didn’t complain too much when I insisted on several layers. Unfortunately, Miriam’s best coat was not waterproof, and I don’t know if we have snow gloves for anybody. We just went out with the best we could come up with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I immediately noticed was that my wife had not left any footprints in the snow when she left, meaning that in just a few hours, everything had been completely covered in snow. The next thing I remarked is that there are limited options for playing in the snow with small children. We ran around, hit the windows with a couple snowballs, and played hide and seek in the snow. I’m glad nobody tried to make a snow angel, although Daniel did slip and fall several times. After less than an hour playing outside, everyone was ready to go back into the house, where I finally succeeded in getting the fire going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would seem that I’ve turned into a bit of a Grinch since my youth, as I was very happy to be back inside and away from the snow. The main thing that I noticed about snow is that it is very cold and wet. While during my childhood I may have looked past this in order to go sledding, this weekend I mostly just wanted to avoid the cold and wet snow. Thankfully, the children had their fun and the snow was beautiful to watch from the comfort of our house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the best part of the snow weekend for me was that it ended the next day. Today when I went out, the snow was completely gone from the roads, and elsewhere only a little remained. Snow is fun for a day, but when it bogs down school, work, and the commute during the week, it loses its charm. We had a good weekend in the snow, and made a few memories with the children. Even so, I’m happy that the snow weekend will remain just the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">On Saturday morning, my wife left the house early to head into Paris and get some specific items from a Chinese grocery store. Given the time it takes to get there and back, and also knowing that she would be going with a friend, I knew that I had the children all to myself for the entire morning, until noon or even a little after. Little did I know that this Saturday morning would be an especially exciting time for them.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Living Ultralight</title><link href="/blog/2021/01/living-ultralight.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Living Ultralight" /><published>2021-01-10T19:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-01-10T19:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/01/living-ultralight</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/01/living-ultralight.html">&lt;p&gt;As it is the beginning of a new year, we recently renewed our Navigo passes for the whole year. Although it is a bit painful to pay for the whole year up front, I prefer that to giving out bank account information for monthly payments. The choice to use the public transportation system exclusively puts us in the minority for middle class families well outside of Paris. In fact, we are the only family in our neighborhood without a car. Rather than go over why we don’t have a car, a topic which I’ve covered previously, I think it would be more interesting to explain the philosophy behind these types of decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a philosophy very similar to ultralight hiking, in which the hiker attempts to reduce the weight of the backpack and its contents by as much as possible. Just like a hiker has the capacity to carry weight, our family has the capacity to pay for things and to manage things. Also similarly to the hiker’s backpack, payments and the time needed to manage our affairs are a burden. When hiking ultralight, a person has to identify the things they absolutely must have, such as a sleeping bag, food, etc. and come up with a strategy to carry all the necessities while minimizing the weight. Nothing is an objective decision, as one could always argue about the necessity of some of the stuff a person carries, and if a lighter version of the gear is available, but with fewer features, etc. In life, we face the same type of decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can handle buying a car, and paying for insurance, and paying for gas, and paying for a driver’s license for my wife. We could pay for occasional repairs. A hiker could say the same type of thing, and many do. It always bothers me immensely when a hiker claims that there is more convenience or comfort to carrying a lot of luxury items. I remember when I met the first hiker who said that, in Southern Florida. He and his partner were taking a break to smoke because their 70 pound packs had tired them out after less than a mile into Big Cypress National Preserve. He saw my small pack and explained that they brought more stuff in order to be comfortable. The problem that ultralight hikers have identified with this is that the logic doesn’t add up. Distance hikers are obligated to spend more time hiking than camping, and it is decidedly inconvenient to carry a lot of stuff that does not get used much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The payments aren’t the only issue. Time spent managing things is a real drag. For example, I always cringe when I open up an application and see that it has included a hundred or so modules of all different types. Even if there are some strategies to minimize the burden of loading or build times, developers won’t even know when modules are no longer used, as there are simply too many to track. The bottom line is that we need to stop thinking if we can do the job by adding something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to figure out if it is possible to do the job without adding anything. If not, perhaps we can exchange something we currently use for something else which can do multiple things. For a hiker, that could be my stealth quilt, which served as a sleeping bag as well as a wearable down layer on the few occasions when the cold merited it. For my family, that could be a trailer for my bicycle, which I can use to get groceries, Christmas trees, or packages. It’s not a lot of fun getting groceries with the bicycle, but it is immensely satisfying not to pay for a car. I always go with the light solution that can still work without being too inconvenient, and I have a higher tolerance than most for inconveniences. It’s a strategy that has been working well so far, and that we hope will work again this year.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">As it is the beginning of a new year, we recently renewed our Navigo passes for the whole year. Although it is a bit painful to pay for the whole year up front, I prefer that to giving out bank account information for monthly payments. The choice to use the public transportation system exclusively puts us in the minority for middle class families well outside of Paris. In fact, we are the only family in our neighborhood without a car. Rather than go over why we don’t have a car, a topic which I’ve covered previously, I think it would be more interesting to explain the philosophy behind these types of decisions.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Year, New Challenges</title><link href="/blog/2021/01/new-year-new-challenges.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Year, New Challenges" /><published>2021-01-03T13:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-01-03T13:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/01/new-year-new-challenges</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/01/new-year-new-challenges.html">&lt;p&gt;2020 is finished, and a new year is upon us. At the beginning of a new year, I like to think about what I want to have accomplished by the end of the year. I think it’s important to specifically set goals. Otherwise, what happens is that time just passes, and pretty soon another year is gone, and I may look back and wish I had done something differently. Some things may come up naturally and be more easily accomplished, but others require planning a series of smaller steps, or at least specific reminders to get something done on time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good example would be learning Chinese. I’ll be going for the HSK (Han Shuo Ke) Level 4 Certificate this year, which means that I need to continuously study character meanings, a bit of grammar, and even some writing. This isn’t something that I can put off, and I need to at least register for the test by a certain time of year. I did this in 2019 for HSK Level 3 and had no problems, so if I study a little bit every day, I should be ready for Level 4 this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning a language is just one of the categories in whih I like to plan advancements. There is also my career, which was the main focus of the previous year, and will continue to be an important subject for the foreseeable future. I want to continue to improve my skills as a CTO. I want to keep looking for better ways for our developers to deliver their solutions and corrections to our application. This past year, I have personally grown a lot as a Lead Developer. Now that I have a solid grasp on our application, I want to shift a bit of that focus onto increasing the skills of other developers. This involves things like implementing best practices in the development process, but starts with  just having more discussions to clarify what we are doing and how that is going to further our long-term goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are other subjects that I will include, such as improvements to our home, or improving our childrens’ English skills. Most goals have to be conscious decisions that are planned accordingly, otherwise the children will speak English at a decent level, but spelling, reading, and writing will all be delayed. Even though one subject can be the focus for a year, I feel that it is important to have a variety of different types of things that are all addressed. This achieves a sense of balance, and ensures that things don’t get forgotten or left unaddressed the whole year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the same vein of thought, I try not to make my goals too big for any one subject. I just want to make small advancements each year, but to make sure that the challenges which I do take on, indeed get done. For example, my plan for our home this year is to finally finish the bedrooms, which basically just need carpetting, and to redo the downstairs bathroom. That is plenty of work by itself. It’s true that I have other plans for our kitchen and eventually the basement, but I’m not going to overwhelm myself thinking about all of that right now. I’m just going to prioritize a couple of important things, and those other improvements can be goals for subsequent years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my mind, half the battle is already won by simply recognizing the importance of the process. Once the annual goals have been defined, they are not easily forgotten. Certain things, like reading a book a month, used to be difficult to manage. Now, it is an automatic process that I organize each year. It’s not even really part of my list of goals anymore, because I don’t need to think about it. A new year is a new opportunity for new things to get done, and to feel good for being organized enough to plan out the important challenges which should be addressed.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">2020 is finished, and a new year is upon us. At the beginning of a new year, I like to think about what I want to have accomplished by the end of the year. I think it’s important to specifically set goals. Otherwise, what happens is that time just passes, and pretty soon another year is gone, and I may look back and wish I had done something differently. Some things may come up naturally and be more easily accomplished, but others require planning a series of smaller steps, or at least specific reminders to get something done on time.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The End of 2020</title><link href="/blog/2020/12/end-of-2020.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The End of 2020" /><published>2020-12-27T14:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-27T14:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/12/end-of-2020</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/12/end-of-2020.html">&lt;p&gt;Compared to most people, we have weathered 2020 quite well. The story of 2020 for us was one of many changes. Of course, COVID-19 was the cause of some of that, but not all. We had never been stagnant in previous years, but had instead tackled big subjects, like the birth of our children or a new house. This year we didn’t have one big challenge like that, but we had a lot of different things come up, some bigger than others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started off the year with a new job at a new company. It was a good job, and an opportunity to learn lots of new things, notably Git and ReactJS, as well as NestJS and a few other backend NodeJS frameworks. Despite the new start, I was clear to take a trip with my family to Wuhan during the Winter break in February. COVID-19 crushed that plan. We followed the news closely, and at the time would have probably gone to Wuhan anyway had the airline not cancelled the flight. Over the course of the next few weeks we would find that it was for the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, COVID-19 failed to cancel the Rambouillet Half-Marathon, which I completed at the beginning of March. France had put out an order that gatherings of over one thousand people were not allowed just the day before, but that was too late to stop the event, which went on anyway. I knew that I would have pain in my knee, but I finished the event anyway. Pretty soon afterward, the order to stay at home was sent out, and the financial market took a serious hit, effectively ending my new job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, an even bigger opportunity immediately filled that gap. I became a CTO / Lead Developer at a small company, and have been quickly gaining experience and increasing my skills ever since.  With all the missed plans, missed school, and work changes that were brought on by the Coronavirus, it was a big relief for us to be able to take a long vacation to Higgins Lake back in the United States during the summer. That was a big break for us, and allowed us to get away from the pressure of quarantines and work for a few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back at work and back to school, we’ve gotten a lot done since then. Miriam has been working on her spelling, reading, writing, basic addition and even a little subtraction. She has been making so many drawings that I think she must have given one to her teachers each week, and left so many at home that we can’t keep track of them all. Drawing has definitely been her go-to activity this year, and now after receiving her Christmas presents, painting is her new thing. I’ve even gotten her interested in playing LittleBigPlanet on the PlayStation 3. She can do the easiest levels, having overcome her fear of failure on the simplest tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, I’ve just finished my reading list for this year. This is a big accomplishment, given that I was lagging behind severely after six months. The books which I read this year were pretty interesting, and I’m proud of myself for selecting and finishing my list of twelve books for the year. I read some pretty big history books as well as some shorter adventure novels. I must have covered at least six books in the last three months of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My saintly wife has made having the holidays at home a treat. Though Halloween was pretty much cancelled because of the pandemic, we had wonderful meals at home for both Thanksgiving and Christmas. Our little family of four had a great time together celebrating the holidays. For me, this is a good sign that though the pandemic may not be over quickly, and in fact even when it is over all may not go back to normal, we always have each other. We don’t just stick it out together, we have fun together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2020 was obviously the year of the Coronavirus, but that was just the foundation of many of the challenges that we faced and conquered. The next year will bring more challenges, and we look forward to tackling those too. Missing out on school, work, and seeing our family is not fun in and of itself, but those situations make us stronger. This is good, because I’m convinced that though we may have seen the worst of the Coronavirus, the pandemic itself is not the biggest problem we face, and the next year may prove to be just as challenging, if not more, than this past year has been.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Compared to most people, we have weathered 2020 quite well. The story of 2020 for us was one of many changes. Of course, COVID-19 was the cause of some of that, but not all. We had never been stagnant in previous years, but had instead tackled big subjects, like the birth of our children or a new house. This year we didn’t have one big challenge like that, but we had a lot of different things come up, some bigger than others.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Making Christmas Traditions</title><link href="/blog/2020/12/making-christmas-traditions.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Making Christmas Traditions" /><published>2020-12-20T21:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-20T21:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/12/making-christmas-traditions</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/12/making-christmas-traditions.html">&lt;p&gt;France and America have some big differences when it comes to the Christmas season. The one I think of in November is that there is no Thanksgiving holiday to provide a buffer between Halloween and Christmas. Though the French don’t typically start singing their Christmas carols in early November, they also don’t have any reason to wait until December to put up their Christmas decorations and encourage the holiday shopping season to start. So for us, the Christmas season has been building up for a while. But now, with just a few more days until Christmas Day, it really does feel like Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we are doing a smaller Christmas at home this year, just the four of us, my wife pointed out the importance of making Christmas special. I’m very happy that she wants to make this Christmas special, as Christmas is not really a big celebration back in China, so I wasn’t raelly expecting her to go all out. But she pointed out that it is important for our children to have good memories of Christmas, and for us to make Christmas special with some traditions just for us. I think that she also wants to make Christmas an enjoyable time for me, and has already proposed a big turkey dinner, with lots of stuff to eat on the side. Though I will probably need to prepare my holidays sweatpants for the aftermath, I am grateful to have a wife who is willing to put a lot of effort into making this holiday special for all of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have contributed a bit as well by bringing a Christmas tree back from our local grocery store parking lot. This is not as small a thing as it may seem since I had to bring it back on the bicycle trailer. The trees become available at the beginning of December, and though I try to wait awhile before getting ours, I’m always concerned about being left with few good options, as there is a limited selection and some are much more expensive than others. So I got the tree almost three weeks before Christmas, and it has been shedding pine needles in the corner of our living room ever since. Well, ever since I cut the top foot off of it, because I can never remember how tall our living room ceiling is when I’m buying Christmas trees, and I figure that bigger is better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And underneath our tree, the presents have been steadily multiplying. It seems that every year, I think that we’ll just have a few gifts to give out and that will be fine. After all, our children are young and we don’t need a lot of gifts to enjoy the holidays. And every year, a few gifts quickly turns into enough to fill up all the space underneath the tree. We start out with a few things that we picked up, usually toys for the kids. Pretty soon, we start getting packages in the mail every other day, and if the gifts aren’t labeled, we have a hard time keeping track of which is from whom, as we have so many. We’re blessed to have family that takes the extra effort to send gifts from overseas. That takes more time and planning, and is more of an expense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t got a concrete plan for starting a big events, but the great thing is that we are all together for the next week. School is out for two full weeks, and I’m off work for one full week. That leaves us plenty of time to hang out together and enjoy the season. We may not have a White Christmas, but on most days we have a wonderful fire going in our fireplace. My wife spent a little extra to put some basic ornaments on the tree, and of course our daughter Miriam never gets tired of making drawings to decorate the tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great traditions are often just activities that come naturally, like playing games in the house with the kids. The big planned outings and events are fun too, but they kind of are expected to be. The memories that I enjoy the most are the unexpected joys of laughing and spending time with family members, often doing nothing more than talking. Those are the types of memories that we will hopefully be making as we spend time together this Christmas, just the four of us.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">France and America have some big differences when it comes to the Christmas season. The one I think of in November is that there is no Thanksgiving holiday to provide a buffer between Halloween and Christmas. Though the French don’t typically start singing their Christmas carols in early November, they also don’t have any reason to wait until December to put up their Christmas decorations and encourage the holiday shopping season to start. So for us, the Christmas season has been building up for a while. But now, with just a few more days until Christmas Day, it really does feel like Christmas.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Frostpunk</title><link href="/blog/2020/12/frostpunk.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Frostpunk" /><published>2020-12-13T09:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-13T09:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/12/frostpunk</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/12/frostpunk.html">&lt;p&gt;I’m a little hesitant to spend time talking about a video game, but I think that given how much time I have spent playing this game recently, and the amount of time I have spent thinking about the game, it is only right that I dedicate a post to the game. The game of which I am speaking is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frostpunkgame.com/&quot;&gt;Frostpunk&lt;/a&gt;, a strategy game released in 2018 by developer &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.11bitstudios.com/&quot;&gt;11-bit studios&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frostpunk is a strategy game and a city-building game. There are already many games in this genre, and I have played some very good city-building games over the years. What drew me to this game was that it is a very different style than most city-building games. In fact, in some ways it could be classified as a survival game. In Frostpunk, the player must build a city which can survive in a frozen wasteland which becomes gradually colder over time.  As the temperature falls, the citizens of the city need to continue to stay warm at home and at work, in addition to being able to eat. In order to make that happen, resources needed to be gathered, research must be done, buildings must be built, and choices must be made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have really been enjoying this game, but that is not a surprise since I enjoy most strategy games. Strategy games give me the ability to be in control of something with a global view of the situation, instead of simply controlling one character. These games also don’t typically require expensive gaming computers, which is convenient. What’s fun about strategy games for me is being the one in charge, and making every decision. In such a position, I can put my own personal touch on new buildings and the city. I can organize the city in the way that I like. For example, in a typical city-building game, I can create a nice grid layout which satisfies me, organized by type of building. Oddly enough, organizing things is a big part of the fun for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frostpunk is different. First of all, it is set during the the late nineteenth century, in a fictional setting in which extreme climate events have entered the Earth into a period of extreme cold. There are no modern technologies, and the city-building doesn’t involve setting up a university or subway system. Next, the city is organized around a generator, in a circular shape, instead of the typical grid. That alone is a big change. Streets still need to be created, but they are simple wooden walkways. Like many strategy games, resources need to be collected, but in this scenario coal must be collected for heat, wood and steel for construction and research, and finally food to keep people alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frostpunk also mixes in exploration, by demanding the player to organize scouts to go out beyond the city and find resources or other survivors and even cities. These become a big part of the strategy as well as the story as scouts discover what is happening outside the city. Ultimately the main differene between Frostpunk and a normal city-building game is that it uses the increasing cold as the factor which drives the story and game forward. The temperature must decrease in order to continually challenge the player to keep all citizens alive and in good health, while also advancing on other frontiers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, strategy games like Frostpunk aren’t just an enjoyable way to spend time. At its most basic level, the game is a game of resource management. The player starts out with nothing but some people, and based on how the player uses their citizens’ time, the player either succeeds or fails. The order in which things are done is very important. Often, a short-term goal must be reached in order to survive, but long-term goals must also be balanced in order to be prepared for future challenges, such as a further drop in temperature, or a need for an increase in the production of a certain resource, or the need for a certain advanced type of research to be completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the same type of thinking which we employ in real life. We have short term goals, but we also have long term plans, and we have to keep those in mind as well. Based on what I’ve learned from games such as Frostpunk, I usally prioritize long-term plans, and I rarely go for the easier option which requires less effort or resources. At work, it’s important to immediately realize a new feature or fix a bug immediately, but I also highly value moving towards long-term goals such as fixes the global architecture of the application, or implementing some best practice. Achieving the long-term goals makes the short-term issues easier to resolve. Ideally all short-term goals would fit into the long-term picture, but sometimes in life, as in Frostpunk, that isn’t the case.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">I’m a little hesitant to spend time talking about a video game, but I think that given how much time I have spent playing this game recently, and the amount of time I have spent thinking about the game, it is only right that I dedicate a post to the game. The game of which I am speaking is Frostpunk, a strategy game released in 2018 by developer 11-bit studios.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What I’m Watching: Jomboy</title><link href="/blog/2020/12/watching-jomboy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What I'm Watching: Jomboy" /><published>2020-12-06T20:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-06T20:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/12/watching-jomboy</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/12/watching-jomboy.html">&lt;p&gt;Sometime during the baseball season I stumbled upon a YouTube channel called Jomboy Media. Jomboy has a fantastic channel, with many videos of just a few minutes, called “breakdowns”. Each one focuses on a single part of a game, usually a baseball game, and makes it entertaining. That in itself is a huge achievement considering that I am not a big of fan baseball, would never watch a full baseball game, and would not of my own volition seek to understand all the nuances of the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is interesting to me is that this channel has actually made me more interested in baseball than I was before, which, as stated, is no small feat. No major sports media outlet has ever interested me in how a pitcher may be tipping his pitches, or how players on different baseball teams react to one another. What sets Jomboy Media apart is that it brings me as the viewer into the baseball world and makes it more personal and human. The main way this is done is through very good lip-reading and second-by-second narration of what the players in the video are saying and thinking. Did I mention that it is done in a very humorous way? The point of the video is to entertain, but in doing so, some videos inevitable educate the viewer on the mentality of the players, the unknown rules of the game, and the minute details that I would never have picked up on if I were watching a typicall broadcast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, Jomboy doesn’t just cover baseball. The most popular video to date is a commentary on the 2012 Inuit Ear Pulling championship. If it sounds silly, just watch the video while listening to Jomboy (Jimmy O’Brien) do the commentary. Between that, Finnish Baseball, Teqball, and many other unusual sports, there is a lot of good material for Jomboy’s entertaining commentary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the channel isn’t just cheap entertainment. Jomboy was actually on the leading edge of the cheating scandal from the Houston Astros 2017 season. Just hours after The Athletic posted details of the subject for the first time, Jomboy Media had a video up breaking down exactly how the Astros were making noise in the dugout to signal certain pitches to the batter, and that the information gained at that speed could never have been done without using a camera. The breakdown format is hilarious when dubbing over a player’s thoughts in an already-entertaining situation, and it is also informative for investigating details. It’s clearly a format that is working well for Jomboy, and one that shows how online sports content is very much different than traditional cable television sports coverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Online, as a viewer I am much faster to change pages or videos, meaning that the videos of just a few minutes are perfect. I don’t really need a former player or experienced television presenter to narrate everything to me. Certainly, inside knowledge of the sport is needed for the more in-depth breakdowns, which is where Jomboy shows that he knows his stuff. I don’t want to wait until the end of the season for a well-compiled Top 10 list. I might just be interested to see something unusual that happened yesterday for a minute or two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I think that it’s better to get the information from an intelligent sports fan that to get it from a sports celebrity. When watching Jomboy, it feels like a friend is sharing something funny and interesting with me, and I don’t spend a lot of time thinking about the narrator. By comparison, I think too many of the modern commentators and personaltiies found on television seem to be injecting themselves as a type of character into the story. They do this with funny voices or fake outrage, but I would prefer to just be entertained by the sports rather than a sideshow. Jomboy’s entertainment comes directly from the baseball action itself, which (again), is quite impressive considering just how unentertaining I normally find baseball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think my interest in Jomboy’s channel and my continual visits to see what new breakdowns have been published shows an alternative to traditional television sports journalism. Whether or not that ends up being ultimately beneficial for sports business or players, or even viewers, remains to be seen. At the very least, I can affirm that Jomboy’s channel is highly entertaining, and has shed new light on baseball for me.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Sometime during the baseball season I stumbled upon a YouTube channel called Jomboy Media. Jomboy has a fantastic channel, with many videos of just a few minutes, called “breakdowns”. Each one focuses on a single part of a game, usually a baseball game, and makes it entertaining. That in itself is a huge achievement considering that I am not a big of fan baseball, would never watch a full baseball game, and would not of my own volition seek to understand all the nuances of the game.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Thanksgiving Abroad</title><link href="/blog/2020/11/thanksgiving-abroad.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thanksgiving Abroad" /><published>2020-11-29T19:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-11-29T19:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/11/thanksgiving-abroad</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/11/thanksgiving-abroad.html">&lt;p&gt;This week we celebrated Thanksgiving at our house. I feel confident in saying that we were the only participants in Thanksgiving festivities in our neighborhood, since I am the only American. We’ve done this for a couple of years, and were lucky enough to share Thanksgiving with another American family two years ago. The nature of life abroad is that holidays happen differently. And while for many aspects of living abroad, there are tricks we can use or different ways of seeing things, when it comes to holidays I find that there is no secret way to make an American holiday feel like it would back home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in America, on Thanksgiving Day I would be with my immediate family, eating a ridiculously large meal. Afterwards we would hobble to the couch and watch some Thanksgiving Day football. Probably wearing sweatpants to accept my new rotund shape after Thanksgiving dinner, I would be enjoying a day or two in the holiday routine before heading back to work or school. It’s a privilege to have a place to go for Thanksgiving, and though at the time it can feel like a bit of a hassle to travel at the busiest time of the year, it definitely feels good to be back home for the holidays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, our home is in France now, and it’s not very convenient to fly back to the United States for a few days. So we do a little Thanksgiving meal at our house. This year, my wife cooked a big chicken quite well, substituting lime for lemon in a recipe that I have come to really enjoy. I must have eaten it four or five times this year, and it has always been great. This time was no exception, and it was enjoyable to have something special for the occasion. I also put on Charlie Brown for the children, as I think it’s fun to have a little tradition for the children, and I like Charlie Brown too. But other than those things, we didn’t have much of a Thanksgiving. I went to work, Miriam went to school, and life went on as it would on any other weekday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily I’m pretty much okay with that, but it definitely is one of the downsides of living abroad. You simply can’t have a full American Thanksgiving experience abroad. If we want to celebrate our own holidays, we have to make our own atmosphere. It’s something that we are working on, as we want our children to experience these things, and to have good memories of holidays like Thanksgiving. We want our children to know the meaning of the holidays that we grew up celebrating, as well as those new ones we celebrate alongside the French.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while having American holidays abroad is different, there is also a difference in the way that we experience French holidays. We didn’t grow up in France, so we don’t have childhood memories of celebrating important French holidays in a uniquely French way. When I’m off of work for a French holiday, often it’s just a simple day off of work for me. If the holiday is for a war memorial, then I might try and watch something related to the subject to think about the sacrifice or suffering related to the holdiay, but for many other holidays, I can’t have the same connection as someone who grew up here. In my defense, I’m not sure that all French people are fervently celebrating the Catholic holidays, such as Ascension or Assomption, so there may not be much for us to do for some of these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living in France has been a wonderful experience for us, as we get to present others with something they don’t usually see, and learn from them at the same time. Unfortunately we can’t simply take all of the good and none of the bad. We don’t get to spend every holidays with our families. My longsuffering wife is especially aware of this, as recent events have made travel back to China difficult for us, and even in the best of times Chinese New Year does not align perfectly with the French school calendar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We simply do the best we can, and are grateful for those times that we are back in the USA or China with our families, just like days of our childhoods. In the meantime, we try to get into the local French holidays and try new things. We may not have a lot of experience with Bastille Day, but we can celebrate anyway. We can also try some new things at Christmas, mixing what we already love with something new. In the process, perhaps we can share a little Thanksgiving in France.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">This week we celebrated Thanksgiving at our house. I feel confident in saying that we were the only participants in Thanksgiving festivities in our neighborhood, since I am the only American. We’ve done this for a couple of years, and were lucky enough to share Thanksgiving with another American family two years ago. The nature of life abroad is that holidays happen differently. And while for many aspects of living abroad, there are tricks we can use or different ways of seeing things, when it comes to holidays I find that there is no secret way to make an American holiday feel like it would back home.</summary></entry></feed>