<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-05-23T18:53:12+02:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Sterling Coleman</title><subtitle>A space for my personal projects and thoughts</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Return of the Fête du Muguet</title><link href="/blog/2023/05/fete-muguet.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Return of the Fête du Muguet" /><published>2023-05-21T12:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-05-21T12:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2023/05/fete-muguet</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2023/05/fete-muguet.html">&lt;p&gt;Last weekend the Fête du Muguet returned to Rambouillet, as it does every year. We know in advance when it will be there, as we receive a notice in the mail that the roads will be closed the weekend of the Fête du Muguet. That doesn’t typically affect us, though the bus won’be running during those times either. The carnival is a nice time to walk around the town and look at the attractions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, with children those attractions become very tempting and are constantly the subject of much begging and demanding. We set a budget this year of 20 euros to spend at the carnival, but that isn’t much to spend on two children, with many things costing more than 5 euros a person. The attractions consist of pellet shooting games to win prizes, some being easier and for smaller reward, others being impossible with the hope of winning a PlayStation 5 or some other very expensive prize. There are bumper cars, rides that spin, rides that flip, and rides that go around in endless circles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our children, the attraction that is still the winner is the multi-story labyrinth. It’s perfect for us as parents as well, as we can send the kids in, and they can spend as much time as they want playing inside. When they come out, they can’t go back in, so we tell them not to come out until we call them. This year, the kids spent a full hour playing inside, and were still sad when we called them out. That was money well spent (6 euros a person).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there, we went to the part of the carnival with the bigger, more sickening rides. Swinging ships, scrambled eggs, and the sort of thing that I would really prefer not to ride at a temporary carnival. This year, however, my wife offered me 20 euros to ride a horrible looking thing which requires a serious locking shoulder harness for riders in order to then spin them while doing the classic Swinging Ship action. We paid the 8 euros for my ticket, and our friend Léo got a ticket as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Together, we strapped in and were raised up above the town, with 10 other people. I then almost got sick as we spent several minutes spinning upside down. At the points when we went completely upside-down, we stayed like that for several seconds, and the only thing keeping us from falling fifty meters to our deaths was the shoulder harness. I was legitimately scared and started to get a little sick. I held onto a pair of metal handles on the seats for dear life in case the shoulder harness failed, though I’m not sure I would have been able to keep myself from falling if that had happened. I was happy to be off the ride after a few more minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that done, we had to endure a lot of crying and whining about all the things we didn’t do. To be honest, I kind of hate doing these carnivals with our kids for just that reason. Everything is expensive, there is no bracelet to buy to be able to do everything as much as we want, and small children can’t ever be happy with what they have done if they see something else they want. We walked home and I lay down to recover from another Fête du Muguet.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Last weekend the Fête du Muguet returned to Rambouillet, as it does every year. We know in advance when it will be there, as we receive a notice in the mail that the roads will be closed the weekend of the Fête du Muguet. That doesn’t typically affect us, though the bus won’be running during those times either. The carnival is a nice time to walk around the town and look at the attractions.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Flea Market Season</title><link href="/blog/2023/05/flea-market-season.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Flea Market Season" /><published>2023-05-08T12:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-05-08T12:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2023/05/flea-market-season</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2023/05/flea-market-season.html">&lt;p&gt;With the very beginning of Spring a month or two ago, I have once again been frequenting the local &lt;em&gt;vide-greniers&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;brocantes&lt;/em&gt;. These are the French terms for the flea markets which pop up all over the place starting in the Spring. In the past, we would go to more of these when our children were very small, as they are perfect for finding secondhand baby clothes, and babies change sizes very quickly. Before this year, I had not been to a flea market since before the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, I have been consciously going to a lot of these. It takes a little discipline to set reminders and to get up early on Sunday mornings to be out at the event by eight in the morning, But it is necessary if we want to get the things we are looking for, as the best stuff goes quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each village tends to have a flea market once a year, and larger towns have several. Most districts in Paris have a flea market every weekend, it seems. I’ve found that it is best to visit the small villages, where people have saved up things all year and are willing to sell for low prices to get rid of their stuff. So far, I’ve been out to Le Perray and Cernay, and today I went to Vielle Église.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was most surprised today, as I expected the flea market at Vielle-Église-des-Yvelines to be small, as the village itself is home to about 600 people. I think the close proximity to Rambouillet changed a lot of things, as when I arrived I had a little difficulty maneuvering my bicycle through the swarm of cars to park it close to the entrance to the flea market. The market itself was the main street of the village, closed off to cars and lined with tables of goods for several hundred meters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These flea markets are still great opportunities to find cheap clothing for our kids. Some tables have their clothing well organized in labeled bins so that it is easy to walk up and find the exact size you are looking for. Today I got at least 10 pieces of clothing for each of our children, plus two pairs of shoes for Miriam and one pair for Daniel. I spent about 30 euros for all of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have found that the key is to be quick and find the tables which have a lot of children’s clothing, especially if it is labeled with the age range you are looking for. Obviously I buy a size or two bigger than what our children are wearing right now. Then I ask what the price generally is, and usually the answer is about one euro per item. Occasionally I will buy some things at two euros a piece. The best thing to find is shoes. Good shoes for kids are a real steal, and today I really lucked out as I bought a pair of tennis shoes in good condition and a pair of Velcro strap sandals for one euro each. For another pair of shoes I paid three euros, which is still a good deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m planning on continuing to frequent these flea markets as much as I can this year. Even if not every item is a big hit with our kids, I’ve found that few of the things I buy turn out to be duds. It’s fun to feel like you’re getting a good deal, and for kids’ clothing, it’s a really good way to save money. The added bonus for me is that I get to visit a lot of cool little villages and see them bustling on an early Saturday or Sunday morning.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">With the very beginning of Spring a month or two ago, I have once again been frequenting the local vide-greniers, or brocantes. These are the French terms for the flea markets which pop up all over the place starting in the Spring. In the past, we would go to more of these when our children were very small, as they are perfect for finding secondhand baby clothes, and babies change sizes very quickly. Before this year, I had not been to a flea market since before the pandemic.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Versailles in the Championnat National</title><link href="/blog/2023/01/versailles-championnat-national.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Versailles in the Championnat National" /><published>2023-01-15T09:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-01-15T09:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2023/01/versailles-championnat-national</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2023/01/versailles-championnat-national.html">&lt;p&gt;Of all the soccer teams which I support, the club team which I have enjoyed supporting the most in these past few years is FC Versailles. When I first got interested in the French football pyramid and the lower leagues, I looked up which team at a decent level was closest to Rambouillet. It took some searching, but I found FC Versailles playing in the National 3, the fifth division of French football, which consists of ten groups of fourteen teams, with only the top team in each group being promoted to the next level up. Versailles were playing very well at that level, and were in first place, though US Ivry was hot on their heels. That season was cut short by COVID, and the French Football Federation made the decision to allow promotion and relegation to continue, despite only about two thirds of the season having been played.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that bit of luck, Versailles moved up from the National 3 to the National 2, which consists of four groups of sixteen team, again with only one team from each group being promoted. The following season did not start exceptionally well for Versailles, who found themselves just above the relegation zone of the bottom three teams after a third of the season had been played. Enter COVID to once again shine on Versailles and end the season very prematurely, this time with no promotion or relegation taking place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following season, the season of 2021-2022, was the stuff of fairy tales for Versailles. The team started off with many draws, and I was nervous, wondering if this season might be a reproduction of the previous season. Despite the team only being in the middle of the table, I noted after about a quarter of the season had transpired, that Versailles had already played all of the teams above them in the table without losing a match, and that they would have a series of games against the bottom half of the table. The team took advantage of this run to go on a bit of a winning streak. At the same time that this was happening, the team as competing well in the Coupe de France, getting favorable picks for their opponents, and winning their games, though often by close margins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in the league, Versailles pushed to the top of the table and took advantage of lapses by other teams to never give up that place. They finished the league in first place by a comfortable margin, earning back-to-back promotions in seasons that were eligible for promotion. The Coupe de France was the real publicity stunt, as Versailles beat Toulouse, a team from Ligue 2, two divisions above them, in a run up to the semi-final, where they finally lost to Nice, from Ligue 1, after not giving up a goal the entire first half against the team three divisions above their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, Versailles is playing in the Championnat National, having moved up from the National 3 and National 2. For the next two years, in order to reduce the number of teams playing in both Ligue 1 and Ligue 2 from twenty each to eighteen each, four teams will be relegated from both. The Championnat National is relegating six of its eighteen teams in order to keep up. I have watched anxiously, hoping not to see Versailles be relegated after their incredible story up until this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, half of the season is complete, and Versailles is in first place in the league, pending a game to be played by Concarneau, one of its primary competitors. Versailles has found the league more difficult than its previous seasons, having lost a few games. And yet, the team has won six of its nine games at home. I was there for the first game of the season when Mondy Prunier scored a goal at the last second of the game against Martigues, a goal that may prove crucial as Martigues sit second in the table right now, only behind Versailles because of that goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This season has been a lot of fun, and it will be interesting to see if Versailles can indeed be promoted for a third consecutive time. Even if that doesn’t happen, it will be a success to have avoided relegation and to be playing in the Championnat National, a world away from where the team was just three years ago.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Of all the soccer teams which I support, the club team which I have enjoyed supporting the most in these past few years is FC Versailles. When I first got interested in the French football pyramid and the lower leagues, I looked up which team at a decent level was closest to Rambouillet. It took some searching, but I found FC Versailles playing in the National 3, the fifth division of French football, which consists of ten groups of fourteen teams, with only the top team in each group being promoted to the next level up. Versailles were playing very well at that level, and were in first place, though US Ivry was hot on their heels. That season was cut short by COVID, and the French Football Federation made the decision to allow promotion and relegation to continue, despite only about two thirds of the season having been played.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">France at the World Cup</title><link href="/blog/2022/12/france-world-cup.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="France at the World Cup" /><published>2022-12-18T09:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-12-18T09:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2022/12/france-world-cup</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2022/12/france-world-cup.html">&lt;p&gt;One of the many perks of living abroad is that I can support multiple countries, such as both the USA and France. Back in 2018, when the USA disapointingly failed to qualify for the World Cup, I could still watch France play. That turned out to be a great tournament to watch from France, as France went on to win the whole World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember when France won, and we went out into the center of our town and celebrated with many other people. There were cars honking everywhere, people cheering with French flags, and even some trucks with a crowd of people loaded into the back, all cheering. It was a little makeshift parade. The games that France played at the 2018 World Cup were tough matchups. They included games against Uruguay, Belgiam, Croatia, and a famous 4-3 win over Argentina to start the knockout rounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time around, France has been playing well again at the World Cup, and will face Argentina once again, this time in the World Cup Final. Both teams have had relatively easy runs up to the Final, in comparison to the teams that one would typically have to face to get that far. This is in large part because of the number of important upsets we have seen in this World Cup. Morocco notably beat both Spain and Portugal to make it to the Semi Final, and Croatia knocked off Brazil to make it to the Semi Final.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;France’s opponents in the group stage were Australia, Denmark, and Tunisia. Denmark was the team that everyone was concerned could threaten to beat France and make a run deep into the knockout rounds. And while it did take a late goal from Kylian Mbappé to beat Denmark, the Danes turned in a very poor World Cup performance overall, finishing last in the Group. In fact, France was already the leader of the group after just two games, with little chance to be overtaken. It was in this way that the French team rested many of their best players in the final game against Tunisia, and ended up losing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, France picked up their form in the knockout rounds with the return of Kylian Mbappé and other notable players, easily beating Poland. The next matchup was the hardest that France would face in the knockout rounds, England. The English were a team that were hoping to make it to the Final and possibly win the Cup, just like France. It was a relatively even match, and France barely won, giving up an unnecessary second penalty to the English. It was only a surprising miss on that penalty that allowed France to advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;France took down Morocco next, and is now up against Lionel Messi and Argentina. This will be another tough match for France, as Messi has established himself well in this tournament. This is probably his last chance to win a World Cup with Argentina and thus establish himself as the greatest Argentinian player, and possibly greatest player period, of all time. Despite that, France has a very good team as well, and I am expecting an even match. Whatever happens, we are proud of the French team for making it to two consecutive World Cup Finals. We will be watching this afternoon, in the hopes of celebrating a second consecutive World Cup win.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">One of the many perks of living abroad is that I can support multiple countries, such as both the USA and France. Back in 2018, when the USA disapointingly failed to qualify for the World Cup, I could still watch France play. That turned out to be a great tournament to watch from France, as France went on to win the whole World Cup.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">USA at the World Cup</title><link href="/blog/2022/12/usa-world-cup.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="USA at the World Cup" /><published>2022-12-10T09:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-12-10T09:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2022/12/usa-world-cup</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2022/12/usa-world-cup.html">&lt;p&gt;For a long time, I, along with many other American soccer fans, have been watching anxiously as the USA has gone through the qualification phase for the 2022 FIFA World Cup. Every American fan has been looking forward to putting the failure of the 2018 qualification campaign behind them, and to start anew with a young team looking to qualify for the world’s most important soccer tournament.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I actually think that in some ways the qualification process is just as, if not more, fun than the actual World Cup. This is mostly because there are more teams competing, and the qualification phase lasts longer. This makes for pretty interesting discussion. Therefore it was a lot of fun to see Canada master their qualification campaign, never losing a match. The USA also played well, beating out rivals Mexico at home, and playing well at Azteca Stadium in a scoreless draw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The USA qualified on the final day, though not without losing their final match to Costa Rica, and finishing in third place, behind both Canada and Mexico. From there, the American team played in the CONCACAF Nations League in June, beating Grenada, and scoring late in El Salvador to earn a draw. Though these matches were not against teams that would be playing in the World Cup, the USA got an opportunity to play teams at that level in September, facing off against Japan and Saudi Arabia in a pair of friendly matches. Unfortunately, neither game was a success, with a loss to Japan and a draw against the Saudis being the final matches the team would play before playing in the World Cup. The hopes of American fans were slightly diminished heading into the all-important first match against Wales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that match, I rejoiced as I watched Christian Pulisic play a great ball in on goal for Timo Weah, who finished his chance and put us up 1-0 over the Welsh. I later despaired as I watched Gareth Bale convert a penalty kick to even the game up. We failed to close the door on the Welsh, and we left ourselves a lot of work to do to get out of the group phase, which was our goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our second match, we faced a strong opponent in England. Oddly enough, because of the way the math worked out, it would not have been a big deal if we lost the match. Therefore I was surprised to see us put out our best players to start the match, and even more surprised to watch us play just as well as the English, if not better. It was a good feeling to avoid losing to England, keeping alive our streak of never losing to England in a FIFA World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our final group match was Iran. It was win, or go home. Iran had beaten Wales in the final minutes of the match, and only needed a draw to advance. We would have to score a goal on a team that could afford to play as defensively as possible if they liked. It was a great game, with lots of energy and emotion. Christian Pulisic showed his quality and leadership, sacrificing his body to get the ball across the goal line and put us up 1-0 near the end of the first half. We were able to hold on, and beat Iran, advancing out of the group and on to the Round of 16.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next match didn’t go so well. We were up against the Netherlands, a team that many saw as a weaker team than the likes of some of the best teams in the tournament. They were a pretty good side nonetheless. In the game against the Dutch, we seemed worn out after having fought hard for our advancement out of the group stage. We had our chances, but weren’t able to capitalize. The Netherlands punished us for defensive mistakes, and beat us 3-1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see a lot of Americans happy with our performance in the tournament, but talking about how we’re gunning for a semifinal finish or better in the 2026 World Cup, which we are co-hosting with Mexico and Canada. Personally, I’m not ready to talk about 2026 yet, and I think that we have a lot to be proud of in advancing out of our group, which is something plenty of teams failed to do, including every other team from North America, as well as some of the best teams in the tournament, such as Belgium, Germany, and Denmark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This World Cup was a reassuring moment for the USA. We showed that we belong at the World Cup, and that we belong in the list of the best 16 teams in this tournament. Obviously, getting to the quarterfinals would have been amazing, but it is still gratifying to see us consistently getting to the Round of 16 (excluding 2018, when we didn’t qualify). There are a lot of reasons to look forward to the future of this team and of this sport in USA.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">For a long time, I, along with many other American soccer fans, have been watching anxiously as the USA has gone through the qualification phase for the 2022 FIFA World Cup. Every American fan has been looking forward to putting the failure of the 2018 qualification campaign behind them, and to start anew with a young team looking to qualify for the world’s most important soccer tournament.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">La Fête du Muguet</title><link href="/blog/2022/05/la-fete-muguet.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="La Fête du Muguet" /><published>2022-05-15T10:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-05-15T10:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2022/05/la-fete-muguet</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2022/05/la-fete-muguet.html">&lt;p&gt;This weekend has been insanely busy, and it’s not over yet. Over the past week, the large parking lot near the local high school has been filling up with recreational vehicles of all types as well as some big trucks, as the group which is putting on the Fête du Muguet came into town to start setting up for the festival.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Muguet is a lily, and the Muguet Festival is the springtime festival, probably the biggest festival of the year in Rambouillet. There are more events going on than I could even mention, but the main ones which I know of are the parade, topped by the Queen, a local girl chosen every year, I believe by a vote. And of course, there is the carnival.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The carnival takes up the streats all around the central portion of the large park at the Château de Ramobouillet. There are many stands to buy crêpes, coffee, cotton candy, slushies, and other snacks. There are numerous stands to try your luck at winning a PlayStation 5 by performing some sort of impossible challenge, as well as other, easier challenges with smaller prizes. There are bumper cars and many rides which whirl the riders around in various dizzying patterns, all with similar results. Near the town hall there is a swinging ship ride as well as a ridiculously tall version of the pendulum ride wtih just a few people screaming their heads off as they twist and turn in their seats, as their seats reach a hundred meters up in the air before swinging back down to ground level and up again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For us, we are thankfully in the small child phase for another year or two. We send our children to the gentle rides. We haven´t had this festival for the past couple of years due to the COVID pandemic, but same as a few years ago, the favorite is still the multi-level jungle gym. The best one was a jungle-themed tower, three stories high, with a big spiral slide. It’s a perfect ride for us, as we can send our childen inside, and tell them not to come out until they are ready to be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a good thing that our children spent almost an hour in the jungle gym over the couse of the weekend, as each entry is six euros. I realize that the people running the carnival need to turn a profit, but every time we go to this event, I can’t help wondering how much money we will have to spend before we can leave. Ten euros lasts about five minutes if two people go on one of the bigger rides. Of course, it was worth it to watch my wife screaming as she whizzed around in an oval for awhile, but still.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And lastly, the disappointing thing is that as a parent of small children, we will always be subjected to a tantrum when it is time to leave, no matter how much fun has been had. As we walk around the rides, the overwhelming number of teenagers reminds us that someday we can just send our children to the carnival without us, and they can enjoy what appears to be the big social outing of the year to put their arm around someone and buy win an oversized teddy bear. For the moment, we’re still budgeting time in the jungle gym.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">This weekend has been insanely busy, and it’s not over yet. Over the past week, the large parking lot near the local high school has been filling up with recreational vehicles of all types as well as some big trucks, as the group which is putting on the Fête du Muguet came into town to start setting up for the festival.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What I’m Watching: Justin Outdoors</title><link href="/blog/2022/02/watching-justin-outdoors.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What I’m Watching: Justin Outdoors" /><published>2022-02-05T09:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-02-05T09:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2022/02/watching-justin-outdoors</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2022/02/watching-justin-outdoors.html">&lt;p&gt;Considering the amount of time I’ve spent watching video logs of hiking trips online, I was a bit surprised to recently come across a series that I hadn’t seen before: a Great Divide Trail thru-hike, from the American-Canadian border all the way to Kakwa Lake, the Northernmost terminus. I search often for videos on the Great Divide Trail, because of the route it takes through wilderness areas that are rarely traversed, and of course for its natural beauty. The trail is a relatively new trail that traverses the Southern portion of the Canadian Rockies. (See my proposed &lt;a href=&quot;/exploration/northern-divide-trail/&quot;&gt;Northern Divide Trail&lt;/a&gt; that would cover the rest of the Rocky Mountains up to the Liard River).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, given that I’ve already seen many videos on the trail, I was surprised to come across a completely new series by a channel called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/JustinOutdoors&quot;&gt;Justin Outdoors&lt;/a&gt;. And it is a well-done log of the entire trip. Justin put out one video per day, every day, from the beginning to the end of the trip, which lasted over a month. Not only that, but each video is not just a short summary, but rather updates throughout the day, from morning until night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that Justin does differently than most other adventure channels that I’ve followed is that he is quite open and honest about the mental challenges that he faces when completing his quest. He doesn’t simply mention a day later that the previous day was a difficult one. He actually makes the effort to get the camera out and talk about how he’s feeling, while he’s feeling it. I can appreciate the effort that it takes, not just to expose that side of the adventure, but also to overcome the hurdle of filming at the time when you most feel like putting the camera away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, just as a hiker who has been following other hikers on the Great Divide Trail for some time, I appreciate the tenacity of hiking all the way to Kakwa Lake. I must admit that I have been dissapointed in the past to find someone who has made a summary video of their GDT hike, and seeing that the video is of considerable length, hope to see the entire trail, only to find tat the hike ended at Jasper, which leaves a considerable portion of the trail untouched. I understand that hiking out of Kakwa Lake is not easy, which leads me to appreciate all the more a hike such as Justin’s, which accomplished that feat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, I was impressed to see Justin taking on many of the more difficult alternate routes. Many choose to take the official route, which in some sections follows a dirt road through a valley. Justin met the extra challenge of climbing to altitude and tackling the even lesser-traveled alternate routes, despite the added dangers of cliffs and exposed ridge lines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope to see Justin put out more thru-hiking content on his trail. Certainly most trails take longer to complete than the Great Divide Trail, which is an obstacle, but I would be interested to see how he compares the GDT to other trails, especially the Continental Divide. In any case, I can only recommend checking out the GDT thru-hike for a comprehensive take on not only the trail itself, but the mind of a thru-hiker each and every day of a thru-hike.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Considering the amount of time I’ve spent watching video logs of hiking trips online, I was a bit surprised to recently come across a series that I hadn’t seen before: a Great Divide Trail thru-hike, from the American-Canadian border all the way to Kakwa Lake, the Northernmost terminus. I search often for videos on the Great Divide Trail, because of the route it takes through wilderness areas that are rarely traversed, and of course for its natural beauty. The trail is a relatively new trail that traverses the Southern portion of the Canadian Rockies. (See my proposed Northern Divide Trail that would cover the rest of the Rocky Mountains up to the Liard River).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Year of the Tiger</title><link href="/blog/2022/01/year-of-the-tiger.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Year of the Tiger" /><published>2022-01-30T22:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-01-30T22:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2022/01/year-of-the-tiger</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2022/01/year-of-the-tiger.html">&lt;p&gt;We’ve just had one of two of our big meals to celebrate the Chinese New Year. The upcoming year is the year of the Tiger, which must be one of the better-sounding animals. Better than the rat or the snake, at least. The Chinese New Year, like many holidays, is principally a time for families to get together, eat big meals, and spend time together. Being away from family this year, we invited friends over to our house to celebrate with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Celebrating Chinese New Year is a lot of work for my wife. Mostly, she plans many dishes and cooks them all on the day of the big meal. I don’t mean three or four different plates. I think there were almost ten different things on the table at tonight’s dinner. That’s more than just cooking for an hour or two. She spends all day cooking the dinner that we all enjoy. Before the day even arrives, she gathers some of the special ingredients that she is looking for, scouting out various stores. She plans certain dishes to be more spicy for those of us that can handle them, and most to be less spicy. She comes up with some vegetable dishes to balance out the meal, which inevitably has plenty of meat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the main reasons that my wife does all this work is that we both want our children to experience Chinese holidays, the New Year being the most important of them all. This year, my wife took our daughter into Paris to visit the Chinese neighborhood, where decorations had been placed up, and she could get a little taste of the festivities. This is a very important part of the holidays for us, especially Chinese holidays. We haven’t found any opportunities to visit China in recent years, which means we have to work harder to maintain our cultural ties, and ensure that our children grow up with those traditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, my wife is up to the task. Despite not having her parents and other family available to be here with us physically, she maintains the holidays atmosphere well all by herself, most importantly with the big festive meal, but also in the little things, like a little Chinese New Year piggy bank that she gave the children for saving up New Year’s gifts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do hope that in the future we will be able to see another New Year in China, but I have my doubts about the feasability of that. Without being too pessimistic, I think it’s safe to say that the decision to take our children there would be questionable, given that we could be forced to stay for an unknown period of time. Thankfully, Chinese culture can take place elsewhere, and we can still be a multicultural family. I know that I have enjoyed the New Year already, and it’s not even over yet. It’s an event that lasts a couple of weeks, and so we’ll be having another meal to celebrate more in a week. I can’t wait.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">We’ve just had one of two of our big meals to celebrate the Chinese New Year. The upcoming year is the year of the Tiger, which must be one of the better-sounding animals. Better than the rat or the snake, at least. The Chinese New Year, like many holidays, is principally a time for families to get together, eat big meals, and spend time together. Being away from family this year, we invited friends over to our house to celebrate with us.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Versailles in the Coupe de France</title><link href="/blog/2022/01/versailles-coupe-de-france.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Versailles in the Coupe de France" /><published>2022-01-08T09:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-01-08T09:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2022/01/versailles-coupe-de-france</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2022/01/versailles-coupe-de-france.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been following FC Versailles 78 for awhile now. It’s fun to follow a team in the lower leagues, where the results are much less certain, and teams can’t simply throw money at their problems and win games based on a large disparity in talent. Versailles plays in the National 2, the fourth level of the French football leagues, but recently I attended a couple of their Coupe de France matches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Coupe de France is a tournament for teams of all levels in the French football pyramid, similar to the Lamar Hunt US Open Cup in the United States, or the FA Cup in England. Teams from the very lowest levels of the pyramid start play in August, before their league seasons have even begun, in order to start the process of elimination early. In each match, the loser is eliminated from the tournament. The cup games are on certain weekends which are set aside during the season, meaning no league games. This means that teams which are eliminated have extra time to rest compared to those teams who are still playing in the cup in addition to their respective leagues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Versailles is in the National 2, they didn’t have to start playing in the tournament until the fourth round, which started in early October. Their 3-0 win against CS Brétigny, a National 3 team (one level below the National 2 in the pyramid), started them on their current seven-game win streak in the tournament, where they currently sit in the final 16 teams yet to be beaten. That’s right, of 8,506 teams which have participated in this year’s edition of the cup, only Versailles and 15 other teams remain. Of course, Versailles didn’t have to beat all those teams to advance. On the contrary, Versailles had a relatively easy path, only being asked to match up against a team of their own level one time (AS Poissy), and never having to play against a team of a higher level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Versailles’ streak in the cup is composed of the following opponents and scorelines:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CS Brétigny (National 3, 5th level) : 3-0&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CO Cachan (Departmental 1, 9th level): 4-0&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Neuilly-sur-Marne (Regional 2, 7th level): 1-0&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Olympique Lumbrois (Regional 1, 6th level): 3-2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;AS Poissy (National 2, 4th level): 1-0&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;US Sarre-Union (National 3, 5th level): 1-0&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;La Roche VF (National 3, 5th level): 4-0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the games were well won, without too many scares. The exceptions were the game away at Lumbrois, which was equalized and then won near the end of the game. Versailles also gave up a penalty kick at the end of the game against Sarre-Union, which was missed. The streak was also kept alive in part because of a relateively favorable draw, in which teams from the Championnat National, the third division, as well as Ligue 2, the second division, and Versailles never had to play any of them. Of the remaining teams, ten teams are from Ligue 1, four are from Ligue 2, and the remaining two teams, including Versailles, are from the fourth level, the National 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On January 29, Versailles’ path crosses a significantly better team in that of Toulouse FC, a Ligue 2 team who is aspiring to make a return to Ligue 1. Though the match was originally scheduled to be played in Versailles (the smaller team traditionally has the right to host, which is one of the best parts of the cup), the unlighted stadium which FC Versailles calls home was judged to not respond to the necessary criteria, and thus the fixture will be played in Toulouse. The match was always going to be a tough one, but this misfortune makes the matchup that much more difficult. I was able to attend the matches against Poissy and La Roche, both of which were highly entertaining. It’s a shame that I won’t be able to see Versailles play in this new matchup in-person, but whatever happens, it will still have been a great run in the Coupe de France.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">I’ve been following FC Versailles 78 for awhile now. It’s fun to follow a team in the lower leagues, where the results are much less certain, and teams can’t simply throw money at their problems and win games based on a large disparity in talent. Versailles plays in the National 2, the fourth level of the French football leagues, but recently I attended a couple of their Coupe de France matches.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Looking back on 2021</title><link href="/blog/2022/01/looking-back-2021.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Looking back on 2021" /><published>2022-01-01T13:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-01-01T13:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2022/01/looking-back-2021</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2022/01/looking-back-2021.html">&lt;p&gt;We enjoyed a great New Year’s Eve with friends last night, and though we may be a bit sluggish today, it was a symbolic finish to an eventful year for our family. Of course, in some ways similar to our goings-on this year, Daniel whined and whined until he fell asleep in his mother’s arms well before midnight. Certainly this was a fitting end to a year that held plenty of good news for us, as well as some challenges to overcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wouldn’t be a real recap if I skipped over all the difficulties of the year. First and foremost in my mind, I made the decision this year to look for a change in my work environment, which I found near the end of the year. The process of looking for a new job can often be grueling, and the end of the process is not in sight until all of a sudden we receive some good news. Recently, the demand for developers has increased enough that I have had recruiters from many different companies contacting me multiple times per week. Though it is certainly nice to feel that interest from the market, it can also be tiring to be constantly communicating the same sorts of messages over and over again. Thankfully, I’m done with that now, and I’ll be moving on to a new post in February.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daniel clearly deserves his own paragraph. He’s a cute kid, but at the age of 2 or 3, every child can be a pain at times. To be fair, he’s going through quite a lot of changes, and in September he started going to school. Obviously, he was very excited beforehand, but not so after the first day. But I was very proud of him for accepting that he will be going to school, and not crying. Many of the other children in his class were crying for weeks after he stopped, some still continue to resist school. That being said, we are still dealing with the sorts of tantrums that most parents have to deal with when their children are this age. We’re hoping that 2022 brings a definitive end to that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Miriam has also made some big strides in the past year. Her reading and writing has been advancing in leaps and bounds. And I don’t just mean in English. She can read and write at some level in English, French, and Chinese. That’s pretty impressive for a 6 year-old. She also started doing her first extracurricular activity this year: gymnastics. She loves it, and I’m happy to see her training her body as well as her mind. She still has plenty to learn, of course. We’re still working on the idea of trying new things, notably food, and being more social.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After years of hard work raising our children, my wife Alex is finally getting a little rest (but not that much). With both of the children finally in school four days a week, she has some time to work on her own projects, uninterrupted. The biggest change that we can all see in her is her desire to be more active in our church. She has been attending several meetings each week, doing some reading, and thinking a lot about what is most important to her. I’m proud that she is prioritizing this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I would be remiss to not also mention the big news in our extended family: notably that my brother Kevin bravely took on Mont Blanc with me, and also got married! It’s been a year full of mostly good news for us, and I’m hoping that 2022 brings more of the same. Clearly the good doesn’t come without challenges attached, but so far we’ve been up for that. Here’s hoping that 2022 goes just as well.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">We enjoyed a great New Year’s Eve with friends last night, and though we may be a bit sluggish today, it was a symbolic finish to an eventful year for our family. Of course, in some ways similar to our goings-on this year, Daniel whined and whined until he fell asleep in his mother’s arms well before midnight. Certainly this was a fitting end to a year that held plenty of good news for us, as well as some challenges to overcome.</summary></entry></feed>