<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-01-15T09:22:32+01:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Sterling Coleman</title><subtitle>A space for my personal projects and thoughts</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Looking back on 2021</title><link href="/blog/2022/01/looking-back-2021.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Looking back on 2021" /><published>2022-01-01T13:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-01-01T13:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2022/01/looking-back-2021</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2022/01/looking-back-2021.html">&lt;p&gt;We enjoyed a great New Year’s Eve with friends last night, and though we may be a bit sluggish today, it was a symbolic finish to an eventful year for our family. Of course, in some ways similar to our goings-on this year, Daniel whined and whined until he fell asleep in his mother’s arms well before midnight. Certainly this was a fitting end to a year that held plenty of good news for us, as well as some challenges to overcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wouldn’t be a real recap if I skipped over all the difficulties of the year. First and foremost in my mind, I made the decision this year to look for a change in my work environment, which I found near the end of the year. The process of looking for a new job can often be grueling, and the end of the process is not in sight until all of a sudden we receive some good news. Recently, the demand for developers has increased enough that I have had recruiters from many different companies contacting me multiple times per week. Though it is certainly nice to feel that interest from the market, it can also be tiring to be constantly communicating the same sorts of messages over and over again. Thankfully, I’m done with that now, and I’ll be moving on to a new post in February.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daniel clearly deserves his own paragraph. He’s a cute kid, but at the age of 2 or 3, every child can be a pain at times. To be fair, he’s going through quite a lot of changes, and in September he started going to school. Obviously, he was very excited beforehand, but not so after the first day. But I was very proud of him for accepting that he will be going to school, and not crying. Many of the other children in his class were crying for weeks after he stopped, some still continue to resist school. That being said, we are still dealing with the sorts of tantrums that most parents have to deal with when their children are this age. We’re hoping that 2022 brings a definitive end to that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Miriam has also made some big strides in the past year. Her reading and writing has been advancing in leaps and bounds. And I don’t just mean in English. She can read and write at some level in English, French, and Chinese. That’s pretty impressive for a 6 year-old. She also started doing her first extracurricular activity this year: gymnastics. She loves it, and I’m happy to see her training her body as well as her mind. She still has plenty to learn, of course. We’re still working on the idea of trying new things, notably food, and being more social.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After years of hard work raising our children, my wife Alex is finally getting a little rest (but not that much). With both of the children finally in school four days a week, she has some time to work on her own projects, uninterrupted. The biggest change that we can all see in her is her desire to be more active in our church. She has been attending several meetings each week, doing some reading, and thinking a lot about what is most important to her. I’m proud that she is prioritizing this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I would be remiss to not also mention the big news in our extended family: notably that my brother Kevin bravely took on Mont Blanc with me, and also got married! It’s been a year full of mostly good news for us, and I’m hoping that 2022 brings more of the same. Clearly the good doesn’t come without challenges attached, but so far we’ve been up for that. Here’s hoping that 2022 goes just as well.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">We enjoyed a great New Year’s Eve with friends last night, and though we may be a bit sluggish today, it was a symbolic finish to an eventful year for our family. Of course, in some ways similar to our goings-on this year, Daniel whined and whined until he fell asleep in his mother’s arms well before midnight. Certainly this was a fitting end to a year that held plenty of good news for us, as well as some challenges to overcome.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Luxembourg Christmas</title><link href="/blog/2021/12/luxembourg-christmas.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Luxembourg Christmas" /><published>2021-12-26T12:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-12-26T12:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/12/luxembourg-christmas</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/12/luxembourg-christmas.html">&lt;p&gt;This year, we did something very different for Christmas. I found a cheap car rental, and a hotel in Luxembourg over Christmas Eve and Christmas Day. Though the distance limit on the car rental is exactly that of twice the distance to Luxembourg, I was confident that I could stick to the route and not go over the limit. Since public transportation is free in Luxembourg, we planned to take advantage of that, leaving the car at the hotel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The drive from our house to Luxembourg was long. I picked up the car, a brand new, never-before driven Renault Clio, as soon as the rental service opened, and we left the house as soon as we loaded some clothing, food, and our Christmas presents into the small trunk. As we headed East, attempting to circumvent Paris and any holiday traffic, we followed smaller roads. Soon on a national highway, we indeed ran into some traffic. It wasn’t as bad as it could have been, and we did eventually get going, albeit after having made an important mistake that ended up increasing the distance to Luxembourg. We passed through nice countryside, and some interesting villages in Northeastern France. I would describe them as a bit run-down, though still functional. The region seemed to have seen better days, likely when manufacturing or resource extraction used to take place in that area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we finally made it to the hotel, the car had 499 kilometers on the odometer, 1 short of the halfway point. We would have to do better on the way home. In the meantime, we relaxed after the long 6 or 7 hour drive. The next day, we got going and started the day off by walking around Grund, a historical neighborhood. It was beautiful. Big stoneworks everywhere, with even the townhouses on old stone foundations. The old-time feel had been well-preserved, much better than we see in Paris. Afterwards we visited the luxurious city center, which is actually quite small. From there, we made it in a very roundabout way out to the village of Mamer. Out there, we enjoyed free ice skating, though Daniel took a lot of convincing. There was also an artificial sledding hill. We stopped by the playground after a having a great time there. Back on the bus, Daniel of course fell asleep, but we made our way back to the hotel and crashed for the evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We let the children open one present each. The kids both got some great presents this year. Lots of good clothing, which is much-needed, as well as some fun toys for both. Daniel got a bunch of toy cars, and Miriam got Jenga, which she is quite good at. On Christmas Day, we opened more presents, then headed out for more fun in the city. Most things were closed, but the city has a fun little playground with a big wooden pirate ship, that was the main focus of the day. We also visited the Pfaffenthal elevator, which is quite scenic, if a bit of a trigger for my fear of falling from high up. We visited a playground or two, saw the inner city again, including the beautiful Cathedral Notre-Dame, then returned to the hotel room to rest for the rest of our Christmas evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our final day, we visited some rides at one of the Christmas markets. Daniel did the trampoline, and we all did the Ferris Wheel. Again, it was far too high up. Thankfully we survived that, and soon got back on the road home. We took a more direct route this time, though it was still quite a long drive as we took the backroads through villages and countryside. It was beautiful, but Miriam was sick, and had to make use of a bucket that we placed with her in the backseat. We did thankfully make it home by the evening, having thoroughly enjoyed our little Christmas vacation. It was fun to do something as a little family unit, and the short length of the vacation was perfect for Luxembourg, where we felt we had seen a lot of what we wanted to see, and were ready to be back home.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">This year, we did something very different for Christmas. I found a cheap car rental, and a hotel in Luxembourg over Christmas Eve and Christmas Day. Though the distance limit on the car rental is exactly that of twice the distance to Luxembourg, I was confident that I could stick to the route and not go over the limit. Since public transportation is free in Luxembourg, we planned to take advantage of that, leaving the car at the hotel.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Christmas Season in Rambouillet</title><link href="/blog/2021/12/christmas-season-rambouillet.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Christmas Season in Rambouillet" /><published>2021-12-18T12:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-12-18T12:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/12/christmas-season-rambouillet</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/12/christmas-season-rambouillet.html">&lt;p&gt;Today was the day that we really got our Christmas vacation going! With the kids out of school for two weeks starting this weekend, we have a few days in Rambouillet before we head to Luxembourg, and we want to really enjoy whatever we can here before we hit the road. For me, I had been thinking about the Rambolitrain museum that I walk past after I drop the kids off at school during the week. In addition to that, some friends of ours invited us to visit some of the events going on downtown this afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rambolitrain is a small museum that only costs a few euros to visit for an hour. Really, an hour is plenty, as there are only a few rooms. One floor has glass cases full of very old model train pieces of all kinds. The top floor has a big model train set with multiple tracks, and multiple trains running. I had never been before, but it turned out to be the perfect place to take my three-year-old son Daniel. He could see all of the trains, show me stuff that interested him, and spend lots of time watching the trains go back and forth, in and out of tunnels, and all around the room. Overall, it was a great experience for us, and one of the rare times that I have been able to go out and do something alone with Daniel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, Daniel and I met up with Alex and Miriam, as well as our friends, and their three children. We met at the gigantic Christmas tree (actually composed of many trees) at the center of Rambouillet. In previous years, a small ice skating area has been placed there, but because of the COVID pandemic, that hasn’t been set up this year. There was a group there singing carols. From there, we went to a small alley where the kids got their faces painted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main attraction that we found was a small band playing Christmas songs in that very alley. There were trumpets and clarinets, a young and charismatic conductor, and a group of girls singing. It made for a nice little show, and many people gathered around to listen. The last song that the group did was a Claude François song, “Alexandrie Alexandra”, which I had never heard before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, Daniel fell asleep in his mother’s arms, and we walked home together as soon as the mini-concert ended. Our outing on the town was short, but it was perfect for a family with young kids. And again, because of the pandemic, there aren’t quite as many things for kids programmed this year, so we are just happy to have done something in Rambouillet before we travel for Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Today was the day that we really got our Christmas vacation going! With the kids out of school for two weeks starting this weekend, we have a few days in Rambouillet before we head to Luxembourg, and we want to really enjoy whatever we can here before we hit the road. For me, I had been thinking about the Rambolitrain museum that I walk past after I drop the kids off at school during the week. In addition to that, some friends of ours invited us to visit some of the events going on downtown this afternoon.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Beginning to Look Like Christmas</title><link href="/blog/2021/12/beginning-to-look-like-christmas.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Beginning to Look Like Christmas" /><published>2021-12-11T12:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-12-11T12:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/12/beginning-to-look-like-christmas</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/12/beginning-to-look-like-christmas.html">&lt;p&gt;We’re well into December now, and the Christmas season is starting to really show itself. I’ve been busy with other projects, but now I’m starting to get excited for the Christmas festivities which are starting up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although we would love to be with extended family during the holidays, the way that schedules worked out this year had us traveling back to the States in the summer, so we decided to have our Christmas just together as our little family unit. For a long time, I figured that we would just have Christmas at our house, like we did last year. Then, at the last minute, I was able to schedule a short trip to Luxembourg for Christmas! We can’t wait to see another European country, even if it’s only for a few days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, with the Christmas season comes a lot of work. Getting gifts is fun when you know just what to get, but when you are searching and searching without finding something that makes sense as a good gift, it can be quite frustrating. Thankfully, many of the gifts that I found this year came rather naturally. It always feels good to come up with something that isn’t just a generic gift. Hopefully the things I’ve picked out will be well received.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the gift preparation, there is also just the general atmosphere, which is probably the best part of Christmas. This year, it’s all about Christmas music for us. My wife and daughter have both been enjoying playing the piano, so naturally come December, our house has been full of Christmas music, which is wonderful. Between that, and listening to some of the old-time classics that I used to hear around the house at Christmastime when I was younger, our Christmas Spirit is high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, we’re just happy to have another holiday to celebrate as a family. It’s always fun to do things with other family, but it is also important for us to create our own holiday environment, and build our own traditions. Since we find ourselves doing that this year, we’ve decided to enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">We’re well into December now, and the Christmas season is starting to really show itself. I’ve been busy with other projects, but now I’m starting to get excited for the Christmas festivities which are starting up.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Working with Wood</title><link href="/blog/2021/12/working-with-wood.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Working with Wood" /><published>2021-12-05T12:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-12-05T12:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/12/working-with-wood</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/12/working-with-wood.html">&lt;p&gt;Being a homeowner for the first time has been an opportunity to get involved with a lot of improvement projects around the house. One of my more recent projects has been the creation of a couple of drawers in a nook underneath a bedroom window. The space is perfect for a fixture, as it’s a small space between walls, spanning the width of the window. The top of the drawers can be a good spot for sitting and looking out the window, perhaps reading a book. This is a great opportunity to buy some planks of wood, and do a little basic carpentry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My worksmanship is quite low-level, but even I can appreciate the ability to take raw wood and turn it into something functional. In the past, I’ve created some rudimentary shelves for our shoes in a tiny nook by the front door. That project just entailed cutting the shelves to the right size, installing some simple pieces to hold the shelves, and tinting the wood to a darker color. The tint is something that I do for all woodworking projects, as the wood I buy is light-colored pine planks, and I think a darker color suits our house much better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this latest project, I ran into problems pretty quickly, as there was a worldwide shortage of wood once most of the world came out of quarantine to get back to construction in 2021. I’mt not typically very fast to finish a project, but this delay was especially long, as I had to keep checking our local hardware store, in the hopes that some wood might show up. Eventually, some wood did show up, and I hauled it back to our house with the trailer attached to my bicycle to continue the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This particular project involved some basic measurements to get all of the pieces in place. There were only two drawers to create, both quite large. The biggest difficulty was definitely the sliding drawer mechanism. I ordered a bunch of drawer sliders, and they work pretty well. However, there is almost no space at all between the wheel of the outslide slider, and the other slider which is attached to the drawer. This means that when attaching the pieces to the drawer, the heads of the screws which stick out about 1 millimeter often get caught on the outside wheels and wreak havoc. I spent a lot of time repositioning the screws to get them to their current state, which is not perfect, but as good as it can be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project has been the toughest one I’ve taken on when it comes to woodworking, as there are moving parts and the measurements all have to be very precise in order for the drawers to fit and the sliding mechanism to work. I’m proud to say that not only do the drawers fit in the space and slide correctly, but they actually look kind of nice as well. I used decent amount of tint in order to make everything darker, and I like the way it came out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m looking forward to filling these drawers up with stuff to gain some much-needed storage space elsewhere. I also really think it will be fun to sit on the created seat above the drawers, and look out the window or read a book while enjoying the furniture that I’ve created. That it itself is one of the more lasting pleasures that I get from working with wood.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Being a homeowner for the first time has been an opportunity to get involved with a lot of improvement projects around the house. One of my more recent projects has been the creation of a couple of drawers in a nook underneath a bedroom window. The space is perfect for a fixture, as it’s a small space between walls, spanning the width of the window. The top of the drawers can be a good spot for sitting and looking out the window, perhaps reading a book. This is a great opportunity to buy some planks of wood, and do a little basic carpentry.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">With Friends for Thanksgiving</title><link href="/blog/2021/11/friends-for-thanksgiving.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="With Friends for Thanksgiving" /><published>2021-11-28T09:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-11-28T09:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/11/friends-for-thanksgiving</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/11/friends-for-thanksgiving.html">&lt;p&gt;Being in France during the holidays means that once again we have to construct our own Thanksgiving plans. Thanksgiving is a tough holiday, because for many Americans it is the second most important holiday behind Christmas, yet it happens over a long weekend. This means that travel is not easy for many Americans, let alone those of us who live overseas. Needless to say, it’s not really possible for us to spend Thanksgiving with family, so we take that as an opportunity to invite old and new friends to take part in a Thanksgiving meal with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like most years, we moved our Thanksgiving Day meal to Saturday. When Thanksgiving Day itself is not a holiday, we all have work and school both on the day itself as well as Friday. But on Saturday, a group of about 10 gathered at our house. Among our guests were friends that we have known almost since our arrival in France, seven years ago, as well as new friends we have made since our move to Rambouillet in 2017, and even a couple that we have just met recently. As is typical among our friends, many different languages were present, but for this occasion, English tended to be the most spoken, with some French here and there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of our Thanksgiving Day traditions is Charlie Brown. Miriam and I watched the first episode of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/This_Is_America,_Charlie_Brown#Episodes&quot;&gt;This is America, Charlie Brown&lt;/a&gt;, which depicts the voyage of the Mayflower and the first Thanksgiving meal. Then, we watched &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A_Charlie_Brown_Thanksgiving&quot;&gt;A Charlie Brown Thanksgiving&lt;/a&gt;, which is not so much a historical tale as it is a Thanksgiving Day meal, as prepared and celebrated by Snoopy, Woodstock, Charlie Brown, and the Peanuts gang. We watched it with a few friends before the meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The meal was a huge success. My wife spent days preparing everything. The centerpiece was a big roast chicken, cooked in a lemon sauce that I have enjoyed many times before. Besides that, there was mashed potatoes, green beans, and baked sweet potatoes. There were even some Chinese dishes which emphasized the mixed nature of the event. A couple of other friends contributed garlic bread and cookies. In addition, there was chocolate cake and macarons. Basically, there was a lot of great food, and we really enjoyed ourselves at the table, as we must for any Thanksgiving meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another element which I personally enjoyed, was having a lovely fire going the whole day and night. We had been saving up firewood for an occasion such as this, and on a day which started with a little snow on the ground, and had rain mixed with freezing rain, it was wonderful to have the shutters closed and created our own warm and cozy space by the fire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We enjoyed the company of our friends immensely, a few of whom were Americans, a few others of whom had been to America several times, and all of whom enjoyed the meal. If I had to change one thing, I think I would move the meal to lunch time, which may be more traditional. That way, we don’t have to cut short the visit late at night, as we really enjoyed our guests’ company. In any case, it was a wonderful day for us, an opportunity to be thankful, nd a chance to share our home and table with friends.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Being in France during the holidays means that once again we have to construct our own Thanksgiving plans. Thanksgiving is a tough holiday, because for many Americans it is the second most important holiday behind Christmas, yet it happens over a long weekend. This means that travel is not easy for many Americans, let alone those of us who live overseas. Needless to say, it’s not really possible for us to spend Thanksgiving with family, so we take that as an opportunity to invite old and new friends to take part in a Thanksgiving meal with us.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Paddle the Waters Expedition</title><link href="/blog/2021/11/paddle-the-waters.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Paddle the Waters Expedition" /><published>2021-11-20T10:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-11-20T10:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/11/paddle-the-waters</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/11/paddle-the-waters.html">&lt;p&gt;Back when I was hiking on the Eastern Continental Trail, I had plenty of time to think about what kind of things I wanted to do afterwards. I thought about canoeing or kayaking on a river often. Though I haven’t really had a good opportunity to get out on a river, other than a poorly-planned attempt at a source of the Amur river, I have been finding some interesting expeditions done by other people. There are not a plethora of published source-to-sea expeditions on the world’s longest rivers, and most that I’ve found have been accomplished by professionals. For that reason, I’d like to mention a different type of expedition on the Mackenzie river that I have always admired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2012, Ben Roche and Vicki Lefrançois set out to travel from the Columbia Glacier, the source of the Athabasca River, downstream to the Arctic Sea at the mouth of the Mackenzie river. Four and a half months later, they accomplished this mission and became the only expedition of this type on the Mackenzie that I can find. Starting with a tough hike in the snow out to the glacier, heavily laden with gear, and ending in Tuktoyaktuk in early September as winter rapidly approached. Along the way they battled challenges such as high winds on Great Slave lake, hordes of mosquitos and flies, and long, lonely sections of river, especially the Mackenzie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I admire this expedition for several reasons. First, it’s not often that an expedition of this difficulty is taken on as a couple. Most trips that we see are completed by one person alone, usually a man. Second, though Ben, Vicki, and their faithful companion Tallak had trained well before the trip, it appears they did not have the experience of doing a trip of this nature before this attempt. The fact that they appear to have completed the trip with little to no serious thoughts of quitting shows their drive and of course their brilliant work as a couple and as a team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is perhaps the aspect that interests me the most concerning this trip. The fact that Ben and Vicki were able to do this trip not only as a couple, but as a multilingual couple, is real inspiration that perhaps someday my wife and I could do something similar. In the video compilations put together by Ben and Vicki (alternatively called the Paddle the Waters team), I get the sense that they just know how to have fun together, which is a big part of making those difficult times on a trip much more bearable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing which made this expedition interesting is that the Mackenzie River is the second longest river system in North America, yet it is rarely talked about because of its remote location. To see an expedition venture up the barely-inhabited Mackenzie River and go the entire distance of that great river, is a treat. I believe that the Paddle the Waters expedition on the Mackenzie shows that with good planning and determination, even amateur paddlers can take on a big expedition such as a source-to-sea descent of the Mackenzie River. I hope someday to do something similar. In the meantime, I must congratulate Ben and Vicki on completing such a quest, one which they will certainly be proud of for the rest of their lives.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Back when I was hiking on the Eastern Continental Trail, I had plenty of time to think about what kind of things I wanted to do afterwards. I thought about canoeing or kayaking on a river often. Though I haven’t really had a good opportunity to get out on a river, other than a poorly-planned attempt at a source of the Amur river, I have been finding some interesting expeditions done by other people. There are not a plethora of published source-to-sea expeditions on the world’s longest rivers, and most that I’ve found have been accomplished by professionals. For that reason, I’d like to mention a different type of expedition on the Mackenzie river that I have always admired.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">USA Beats Mexico</title><link href="/blog/2021/11/usa-beats-mexico.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="USA Beats Mexico" /><published>2021-11-14T12:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-11-14T12:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/11/usa-beats-mexico</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/11/usa-beats-mexico.html">&lt;p&gt;In the early hours of Saturday morning, I got up to watch the biggest soccer match the US Men’s National Team has played in a long team. The team’s biggest rival is Mexico, and the rivaly isn’t just about the soccer match. In most things, Mexico doesn’t stack up well against the United States. Economically, militarily, historically, and developmentally, the United States is superior. In most sports, the United States comes out on top as well. American football, baseball, basketball, ice hockey, and most any other sport would not be a difficult win for the US. But soccer is different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the history of the rivalry between the two teams, Mexico has won far more games. This stems mostly from the games between the beginning of the teams’ play in the 1930s up to the 1980s, when the United States did not have a competitive team. From the 1990s on, the matches have been much more competitive, and both teams have enjoyed success. The USA had the lion’s share of that success in the 2000s, but since then it has swung back to being a very even matchup. That being said, the USA has now won the last three matches in a row.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The USA won the Gold Cup final, which is a tournament that is played every two years in the United States, and as such is not nearly as prestigious as other regional tournaments such as the Copa America or the Euros. The USA then won the CONCACAF Nations League final, which is a brand new tournament, and therefore not necessarily very prestigious. Well, now the United States has beaten Mexico for the third straight time, and this time it was a World Cup Qualifying match, which is very important for both teams to get to the World Cup, the biggest tournament in the sport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The match was a joy to watch, which is the most important thing. In some matches in the past, the USA hung on with teams that did not necessarily have the talent of their Mexican counterpart, but which played their hearts out for each other as a unit. They might have to defend for long stretches, and finally attempt a counterattack. Not today. Both teams played attractive attacking football, and I think that the USA played better in both halves. Their second-half play was decidedly unmatched by their opponent. The most satisfying part of the match for me as a spectator was seeing the coherent passing throughout the pitch. The US was able to play the ball out of the back in tight quarters, making the right passes at the right moments to players who positioned themselves very well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only did the US score two great goals, they did it with a young team. I don’t think any of the players were over 30. Some were 18 years old. In comparison, the Mexican team was much older, but those years of experience did not translate to a higher level of play. The American players were faster to react, pressed the Mexican team high up the field, and were just overall faster. It was a fantastic experience as a fan, easily the best match the US has played in the World Cup qualifying campaign so far.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">In the early hours of Saturday morning, I got up to watch the biggest soccer match the US Men’s National Team has played in a long team. The team’s biggest rival is Mexico, and the rivaly isn’t just about the soccer match. In most things, Mexico doesn’t stack up well against the United States. Economically, militarily, historically, and developmentally, the United States is superior. In most sports, the United States comes out on top as well. American football, baseball, basketball, ice hockey, and most any other sport would not be a difficult win for the US. But soccer is different.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Turning on the Heat and Weighing Priorities</title><link href="/blog/2021/11/heat-priorities.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Turning on the Heat and Weighing Priorities" /><published>2021-11-06T09:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-11-06T09:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/11/heat-priorities</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/11/heat-priorities.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s November now, and my poor family has been living in a house that seems to get cooler by the day as winter approaches. Where we are, September is an enjoyable transition from summer to fall, October is a rude awakening that the warm weather is over, and by the time November arrives, we’re wondering if November isn’t technically winter. Today, we are waking up to a chilly morning, with the temperature below 0° Celsius. And yet, for now, only our children’s bedroom has the heat on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, I’m a bit of a cheapskate. So when I look at our expenses each month, I identify the electricity bill as being the biggest expense, and I try to find ways to minimize that expense. Of course, the fact that the electricity bill is the highest single expense is not necessarily unexpected, given that our neighborhood does not have a gas connection, meaning that the radiators which supply heat to each individual room are all electric. Also, I have to consider the fact that part of the electricity bill is the contract itself, meaning that there is less ability to reduce the bill in relation to its current amount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the same way, the argument can be made that increasing our electricity usage wouldn’t be that bad, even doubling our usage would not double the bill. Up until now, our strategy has been to heat the bedrooms, the bathroom, and the living room. For the living room, we bought a lot of firewood for the wood-burning stove, and haven’t been using the radiators. There are some inconveniences to that method, as we have to start and maintain the fire, but my wife and I both love having a fire going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When considering the heating, there are many factors. First of all, there is our happiness, which tends to descend with the temperature. But on the other hand, we can also stay somewhat warm by wearing more clothing. But on the other hand, it’s not enjoyable to wear a coat inside the house. But on the other hand, if we turn on the heat in the beginning of November, it will probably be on for almost five months, given that the month of March in Paris is not a warm, sunny, paradise. And back and forth go the arguments for and against turning on the heat, in which rooms, at what temperature, when, and for how long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it’s clear that the best option is a compromise somewhere in the middle. Saving a couple hundred euros over the course of the year won’t be worth it if we are unhappy sitting in a cold house. But it won’t just be a couple hundred euros if we turn the heat up warm enough to wear T-shirts and shorts around the house. We’re going to have to wear sweatshirts and long pants, but that’s fine with us. The main change I think we’ll be making is to turn on the radiators in the living room to have some bare minimum heat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why am I going on and on about a relatively mundane decision, given that the difference between no heat and plenty of heat is less than a thousand euros for the entire year? It’s the decision-making process that is important. We have to be able to have a process that correctly identifies all the important factors, and which identifies are own priorities. Then we try and reason the solution to align with those variables. It’s the same kind of process we use when getting groceries for the week, or planning a trip, or choosing a career. The stakes may be higher, but the process is roughly the same. We practice the process and master it, even on decisions like when to turn on the heat. Then, when it comes time to choose a house, a career, or a partner, we are prepared to make the right choice.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">It’s November now, and my poor family has been living in a house that seems to get cooler by the day as winter approaches. Where we are, September is an enjoyable transition from summer to fall, October is a rude awakening that the warm weather is over, and by the time November arrives, we’re wondering if November isn’t technically winter. Today, we are waking up to a chilly morning, with the temperature below 0° Celsius. And yet, for now, only our children’s bedroom has the heat on.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Halloween</title><link href="/blog/2021/10/halloween.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Halloween" /><published>2021-10-31T12:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-10-31T12:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/10/halloween</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/10/halloween.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve waited until the end of Halloween weekend in order to be able to provide a full recap of our goings-on this year. I think I can summarize by saying that as with most years, we did our best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a parent I have to say that I’m often a little depressed by the lack of effort that France puts into Halloween. To be fair, as an imported holiday it does not have the deep roots of other holidays here. But I do feel that, given that most other French holidays are Catholic, and therefore not actually observed by most of the population in any meaningful way, it would be nice to celebrate something together, and Halloween seems the perfect opportunity to do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know that some Catholics feel that observing Halloween impedes on Toussaint, which is the Catholic holiday. But given that Halloween is the day before Toussaint, and that Halloween is simply a time to have fun, especially for kids, we hope that more people will come to realize that we can do both. Halloween is just an opportunity to play silly games, do some activities together, and let children get excited about dressing up in their costumes, and of course for trick-or-treating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We always start a week or more before with the jack o’lanterns. I’m not an expert carver, but I’m able to do a basic design which guarantees I don’t go overboard and ruin the pumpkin. This year, I only found small pumpkins at the store, so I got four of those, and tried to share them with our friends. Needless to say, I was only partly successful. Thankfully, my wife found a big pumpkin, so we had our traditional public jack o’lantern outside our gate this week, in addition to some small ones decorating our house. Our neighbor actually did their own jack o’lantern this year, and they did a great job! Sadly I must not have sufficiently scraped the insides of some of the pumpkins, and they built up some fearsome mold by the end of the week. Thankfull they are now gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than that, we mostly just found some simple costumes for the kids. Daniel told us he wanted to be a pumpkin this year, which suited us just fine, as it’s a simple costume to find. Miriam found a cape and gloves with which she pretended to be a vampire. On Halloween night, the children put on their costumes underneath their coats, and we went out to the dark neighborhood, hoping to find someone handing out candy. No one in our neighborhood had a light on, but we did find a few houses in a nearby group that received our trick-or-treaters. In prior years, everything would have been fine, but now that Miriam is a little older, I could see that she felt a little disappointed by the few houses giving out candy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, when we got back, our neighbors had put out their fearsome jack o’lantern, and they gave the children a ton of candy. We finished off the holiday with our traditional viewing of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/It%27s_the_Great_Pumpkin,_Charlie_Brown&quot;&gt;It’s the Great Pumpkin, Charlie Brown&lt;/a&gt;. We also watched &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coco_(2017_film)&quot;&gt;Coco&lt;/a&gt; with Miriam, which was great way to finish off Halloween night. It’s a shame that we can’t have the big Halloween parties that I remember from my childhood, but I’m proud that we could at least establish some tradition for our children to remember fondly.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">I’ve waited until the end of Halloween weekend in order to be able to provide a full recap of our goings-on this year. I think I can summarize by saying that as with most years, we did our best.</summary></entry></feed>