<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-05-16T07:58:53+02:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Sterling Coleman</title><subtitle>A space for my personal projects and thoughts</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Finishing the Carpet</title><link href="/blog/2021/05/finishing-carpet.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Finishing the Carpet" /><published>2021-05-16T07:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-05-16T07:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/05/finishing-carpet</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/05/finishing-carpet.html">&lt;p&gt;For a long time, the upstairs bedrooms in our house have been unfinished. This is mostly because of a multitide of setbacks, starting with the discovery that we had water damage at two different windows. Including the time needed to find a suitable way to replace the windows as cheaply as possible, the manufacture of the windows, and the delays in the installation process, the replacement of these windows took over a year to complete. Once that was done, we were finally able to get our insurance company to send a contractor to do a little drywall underneath both windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that mess finally out of the way, I set to work looking for carpet. For some reason carpet is not very popular in France. Most homes that we have seen use parquet flooring, which can look good if a more expensive option is picked, but in our case the floor was obviously not a real hardwood floor, but rather a cheaper option. Furthermore, I don’t understand the aversion to using carpet in the bedrooms, where they add a soft touch and feel warmer than a cold wooden floor. This is a country where the weather is cold for half of the year, and for three months it’s miserably cold. What little carpet is available is mostly very thin, which feels more appropriate in a commercial setting than in the home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finally finding the carpet I wanted, I was worried about the price but finally made the decision to buy. Of course at this point the carpet was no longer available and the store had completely stopped stocking any more carpet of that particular brand. I despaired of finding something else that I actually wanted to install in my home of all the hundreds of paper-thin and rough carpets to be found on the internet. I was therefore very pleased to find a different store that had something very simiilar to my previous choice, and I bought it immediately. It’s always a bit unsettling to spend over a thousand euros on a single purchase, but after what I had been through, I was ready to pay to get what I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I still had research to do before I could install the carpet. I had considered putting a layer underneath the carpet, primarily for insulation. After searching around and reading  a lot of information on the subject, I came to the conclusion that it wasn’t really necessary, and that the type of carpet that I had chosen could be installed all by itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The installation process itself was not too difficult. The main issue was completely removing everything from each bedroom, one at a time. We removed a sublayer from one of the rooms to find it had been attached by glue, which was now a potent yellow dust that needed to be cleaned up. The other rooms didn’t have this problem, but I did have to almost completely disassemble my daughter’s IKEA bed in order to remove it from the room. The actual installation of the carpet just involved careful measurements and planning for the cuts of the carpet. I knew that I would have to join different cuts in a couple rooms, but I wanted to minimize that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that the work is pretty much done, I’m very happy with the look and feel. Most importantly, everyone is finally back in their own bedrooms for good. I still have some work to do to get a new bed installed for our son and build a wardrobe in our bedroom, but at the very least we have more breathing room now.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">For a long time, the upstairs bedrooms in our house have been unfinished. This is mostly because of a multitide of setbacks, starting with the discovery that we had water damage at two different windows. Including the time needed to find a suitable way to replace the windows as cheaply as possible, the manufacture of the windows, and the delays in the installation process, the replacement of these windows took over a year to complete. Once that was done, we were finally able to get our insurance company to send a contractor to do a little drywall underneath both windows.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Terrorism in Rambouillet</title><link href="/blog/2021/04/terrorism-rambouillet.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Terrorism in Rambouillet" /><published>2021-04-24T10:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-04-24T10:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/04/terrorism-rambouillet</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/04/terrorism-rambouillet.html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday afternoon, a man of Tunisian origin attacked and killed Stephanie, an employee at the Rambouillet police station, with a knife. He cut her throat before being killed by policemen on the scene. I found this to be much more shocking than most news of this type because I am well acquainted with the neighborhood around the police station. Our children’s school is a few hundred yards away. We’ve lived in Rambouillet for almost four years now, and for our town to be in the national spotlight and to make world news, albeit very briefly, for a story like this is actually quite surprising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rambouillet is a town that grew a lot in the twenty years preceding 1990, nearly doubling its size. In the thirty years since then, the town has increased its population by less than ten percent. As a result, the population continues to age. With an aging population comes a statistical tendency to vote for more conservative values and political representatives. As such, François Fillon, the Republican candidate, won the most votes in the first round of the 2017 presidential election, despite accusations of political nepotism, for which he was later convicted. Rambouillet is a town which in my mind aspires to be a miniature Versailles, and the comparison is easy to make. Rambouillet has a large château which was a residence for French royalty, including Marie Antoinette, who loved its large park and its creamery, gifted to her by her husband Louis XVI. In short, it’s not at all a hotspot for violence of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, events of this nature are not really surprising anymore in the Yvelines department as a whole, where the teacher Samuel Paty was infamously beheaded for showing cartoon caricatures depicting Mohammed in his class. Besides that, the town of Trappes has been known as being a hotspot for violence for decades, and is also recognized as having sent a lot of people to fight for the Islamic State relative to the rest of France. There continue to be clashes with police, often including attacks on police cars with rocks, and attacks on the police station with fireworks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a foreigner and a Christian in France, the political repercussions are at the forefront of my mind. It’s clear that President Macron has not become more popular since taking office in 2017, and his path to re-election will be a challenging one. He must convince voters that he deserves re-election in the face of discontent from the more liberal political spectrum, which supported the squashed Yellow Vest movement and strikes, as well as discontent from the more conservative political spectrum, which is not happy about continuing islamist and immigrant violence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continuing violence will probably cause Macron to either lose the election to someone who promises to impliment harsher actions, or Macron will have to implement those actions himself. When that happens, the response is likely to place more restrictions on religious activity in France as a whole, as the response to islamist attacks has been the promotion of secularism. Similarly, the response to immigrant violence is likely to inconvenience us as well, as we are non-European immigrants and France is unlikely to single out specific African and Middle Eastern immigrant groups. In summary, the situation is almost certainly going to get worse before it gets better.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Yesterday afternoon, a man of Tunisian origin attacked and killed Stephanie, an employee at the Rambouillet police station, with a knife. He cut her throat before being killed by policemen on the scene. I found this to be much more shocking than most news of this type because I am well acquainted with the neighborhood around the police station. Our children’s school is a few hundred yards away. We’ve lived in Rambouillet for almost four years now, and for our town to be in the national spotlight and to make world news, albeit very briefly, for a story like this is actually quite surprising.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Robert Massie’s Russian Rulers</title><link href="/blog/2021/03/massies-russian-rulers.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Robert Massie's Russian Rulers" /><published>2021-03-27T14:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-03-27T14:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/03/massies-russian-rulers</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/03/massies-russian-rulers.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve just finished Catherine the Great: Portrait of a Woman by Robert Massie, and since it is the third and final biography of a Russian emperor or empress that I will read, I’d like to dedicate a post to applaud these three great books. The first book written by Massie on the subject was Nicholas and Alexandra, published in 1967. Interestingly, the author became interested in this family when his son was born with hemophilia, a condition which also plagued Nicholas’ son Alexei. The next book, published over a decade later, was the Pulitzer Prize-winning Peter the Great: His Life and World. The final book, published in 2011 when Massie was over eighty years old, was the book on Catherine the Great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I happened to read the books in the order they were published. My memory from my time reading the first book was that the Romanovs were decent people, but they believed that it was their duty to be the rulers of Russia by hereditary right. Nicholas did not come across as haughty or condescending to his subjects. Basically, he was the one who lost the ultimate game of hot potato that occurs when a country does not reform itself enough to avoid a revolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second book on Peter the Great was highly interesting. I find the time period interesting all by itself. When I read a book about someone born in the seventeenth century, I can’t help but think of how much different life would have been like back then. Of course, the most interesting thing about the book was the way it described in detail Peter’s foresight in modernizing Russia, gaining access to the Baltic, creating Saint Petersburg, and reforming religion and culture in his empire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final book on Catherine the Great was great. The character of Catherine was fascinating, and it was enjoyable to read about someone who was in difficulty as a young woman rise from that to a position of power, and to reward those who helped her, and remain benevolent as an autocrat. The fact that Catherine was overwhelmingly a force for good, but that she still failed to ultimately remove serfdom, just goes to show the difficulty in getting things done politically, even as an empress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is obvious that an enormous amount of research went into each book. Each one is quite long. This most recent book took me over a month to finish. But it was worth it to read the whole thing, as Massie doesn’t skip anything. The books all cover the early childhoods of these rulers, and explain the environment at the time and why these people became the people that they became. Reading these biographies, I felt like I was in the heads of these emperors and empresses, and that I understood the various pressures they were under, and how they determined their goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that after reading these books, one of the major takeaways for me was the gladness I feel for not being in a position of power like that. Whatever power that there is to be had, whatever money is available to an emperor, wouldn’t be worth having the family be perpetually in jeopardy of being murdered by someone who wants to take the throne, or put someone else on the throne. Even if there is little danger of that, the entire family dynamic is rarely well-developed in a royal household. Catherine’s own son Paul was taken away from her after his birth, to be raised by her husband’s aunt, the Empress Elizabeth, who was the daughter of Peter the Great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a consequence, Catherine did something similar for the birth of her grandson Alexander. Massie doesn’t mince words when it comes to the things that Peter and Catherine did, despite their greatness. They were still humans, and as such Robert Massie’s books give a great insight into their personalities, and how they shaped the Russian Empire.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">I’ve just finished Catherine the Great: Portrait of a Woman by Robert Massie, and since it is the third and final biography of a Russian emperor or empress that I will read, I’d like to dedicate a post to applaud these three great books. The first book written by Massie on the subject was Nicholas and Alexandra, published in 1967. Interestingly, the author became interested in this family when his son was born with hemophilia, a condition which also plagued Nicholas’ son Alexei. The next book, published over a decade later, was the Pulitzer Prize-winning Peter the Great: His Life and World. The final book, published in 2011 when Massie was over eighty years old, was the book on Catherine the Great.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How Long is the Eastern Continental Trail?</title><link href="/blog/2021/03/ect-distance.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Long is the Eastern Continental Trail?" /><published>2021-03-21T16:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-03-21T16:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/03/ect-distance</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/03/ect-distance.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve finally gotten around to adding an important page to the Eastern Continental Trail website: the route distance &lt;a href=&quot;https://easterncontinentaltrail.com/route/distance&quot;&gt;page&lt;/a&gt;. This page responds to one of the more common questions that I received when I was hiking on the ECT: “How long is that?”. This question really deserved a page of its own, because the answer depends on several factors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, an ECT hiker has several choices to make. Besides the common choice of choosing to travel the trail going North, or to take the path less traveled and head South, there are choices which can actually affect the distance of the hike. First, the Florida Trail includes two basic East-West decisions: Lake Okeechobee and the Central Florida Corridors. Lake Okeechobee is situated in South Florida, and most hikers choose to take the slightly more direct route and travel West around this lake, rather than East, though the difference is a miniscule two miles. In Central Florida, many hikers choose to travel on the Eastern Corridor, which passes through the Northeastern suburbs of Orlando, while others choose the Western Corridor, which is 34 more miles in comparison, and includes the Green Swamp and a path much farther from Orlando.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most trails don’t contain these sorts of options. Besides these two choices, the only other real decision is to determine the Northern Terminus of the hike. The Eastern Continental Trail was originally a hike from Key West to Cap Gaspé in Québec. Since then, the International Appalachian Trail has expanded, and some hikers choose to include the provinces of Prince Edward Island, Nova Scotia, and Newfoundland in their journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So finally, the answer to the question is that the ECT is about 4800 miles (7800 kilometers) when starting or finishing at Cap Gaspé, or 5700 miles (9200 kilometers) when starting or finishing at Crow Head (or Belle Isle) in Northern Newfoundland. These distances should be accurate, as the distances of each component trail have been refined over the years to be more and more accurate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The distance of the Appalachian Trail has been well studied over the years, and is currently measured to be 2193 miles (3537 kilomets), which is almost half of the ECT as it runs between Key West and Cap Gaspé. Likewise, the distances of the other trails is continually being more accurately measured. In my mind, the real question in this area is: what is the most accurate way to measure the distance of the trail. For example, is a detailed GPS track a good source? From what I have seen, the measured distances of the files which exist on the internet are significantly different from those of the published lengths of the trails. For example, I have a Keyhole Markup file for the Appalachian Trail which measures 1970 miles, a full 220 miles of difference, or 10% of the entire trail. Meanwhile, each chapter of the International Appalachian Trail seems to have used the GPS file data as the official distance, as each file matches the reported distance to the kilometer (or mile).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether or not the reported numbers are 99% accurate or just 95% accurate, the page which I have added to the ECT website clearly shows the breakdown of the distance among the ECT’s component trails. Besides the Appalachian Trail, about 1300 miles (2100 kilometers) of distance is in the state of Florida alone. The relative distance of the IAT in proportion to the entire ECT varies greatly depending on the choice to set the Northern Terminus at Newfoundland or Québec. The extra 850 miles (1400 kilometers) makes Newfoundland the province with the most trail distance in the IAT, instead of Québec.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter what choices are made, the Eastern Continental Trail is quite a long trail. I’d pack a lunch.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">I’ve finally gotten around to adding an important page to the Eastern Continental Trail website: the route distance page. This page responds to one of the more common questions that I received when I was hiking on the ECT: “How long is that?”. This question really deserved a page of its own, because the answer depends on several factors.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My One Thing at a Time Theory</title><link href="/blog/2021/03/one-thing-theory.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My One Thing at a Time Theory" /><published>2021-03-07T15:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-03-07T15:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/03/one-thing-theory</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/03/one-thing-theory.html">&lt;p&gt;Often when I’m working on a project, a proposal will be made to make multiple improvements at the same time. We can upgrade to a different technology so that we can use that technology’s exclusive features. So why not do both at once? The short answer is usually: because it multiplies the risk of encountering problems. I find that this is a principle which applies not just to a software project, but to life in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I’m reading about other people hiking or doing some kind of adventure, there are often comments made about financial issues. Someone wants to go on an adventure, but they haven’t got the funds to do so. Instead of carefully saving up the funds, making a financial plan for managing the money during the adventure and how much will be left afterwards, the person may choose to just go out there, and hope that the trip will turn out to be cheaper than originally thought, or that a little money can be raised through donations, or by putting out content for people to see. To me, this is the same category of problem as the software issue. We want a new feature or a new adventure, and instead of being sure that we have fulfilled the prerequisites first, we try to combine the two. By mixing up multiple things, we risk nothing going well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a software project, the risk that we take when combining things is that when a problem such as a bug arises, we have to be able to isolate and correct the bug. When the bug is linked to a development which introduces multiple changes, this may mean rolling back all of that stuff while the bug gets fixed. Even if we are doing some preliminary steps only in order to build on those steps later, it is best to isolate that work and deliver it by itself. If we can confirm that the first steps have been performed correctly, then we can proceed. Otherwise, when we deliver everything at once and there is a bug, we have multiple variables which could be causing the bug.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On an adventure, obviously we need funds to buy equipment, transportation, food and often, lodging. Not having enough money is stressful. It makes an otherwise enjoyable and exciting adventure seem like work. We may have to beg for free gear, or ask for donations online. For me, part of the problem with that is that it no longer becomes our adventure. Personally, I don’t really want to thank a list of sponsors as the end of an adventure, and be forced to say that none of it would have been possible without them. I want to accomplish something without depending on the charity of others. I want it to be my adventure, not a corporation’s adventure in which I am featured. First I will be sure to have everything I need, then I will really enjoy myself, during and after the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The advantage of my theory is that often, the prerequisites to the things we want are good things in and of themselves. It would be good to save up some money, even if we aren’t going on an adventure. It would be good to switch to a newer technology, even if we don’t take full advantage of all of its features. The consequence is that if we don’t satisfy the prerequisites, we don’t attempt to do what we really want to do. I would actually argue that is is a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many times, I have seen someone get turned off by a bad experience that could have been avoided through good planning. A hiking trip can be a lot of fun, but if we are stressed out about money during the trip, we might get the false impression that this is a problem common to trips of this nature, and not make second attempt after proper planning. The same type of problem can occur on a project of any kind. However, I’ve rarely seen someone regret slowly and steadily making progress towards their goal, one step at a time.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Often when I’m working on a project, a proposal will be made to make multiple improvements at the same time. We can upgrade to a different technology so that we can use that technology’s exclusive features. So why not do both at once? The short answer is usually: because it multiplies the risk of encountering problems. I find that this is a principle which applies not just to a software project, but to life in general.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Running</title><link href="/blog/2021/02/running.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Running" /><published>2021-02-28T20:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-02-28T20:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/02/running</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/02/running.html">&lt;p&gt;This weekend I went running for the first time in almost a year. My friend Yohan has been trying to get me back into running off and on for several months, and this weekend I finally gave in and put my running shoes back on. It had been a long time since I had actually done any running, as I stopped completely after finishing the 33rd Rambouillet Half-Marathon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in the fall of 2019, I decided that I was going to start training for the half-marathon that is put on annually in our town. I had seen organisers for the event in years past, as there is a portion of the route that is not far from our house. I saw the half-marathon as a big challenge, but something that was within my grasp if I prepared well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started running in early September, my first outing being just five kilometers. From there, I took on a fairly challenging plan to increase my distance. Each time I went running, I added a kilometer to my route. Going running twice a week, I was able to quickly change from running just five kilometers, to ten or eleven kilometers, which is a quarter of a marathon. I was halfway there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changing my running to just once on the weekend, I often found a partner to run with, and continued to increase the distance by one kilometer each time. It soon became difficult to find routes that were exactly the distance I was looking for. We are lucky to have agricultural land near us, and there are tracks running through these parcels of land made for tractors and other farm equipment. These are good for running, as there are no cars, and in fact no one there at all. Aside from difficulties in the mud after a big rain, these were ideal spots to do the training for the half-marathon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon, however, I outgrew this area, as there simply weren’t any good options for the distances I was trying to do. After doing about seventeen kilometers one weekend, I realized that I could probably run the entire half-marathon (21.1 km) if I tried. Soon afterwards, I went running with my friend Gwen. We weren’t really planning on running a half-marathon, but we went far away from Rambouillet to a neighboring village, and had difficulty finding a good route to loop back to our starting point. By the time we finished, we had done the full distance. It had taken us two hours and fifteen minutes, which is quite slow for people who had been training regularly. One of our excuses was that we had to check our phones to find our way back, even bushwhacking and doing a small portion of the distance on the shoulder of the highway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kept up my training, and was soon able to do the half-marathon distance at a much quicker pace. My fastest time was one hour and forty eight minutes. I impressed myself, but I also developed pain in my left knee. On the day of the race, I knew that I was going to be in pain, and that I shouldn’t try to go too fast. After three kilometers, I started to feel it. I persevered and finished the race in just more than two hours, but I didn’t have much desire to run again. I had accomplished my main goal, and I had participated in the official race and finished it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A year later, I’m starting to run again, but not for a half-marathon (canceled this year). I’m doing it just to push my limits a little bit, and to do some simple physical exercise outside, hopefully with the whole family. I never really enjoyed running when I was younger, but now that I’m no longer playing organized sports, it is a simple way to stay active. Coming back after a morning run feels good, and even if I don’t find a specific goal or event to build towards, I will enjoy incorporating something more physical into my lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">This weekend I went running for the first time in almost a year. My friend Yohan has been trying to get me back into running off and on for several months, and this weekend I finally gave in and put my running shoes back on. It had been a long time since I had actually done any running, as I stopped completely after finishing the 33rd Rambouillet Half-Marathon.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Year of the Cow</title><link href="/blog/2021/02/year-of-the-cow.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Year of the Cow" /><published>2021-02-14T21:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-02-14T21:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/02/year-of-the-cow</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/02/year-of-the-cow.html">&lt;p&gt;This past weekend has been double packed with special days. Friday was the Chinese New Year, which is actually an event that goes on for weeks. This year is the year of the Cow, which is supposed to be a more auspicious symbol than that of the previous year, the Rat. Given the events that transpired last year, the symbol of the rat seems to be quite fitting. I think everyone is hoping that the cow brings along better news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Certainly China has been at the center of the headlines in the past year, with the unfortunate outbreak of COVID-19 appearing to have originated in the city of Wuhan. Wuhan is the capital of Hubei province in the center of China. It is also the place where I worked as an English teacher. I met my wife there and got married there. We actually had plane tickets directly to Wuhan from Paris set for February 2020, but the rat of 2020 reared its ugly head and canceled those plans just a couple of weeks before our trip. With the coronavirus scare starting to be resolved with the wave of vaccinations currently underway, we hope that China will no longer be the source of bad news or negative attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, we’re happy to have met other Chinese people in our town to be able to share a celebratory meal. One advantage of China being such a populous country, is that there are Chinese people almost everywhere you go. They are always a good source of friends for us, as we like to maintain links to Chinese culture for ourselves as well as our children. We had one such couple over yesterday, as well as a couple who are not Chinese. We all had a big meal together, and it felt great to see each other after so much time under quarantine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of all, it was a fun time for our children. Our friends have children at the same age as ours, and they all have a blast running around the house together. Sometimes our son Daniel ends up following all the bigger kids around, but this time he was in luck, as there were other children his own age to play with. A lot of our friends have girls, so it was a real treat for him to get to play with a boy his own age this time. At one point, I looked over to the couch and saw four little legs sticking up into the air from a jumbled pile, which consisted of two small boys rolling around and laughing together. It was fun for me as a parent, as I usually only see Daniel play with his big sister.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the adults, it was a time to eat. We must have sat at the table for an hour and a half minimum. My wife had spent the better part of two or three days preparing many different dishes. When our friends arrived, they helped by making dumplings. This involved simply taking the circular dough slices, putting dabs of pork inside, and sealing them, forming the dumpling shape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides dumplings, there were many other dishes of beef, pork, Kung Pao Chicken, fried rice, and others that I can’t even remember. We ate as much as we could ever want, and there was still a table full of food. Everyone was able to take home their favorite dish, and even after that there was plenty of food leftover for us. Such is a testament to what a good host my wife is, and the amount of work she puts in to making others feel great when they are at our house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though we had a great time among ourselves, we were definitely missing our family back in China. We still haven’t been able to visit them and don’t know when the next good opportunity to go there will be. We want the best for them and them for us, but unfortunately we live on the other side of the world, and this past year has shown that catching a quick flight is far from a guarantee. We’re hoping the Year of the Cow brings better news for us all.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">This past weekend has been double packed with special days. Friday was the Chinese New Year, which is actually an event that goes on for weeks. This year is the year of the Cow, which is supposed to be a more auspicious symbol than that of the previous year, the Rat. Given the events that transpired last year, the symbol of the rat seems to be quite fitting. I think everyone is hoping that the cow brings along better news.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Eastern Continental Trail Route</title><link href="/blog/2021/02/eastern-continental-trail-route.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Eastern Continental Trail Route" /><published>2021-02-07T12:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-02-07T12:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/02/eastern-continental-trail-route</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/02/eastern-continental-trail-route.html">&lt;p&gt;As I have often mentioned, my time on the Eastern Continental Trail was transformative for me. Finishing the thru-hike, and doing so without having ever done a real hiking trip before, was a big accomplishment for me. Afterwards, I was ready and confidnent to take on new challenges. Therefore I look back fondly on my time on the ECT and hope to follow the journeys of new hikers on the trail. Because the ECT isn’t a trail with its own caretaker organization, the information needed to learn more about the trail is scattered among the various trails which constitute the ECT, as well as the personal sites of various hikers. Therefore, I’ve decided to launch a new website dedicated to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://easterncontinentaltrail.com&quot;&gt;Eastern Continental Trail&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The website has just been started recently, and there is much work to be done. So far, I’ve spent a lot of time working on the route page. This is important, because as soon as someone arrives on the home page for the site, they should instantly have an idea of what the Eastern Continental Trail is. By putting a static image of a satellite view of the East Coast with the trail layered in, the vast distance of the trail and its geography should be evident. Clicking this image leads to the route page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The route page is currently just a Google Map of the Eastern Continental Trail. Just putting this map together took a lot of time. In order to do so, I had to find the appropriate files for the Florida Keys Overseas Heritage Trail, South Dade Greenway, Roberts Lake Trail, Florida Trail, Pinhoti Trail, Benton MacKaye Trail, Appalachian Trail, and each state or province of the International Appalachian Trail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even all that was not enough. The trail on Prince Edward Island is simply the Confederation Trail, but the Confederation Trail is a network of trails, and therefore I had to remove all the portions which are not part of the Eastern Continental Trail. I had to do the same type of thing for Newfoundland. The file which I found on the Florida Trail required the most work. It has the trail split into over a hundred small sections, with many parts being connector trails or side trails. I removed all the unnecessary stuff, and then had to work a considerable amount to trim down the file size to something acceptable by Google Maps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There does not seem to be any GPS track or other similar file for the Nova Scotia portion of the International Appalachian Trail. I used the existing maps to make a new file, as I did for the Alabama Roadwalk and the walk on US 41 to the Roberts Lake Trail. The end result is, to my knowledge, the first ever interactive map of the official route of the entire Eastern Continental Trail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that this is a very important part of advocating for the ECT. Most people want to see a visual representation of the trail, and simply stating that the trail includes a bunch of trails on the East Coast doesn’t really do the trail justice. A single interactive map with the entire trail should capture more interest in the trail. The goal of the website is to continue to centralize information on the trail in this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Future developments on the route page include adding the connection between the Northern Terminus of the Appalachian Trail and the Southern Terminus of the International Appalachian Trail. In addition, I will be adding a simple tool to calculate how long the route is, depending on the route taken in Florida and the choice of Northern Terminus. Many people start or end their hike at Cap Gaspé in Quebec, but some choose to additionally do the sections in Prince Edward Island, Nova Scotia, and Newfoundland, though none of these sections are connected to each other by land.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is much more to be done to make the site really useful, but I’m already happy to have the route online. I want to put more resources on the website to help people planning to spend time on the trail, and I also want to build a small community interface. One nice thing about the ECT is that few people actually hike the trail, so the thru-hiker community is quite small and can have a more personal feel. I’ll be working on bringing that experience to encourage more publicity for the Eastern Continental Trail.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">As I have often mentioned, my time on the Eastern Continental Trail was transformative for me. Finishing the thru-hike, and doing so without having ever done a real hiking trip before, was a big accomplishment for me. Afterwards, I was ready and confidnent to take on new challenges. Therefore I look back fondly on my time on the ECT and hope to follow the journeys of new hikers on the trail. Because the ECT isn’t a trail with its own caretaker organization, the information needed to learn more about the trail is scattered among the various trails which constitute the ECT, as well as the personal sites of various hikers. Therefore, I’ve decided to launch a new website dedicated to the Eastern Continental Trail.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Sequelize Saga</title><link href="/blog/2021/01/sequelize-saga.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Sequelize Saga" /><published>2021-01-30T11:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-01-30T11:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/01/sequelize-saga</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/01/sequelize-saga.html">&lt;p&gt;Recently I found the source to a very befuddling problem that I had been grappling with on and off again for weeks. As a warning to other developers, I’d like to recount my tale of woe. The subject here is Sequelize, which is an ORM (Objet Relational Mapping) tool which can be used to query a database from the backend of a web application. Sequelize is quite versatile, being available for use with Postgres, MySQL, MariaDB, SQLite and Microsoft SQL Server. In this saga, Sequelize is querying a Postgres database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The utility of a tool like Sequelize is that it can abstract the database to models and functions. Models can be defined, and these models represent tables. These models then expose simple functions, which represent types of queries. One of the more useful examples is the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bulkCreate&lt;/code&gt; function, which can insert multiple records into a table in just one function call. This type of function is especially useful when performing operations on large sets of data, such as a data migration. We can simply construct an array of models and pass that array to the function. The function inserts each model as a record in the specified table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what does it return? In Postgres, the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;RETURNING&lt;/code&gt; keyword can be used to define what values are returned from the query. Therefore, Sequelize has the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;returning&lt;/code&gt; option, which activates this option. Postgres even has extra functionality for this feature, allowing an array of fields to return to be passed instead of a simple boolean if desired. But when I search the internet for “bulkCreate”, I can see that there may be issues, based on the fact that the top five results are all for Sequelize, and two of those results are for issues. One of these stemmed from a simple lack of knowledge of this option, and the other is a real issue logged on the site for the GitHub repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of GitHub issues, the Sequelize currently has over a thousand opened issues. That speaks partly to the popularity of the tool. The GitHub repository has over twenty thousand stars. It also demonstrates that the application has some issues. Currently, there are almost fifty open issues related to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bulkCreate&lt;/code&gt;. One of the main topics is the same issue that I ran into: namely, that on one environment, Sequelize returned the IDs of newly-created records from &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bulkCreate&lt;/code&gt;, while on another environment, the exact same line of code did not. The call did not pass &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;returning: true&lt;/code&gt;, meaning that according to the current &lt;a href=&quot;https://sequelize.org/master/class/lib/model.js~Model.html&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;, the default value used is &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;false&lt;/code&gt;. So why did one instance of the code magically return the ID anyway?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, according to this &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sequelize/sequelize/issues/12711&quot;&gt;issue&lt;/a&gt;, the documentation is wrong! The default value is actually &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;true&lt;/code&gt;. But if that is the case, why does one version of the code not return the newly-created IDs? To explain that, we first have to acknowledge that the code should explicitly pass &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;returning: true&lt;/code&gt;, as the documentation suggests, if it expects to use these IDs. Expecting the function to return these IDs by magic is unacceptable, despite it being the admitted behavior as stated in the GitHub issue. Next, we have to examine our use of package versions to be sure that we are using the same version of Sequelize in both cases. Given that we performed an &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;npm install&lt;/code&gt; on both environments, we would hope that the same version would be installed in both cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alas, the way that we have defined our package dependencies leaves room for error. If we define the Sequelize dependency as &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;^5.1.0&lt;/code&gt;, then an &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;npm install&lt;/code&gt; will check to see if we have at least that major and minor version, and if we do, it won’t upgrade the package. In the case that it does need to upgrade, it will get the latest minor version, such as 5.22. Unfortunately, version 5.22 works as explained in the GitHub issue, whereas version 5.3 works as the documentation describes. Whether or not this is a breaking change is debatable, given that it is difficult to imagine a scenario in which we are creating multiple records, and expecting to not have the IDs returned, and that having them returned breaks our logic. But it certainly should be documented behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is that combining mistakes in our version logic, the code, and the Sequelize repository leads to a big headache. If we want to allow our application a margin of error for these types of things, it may be better to use an ORM which at least behaves as documented. Ultimately, the application should define specific version of packages, especially in the case of Sequelize, such that extra steps such as removing the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;node_modules&lt;/code&gt; directory are not needed to ensure that two different environments have the same packages. And finally, we have to write code that makes sense. If we expect &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bulkCreate&lt;/code&gt; to return something, then we need to tell it to do that.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Recently I found the source to a very befuddling problem that I had been grappling with on and off again for weeks. As a warning to other developers, I’d like to recount my tale of woe. The subject here is Sequelize, which is an ORM (Objet Relational Mapping) tool which can be used to query a database from the backend of a web application. Sequelize is quite versatile, being available for use with Postgres, MySQL, MariaDB, SQLite and Microsoft SQL Server. In this saga, Sequelize is querying a Postgres database.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On the Trail: Matthew Hengst</title><link href="/blog/2021/01/matthew-hengst.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On the Trail: Matthew Hengst" /><published>2021-01-24T20:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-01-24T20:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/01/matthew-hengst</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/01/matthew-hengst.html">&lt;p&gt;During a recent conversation with my parents, I mentioned that it was a shame that no one had recently surfaced on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://trailjournals.com&quot;&gt;Trail Journals&lt;/a&gt; site with a journal of a hike on the Eastern Continental Trail. Ever since I hiked the ECT in 2012, I’ve been keen to read other people’s experiences. Sadly, very few seem to take on the challenge of a hike covering the length of the East Coast in the United States as well as a portion of Canada. Of course, I know that not everyone publishes their hiking efforts online, and of those who do, not everyone uses the same website which I used when I hiked the trail. So, I did a quick search on the internet to see if by chance I could find information elsewhere, and I happened to come across Matthew Hengst!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matthew started hiking North on the Eastern Continental Trail just before New Year, which is about the same timing as the beginning of my own hike, way back in 2012. He is already an experienced thru-hiker, having just finished the Pacific Crest Trail last year. He also has a nice &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.firstchurchofthemasochist.com/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;, with links to his Instagram and YouTube accounts, both of which have good content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s rare to find someone hiking the Eastern Continental Trail at all. It’s even more rare to find someone doing the trip and simultaneously putting out good content. When I did the trail, I personally struggled to write down my thoughts into journal entries, often having to take time to write entries for the past several days all at once. For that reason, I’m impressed that Matthew is able to compile videos of a decent length every few days. I’m sure it takes a lot of work. I have been enjoying the videos, as I know the trail and I understand a bit of what a hiker experiences on this trail. Through the videos, I can see that Matthew is going to do well on his thru-hike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first portion of the hike, from the Southernmost Point in the Continental United States to the beginning of the Florida Trail, can easily discourage hikers and get them to quit the hike before it has really begun. There were few good spots to camp in the Florida Keys back in 2012, and it can only have gotten more difficult since then. Increased traffic and COVID-19 can only made hiking harder, but Matthew has taken it all in stride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He has not started out doing needlessly ambitious days of more than thirty miles like I did, and he seems to have done a better job planning his stopping point for each night well in advance. Hiking in the Keys, while a unique experience, can be uniquely frustrating, so from my perspective the fact that Matthew can just accept these frustrations and move on shows that once he gets onto more secluded trails in Florida, there won’t be much stopping him from succeeding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think Matthew is going to enjoy the trail, and I hope that others enjoy his videos and photos. I’m a big advocate of the Eastern Continental Trail, and the best way to advocate for it is to show off all the cool stuff there is on this trail, in places like Florida. Even the unique experience of hiking along the Overseas Heritage Trail in the Florida Keys is something many people in the hiking community haven’t seen. Matthew is doing a great job of showing off what the ECT has to offer, and I’ll definitely be following along with this journey and rooting for him all along the way.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">During a recent conversation with my parents, I mentioned that it was a shame that no one had recently surfaced on the Trail Journals site with a journal of a hike on the Eastern Continental Trail. Ever since I hiked the ECT in 2012, I’ve been keen to read other people’s experiences. Sadly, very few seem to take on the challenge of a hike covering the length of the East Coast in the United States as well as a portion of Canada. Of course, I know that not everyone publishes their hiking efforts online, and of those who do, not everyone uses the same website which I used when I hiked the trail. So, I did a quick search on the internet to see if by chance I could find information elsewhere, and I happened to come across Matthew Hengst!</summary></entry></feed>