<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-11-06T09:18:17+01:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Sterling Coleman</title><subtitle>A space for my personal projects and thoughts</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Turning on the Heat and Weighing Priorities</title><link href="/blog/2021/11/heat-priorities.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Turning on the Heat and Weighing Priorities" /><published>2021-11-06T09:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-11-06T09:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/11/heat-priorities</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/11/heat-priorities.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s November now, and my poor family has been living in a house that seems to get cooler by the day as winter approaches. Where we are, September is an enjoyable transition from summer to fall, October is a rude awakening that the warm weather is over, and by the time November arrives, we’re wondering if November isn’t technically winter. Today, we are waking up to a chilly morning, with the temperature below 0° Celsius. And yet, for now, only our children’s bedroom has the heat on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, I’m a bit of a cheapskate. So when I look at our expenses each month, I identify the electricity bill as being the biggest expense, and I try to find ways to minimize that expense. Of course, the fact that the electricity bill is the highest single expense is not necessarily unexpected, given that our neighborhood does not have a gas connection, meaning that the radiators which supply heat to each individual room are all electric. Also, I have to consider the fact that part of the electricity bill is the contract itself, meaning that there is less ability to reduce the bill in relation to its current amount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the same way, the argument can be made that increasing our electricity usage wouldn’t be that bad, even doubling our usage would not double the bill. Up until now, our strategy has been to heat the bedrooms, the bathroom, and the living room. For the living room, we bought a lot of firewood for the wood-burning stove, and haven’t been using the radiators. There are some inconveniences to that method, as we have to start and maintain the fire, but my wife and I both love having a fire going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When considering the heating, there are many factors. First of all, there is our happiness, which tends to descend with the temperature. But on the other hand, we can also stay somewhat warm by wearing more clothing. But on the other hand, it’s not enjoyable to wear a coat inside the house. But on the other hand, if we turn on the heat in the beginning of November, it will probably be on for almost five months, given that the month of March in Paris is not a warm, sunny, paradise. And back and forth go the arguments for and against turning on the heat, in which rooms, at what temperature, when, and for how long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it’s clear that the best option is a compromise somewhere in the middle. Saving a couple hundred euros over the course of the year won’t be worth it if we are unhappy sitting in a cold house. But it won’t just be a couple hundred euros if we turn the heat up warm enough to wear T-shirts and shorts around the house. We’re going to have to wear sweatshirts and long pants, but that’s fine with us. The main change I think we’ll be making is to turn on the radiators in the living room to have some bare minimum heat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why am I going on and on about a relatively mundane decision, given that the difference between no heat and plenty of heat is less than a thousand euros for the entire year? It’s the decision-making process that is important. We have to be able to have a process that correctly identifies all the important factors, and which identifies are own priorities. Then we try and reason the solution to align with those variables. It’s the same kind of process we use when getting groceries for the week, or planning a trip, or choosing a career. The stakes may be higher, but the process is roughly the same. We practice the process and master it, even on decisions like when to turn on the heat. Then, when it comes time to choose a house, a career, or a partner, we are prepared to make the right choice.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">It’s November now, and my poor family has been living in a house that seems to get cooler by the day as winter approaches. Where we are, September is an enjoyable transition from summer to fall, October is a rude awakening that the warm weather is over, and by the time November arrives, we’re wondering if November isn’t technically winter. Today, we are waking up to a chilly morning, with the temperature below 0° Celsius. And yet, for now, only our children’s bedroom has the heat on.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Halloween</title><link href="/blog/2021/10/halloween.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Halloween" /><published>2021-10-31T12:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-10-31T12:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/10/halloween</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/10/halloween.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve waited until the end of Halloween weekend in order to be able to provide a full recap of our goings-on this year. I think I can summarize by saying that as with most years, we did our best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a parent I have to say that I’m often a little depressed by the lack of effort that France puts into Halloween. To be fair, as an imported holiday it does not have the deep roots of other holidays here. But I do feel that, given that most other French holidays are Catholic, and therefore not actually observed by most of the population in any meaningful way, it would be nice to celebrate something together, and Halloween seems the perfect opportunity to do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know that some Catholics feel that observing Halloween impedes on Toussaint, which is the Catholic holiday. But given that Halloween is the day before Toussaint, and that Halloween is simply a time to have fun, especially for kids, we hope that more people will come to realize that we can do both. Halloween is just an opportunity to play silly games, do some activities together, and let children get excited about dressing up in their costumes, and of course for trick-or-treating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We always start a week or more before with the jack o’lanterns. I’m not an expert carver, but I’m able to do a basic design which guarantees I don’t go overboard and ruin the pumpkin. This year, I only found small pumpkins at the store, so I got four of those, and tried to share them with our friends. Needless to say, I was only partly successful. Thankfully, my wife found a big pumpkin, so we had our traditional public jack o’lantern outside our gate this week, in addition to some small ones decorating our house. Our neighbor actually did their own jack o’lantern this year, and they did a great job! Sadly I must not have sufficiently scraped the insides of some of the pumpkins, and they built up some fearsome mold by the end of the week. Thankfull they are now gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than that, we mostly just found some simple costumes for the kids. Daniel told us he wanted to be a pumpkin this year, which suited us just fine, as it’s a simple costume to find. Miriam found a cape and gloves with which she pretended to be a vampire. On Halloween night, the children put on their costumes underneath their coats, and we went out to the dark neighborhood, hoping to find someone handing out candy. No one in our neighborhood had a light on, but we did find a few houses in a nearby group that received our trick-or-treaters. In prior years, everything would have been fine, but now that Miriam is a little older, I could see that she felt a little disappointed by the few houses giving out candy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, when we got back, our neighbors had put out their fearsome jack o’lantern, and they gave the children a ton of candy. We finished off the holiday with our traditional viewing of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/It%27s_the_Great_Pumpkin,_Charlie_Brown&quot;&gt;It’s the Great Pumpkin, Charlie Brown&lt;/a&gt;. We also watched &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coco_(2017_film)&quot;&gt;Coco&lt;/a&gt; with Miriam, which was great way to finish off Halloween night. It’s a shame that we can’t have the big Halloween parties that I remember from my childhood, but I’m proud that we could at least establish some tradition for our children to remember fondly.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">I’ve waited until the end of Halloween weekend in order to be able to provide a full recap of our goings-on this year. I think I can summarize by saying that as with most years, we did our best.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">PostGIS</title><link href="/blog/2021/10/postgis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="PostGIS" /><published>2021-10-23T12:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-10-23T12:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/10/postgis</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/10/postgis.html">&lt;p&gt;Recently I was working on a personal project involving geographical data, and realized that I needed to do spatial calculations such as distance inside a certain radius. In previous times, I might have programmed a function in JavaScript to do the calculations directly in the backend of my application. But in recent years, I’ve been improving my awareness of how to structure applications and make the right decisions when it comes to assigning responsibilities and roles among the different portions of an application. In the old legend of the Handyman’s Invoice, the engineer explains that knowing where to place the fix is worth much more than the fix itself. With that in mind, wouldn’t it be great to do the geographical calculations directly at the database level?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem I was presented with demanded handling a large set of geographical data, and performing distance calculations to return the subset which matched a certain criteria. Clearly, the JavaScript solution would not be ideal. Even getting started on such a solution would present problems. Would the backend simply get all data, then filter via its calculations? Theoretically, the backend could do some prior calculations, such as calculating absolute maximum and minimum latitude and longitude limits, then get all points within those limits, and finally perform the radius calculations to see which points actually fall in the circle. And in fact, the instructions sent to the database by the backend could become even more complicated if the backend calculated certain regions (to exclude) that were within the absolute limits, but certain not to be within the radius, such as the corners of a square which contains a circle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By thinking about the problem this way and trying to improve the backend solution, we can see that we are moving towards the ideal solution, of having the database return only the points within the radius, and doing no extra calculations in the backend whatsoever. This would be not only more logical, but also better in terms of performance. Such a solution would require database tools which understand a spatial calculation, and ideally could use the power of an index to avoid a sequential search of the geographical data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter &lt;a href=&quot;https://postgis.net&quot;&gt;PostGIS&lt;/a&gt;. PostGIS is an extension of PostgreSQL databases that loads a library of geographical and geometrical functions, types, and indexes. There is too much to present in one post, but suffice it to say that every possible function, data type, and index is present in this very helpful tool. For my project, I first needed a function that would calculate the distance between a data point and a test point (or alternatively, calculate the inclusion of a point within a given radius of another point). PostGIS has many functions that could fill this requirement, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://postgis.net/docs/manual-1.4/ST_Distance_Sphere.html&quot;&gt;Distance Sphere&lt;/a&gt;. Note that the function even takes a spherical shape into consideration, and treats points as WGS 80 latitude/longitude points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there is another function, &lt;a href=&quot;https://postgis.net/docs/ST_DWithin.html&quot;&gt;Within&lt;/a&gt;, that does one better. This function accomplishes the same goal, yet can take a &lt;a href=&quot;http://postgis.net/workshops/postgis-intro/geography.html&quot;&gt;geography&lt;/a&gt; type, and most importantly, seeks by default to use a &lt;a href=&quot;http://postgis.net/workshops/postgis-intro/indexing.html&quot;&gt;spatial index&lt;/a&gt;. This is where PostGIS goes from being useful to being critically important. Using a spatial index, we no longer need to sequentially scan all of our data points. Instead, we have the points already organized (indexed) in such a manner that we can jump straight to the records where we are most likely to match our request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this in place, a request for all points within hundreds or thousands of kilometers of another point returns us our result set in less than five milliseconds! Though this measurement is taken from a reduced data set, even a larger data set will still perform quite admirably when properly indexed. This is a relatively simple example of the utility of PostGIS. The tool can also perform much more complex operations and keep indexes on spatial geometries. Given what I’ve seen from PostGIS in my limited time working with it, I will definitely be trying to take advantage of it on future projects.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Recently I was working on a personal project involving geographical data, and realized that I needed to do spatial calculations such as distance inside a certain radius. In previous times, I might have programmed a function in JavaScript to do the calculations directly in the backend of my application. But in recent years, I’ve been improving my awareness of how to structure applications and make the right decisions when it comes to assigning responsibilities and roles among the different portions of an application. In the old legend of the Handyman’s Invoice, the engineer explains that knowing where to place the fix is worth much more than the fix itself. With that in mind, wouldn’t it be great to do the geographical calculations directly at the database level?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jonah</title><link href="/blog/2021/10/jonah.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jonah" /><published>2021-10-16T12:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-10-16T12:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/10/jonah</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/10/jonah.html">&lt;p&gt;On Wednesdays, I’ve been trying to get through one section of the book of Jonah during my train ride home. Our church has Wednesday night Bible studies, but they aren’t very convenient for a family with small children who need to get to bed early in preparation for school the next day. Given that I’ve now finished the short story of Jonah, I’d like to share a few of my thoughts. I find it interesting to compare my life with that of a person like Jonah, living in ancient times and thus a different social or cultural environment. Despite the differences, he seems to have many of the same problems that modern peopel encounter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story of Jonah is well known as that of a man swalled by a big fish and spit out on the shore. This, of course, is because God sent Jonah on a mission. But how did he send him? Did Jonah hear a voice. For those of us who wish things were a little more concrete, the missing details of the form of communication between Jonah and God throughout the story are frustrating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, the idea of the ancient city of Nineveh interests me. I like geography, and I like history, so the workings of an ancient city seems quite interesting. In fact, Nineveh was probably the most populous city in the world at the time of Jonah’s visit, and Jonah may have in fact visited Nineveh as well as a few surrounding sites. Whatever the geography, God’s interest in Nineveh shows the importance of urban ministry in its ability to reach out to many people in a single location. Without the ministry, the city degenerates into what Nineveh was before Jonah, but by the same means, Jonah’s message spreads throughout the city and even reaches the Assyrian king, Nineveh being the seat of his empire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the most astonishing thing for me as a modern reader is to consider that the city accepted Jonah’s message and repented. This is incomprehensible in a modern setting. Can we imagine going to Moscow and having the city take a message from God seriously, and initiate a city-wide repentance movement. Or Beijing, or Paris, or New York? It’s unthinkable in a modern context in which such a message would be laughed off, treated as some sort of scam, or more likely simply drowned out by crowds wearing their headphones on their commutes and going about their daily lives, uninterested in the dealings on any particular street corner or the city square.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally, Jonah’s reason for avoiding the city is the most surprising to me personally. If it were me, I would be avoiding the trip to Nineveh because I don’t like public speaking, especially unscheduled appearances on the street to random passers-by. Jonah’s message isn’t exactly a cheerful one, so it would make sense for him to want to avoid the wrath of the Ninehvites. But no, Jonah tells God that he wanted to avoid Nineveh in order to avoid God pouring His compassion out on the city, presumably because Jonahs feels the Ninehvites are undeserving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jonah’s mindset is therefore not aligned completely with God’s values, and the story ends with God posing the question to Jonah, “Are you right to be angry?”, referring to an analogy which God makes between a shade plant and the city of Nineveh. I’m not sure that the analogy makes sense from Jonah’s perspective, given that Jonah is a human comparing himself to the Ninehvites, but the book nonetheless ends there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no continuation to show us the end of Jonah’s life, and I often wonder what kind of man Jonah was in general. Did he have a family? What was his main occupation? He surely must have had quite a reputation after having preached to the entire city of Nineveh, and he was in fact referenced by Jesus in the New Testament.. His father was apparently named Amittai. A site that was possibly his gravesite was attacked by ISIS in 2014. Despite the open-ended ending, I like the simple and short story, and the fact that there is a lot to consider.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">On Wednesdays, I’ve been trying to get through one section of the book of Jonah during my train ride home. Our church has Wednesday night Bible studies, but they aren’t very convenient for a family with small children who need to get to bed early in preparation for school the next day. Given that I’ve now finished the short story of Jonah, I’d like to share a few of my thoughts. I find it interesting to compare my life with that of a person like Jonah, living in ancient times and thus a different social or cultural environment. Despite the differences, he seems to have many of the same problems that modern peopel encounter.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Stellaris</title><link href="/blog/2021/10/stellaris.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stellaris" /><published>2021-10-09T12:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-10-09T12:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/10/stellaris</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/10/stellaris.html">&lt;p&gt;Given how much I’ve played this game in recent months, it’s only fair that I spend some time talking about my interest in one of Paradox Interactive’s games. My interest in Paradox came when I started playing Europa Universalis 4, a game which really deserves its own post. That is probably Paradox’s most well-known and successful game, and thoug I knew that they had done other games such as Crusader Kings, I never jumped at the chance to play any of their other games. That changed recently when I found a bundle on the wonderful site Humble Bundle to buy Stellaris and some extra content for a low price. I decided to take the offer, and I haven’t regretted it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the games that I enjoy are strategy games. Games in which I can control some territory and build a civilization are always fun. Most of the games that I had played in this genre focused on ancient times: Age of Empires, Civilization (which I find more fun in the early stages), and Europa Universalis, which is not ancient but certainly medieval. I had some interest in trying the same context in a futuristic setting, which led me to buy Master of Orion years ago. That was an interesting game, though flaxed. Stellaris far surpasses it, and really meets my expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much more than just Europa Universalis in space, Stellaris has a all the basic elements of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/4X&quot;&gt;4X game&lt;/a&gt;, but with some story elements as well. As the game progresses, events occur which can shape the outlook of your civilization, and there is a lot of good science fiction writing that makes the archeological finds and scientific discoveries interesting. To me, this is the mark of a good space game. Because the game is in the future, naturally it is fiction, and being in space, it’s science fiction, which is a difficult genre for which to write a story. The events have to be beyond the current experiences of humanity, but also believable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the ways that Stellaris stays interesting is by simply having so many dimensions. Other games that I know in this genre have types of planets and different civilizations, each with specific characteristics. Stellaris has that, but also has more sophisticated systems for planet, resource, and population management. The exploration and discovery process is a little more detailed, and there are simply more types of non-playable entities in the galaxy, with fallen empires, merchant groups, hostile drones, and more all being not unimportant pieces of the galactic picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technological tree is vast, and there are ways to play the game “tall” instead of just “wide”, meaning that there are viable strategies to sticking to a small piece of territory and not expanding. This is an important subject for any 4X game, as most fail to come up with alternatives to the typical strategy of expanding infinitely in order to control more resources. That is still one possibility in Stellaris, but the player can also stick to the few planets surrounding the homeworld, and vastly increase the population on these planets, all while remaining competitive with those empires covering many more systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would definitely recommend Stellaris to anyone interested in this genre, who also enjoys science fiction. If the futuristic aspect is not important, there are already many other games that do exploration and civilization-building quite well. Concerning Stellaris, I haven’t seen any game that has accomplished as much in an engaging futuristic science fiction galaxy while retaining everything great about the empire-building games that I have come to enjoy the most.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Given how much I’ve played this game in recent months, it’s only fair that I spend some time talking about my interest in one of Paradox Interactive’s games. My interest in Paradox came when I started playing Europa Universalis 4, a game which really deserves its own post. That is probably Paradox’s most well-known and successful game, and thoug I knew that they had done other games such as Crusader Kings, I never jumped at the chance to play any of their other games. That changed recently when I found a bundle on the wonderful site Humble Bundle to buy Stellaris and some extra content for a low price. I decided to take the offer, and I haven’t regretted it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Back to School</title><link href="/blog/2021/10/back-to-school.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Back to School" /><published>2021-10-02T12:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-10-02T12:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/10/back-to-school</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/10/back-to-school.html">&lt;p&gt;With all of the other topics that I wanted to share, I haven’t yet had a chance to write about the start of a new school year. As parents, the apprehension of our children to going to school is balanced directly by our joy in sending them. This year is the big year for us, as not only is our daughter Miriam starting CP (Cours préparatoire), which is the first year of elementary school, but we also are sending our son Daniel to Petite Section for his first year of preschool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the moment that we have been waiting for, for about a year. During this time Daniel has been constantly asking when he can go to school like his big sister. Well, that day has finally come. As a parent I had been steeling myself for that first day, knowing that no matter how excited Daniel seemed to be to go to school, he would feel differently when he actually got there. Somehow, on the way to school I allowed myself to believe that maybe things would be different with Daniel, and he would be happy to be at school for the first time. Sadly, I was wrong in my thinking, and Daniel cried, just like most children, as he realized that being at school means being separated from his parents, and meeting new people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then, however, things have progressed rapidly. Given that this is our second go-round, we have been doing our best to prepare Daniel for school by getting him to watch videos in French, speaking to him in French occasionally, and of course getting him to play with Miriam and her friends, who speak French together. This is a big improvement on our preparations for Miriam’s first day at school three years ago, when she entered the classroom for the first time with minimal French language skills. This, and the difference in personality, may have contributed to Daniel’s quite acclimatization to the school environment. After just one month, Daniel now walks into the classroom on his own accord, without pouting or whining. As a parent, it is a huge relief to be able to get the children to school without a lot of whining, and without having to spend energy hyping the kids up for school, or trying to distract them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, given that both children are now in school, my wife Alex is finally free for most of the day, to do what she wants to do. This is a much-deserved break after six years of raising children all day, every day. She finally can do the things that can’t be done with kids, like simply going for a run, or do things which would be much more difficult with children, like going into Paris.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daniel is not the only one undergoing a big change. Miriam’s schooling is more serious than before, and as she learns to read and write French in school, we are doing our best to complement that with English and Chinese learning at home. Meanwhile, we’ve also picked out one extracurricular activity, gymnastics, for her to do on Wednesdays, when there is no school, as well as on Friday evenings. It feels good to see her doing something she enjoys with other kids, and we are so lucky to live a few minutes’ walk from the practice gym.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a father, it’s important to be leading our familiy to grow in a smooth and constant manner, and this Back to School season definitely feels like that. With both kids now in school, I can see our family transitioning into a new phase, and it’s a wonderful thing.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">With all of the other topics that I wanted to share, I haven’t yet had a chance to write about the start of a new school year. As parents, the apprehension of our children to going to school is balanced directly by our joy in sending them. This year is the big year for us, as not only is our daughter Miriam starting CP (Cours préparatoire), which is the first year of elementary school, but we also are sending our son Daniel to Petite Section for his first year of preschool.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What I’m Watching: Justin Barbour</title><link href="/blog/2021/09/watching-justin-barbour.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What I'm Watching: Justin Barbour" /><published>2021-09-25T12:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-09-25T12:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/09/watching-justin-barbour</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/09/watching-justin-barbour.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s not often for me to find a series of adventures that really captures my attention these days, as many of the popular trips we find on the internet are road trips or rather mundane adventures that never enter into truly remote territory. Recently, while playing around on Google Maps, I was thinking how it would be interesting to attempt to cross the enormous peninsula formed by Northern Québec and Labrador by kayak or canoe, thus connecting the Hudson Bay and the Atlantic Ocean. By map, we can see roughly that there are rivers which descend in both direction from the large lakes in the center of this area, and thus it should be possibile. It was thus with glee that I found that Justin Barbour had already set out on this exact adventure and had put together a compelling series of videos covering his trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that I like about Justin is that he labels himself “Newfoundland Explorer”, advertising his roots in the wild Canadian province of Newfoundland and Labrador. I finished my ECT hike in Newfoundland and got a glimpse of Labrador across the Gulf of Saint Lawrence. I loved the wild feeling of emptiness and the raw beauty of that land, and was always interested to see more of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Justin and his trusty sidekick Saku the dog have done several adventures in Newfoundland and Labrador. Besides the aforementioned undertaking to take a canoe up the Red Wine River from Labrador and then make it all the way to Kuujjuarapik on the shores of the Hudson Bay, he also trekked by foot and packraft across Southern Newfoundland, and just recently put out trailers for a new series in Newfoundland’s Northern Peninsula. Justin travels by a variety of methods in his various adventures, most often by foot and canoe, though he often has to adapt these means to the conditions, such as snowshoeing or pulling a sled in winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nature of the content that he puts out makes Justin Barbour an adventurer slightly different from others that I have watched in the past. Usually, I’m interested in a series in which we cover a sizeable distance each day and during the entire trip, but several of the adventures that Justin does are in more of a wilderness survival style, in which there is a defined goal and route to achieve that, but each day he takes time to fish, take care of Saku, and enjoy the land at a slower pace than a simple dash to the finish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps more enjoyable is Justin’s attitude throughout his time in the wild. He never appears stressed or anxious, instead choosing to tackle imposing challenges with an eager attitude. The trip across Labrador struck me as a particularly tiring adventure, as Justin dragged his canoe upriver for weeks on end. Having conquered the mental aspect of life out in the wild, Justin can really enjoy the wilderness and make the viewer feel that they are on a simple camping trip, briefly forgetting that the surroundings are completely uninhabited and rarely visited by people, and that Justin is often far from any town or person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This enjoyable difference in Justin’s attitude is what makes his camping-style videos so enjoyable. Whereas most camping doesn’t interest me, seeing Justin and Saku camping out on a North Atlantic island for a long period is actually one of the more interesting video series, because of the atmosphere. These types of videos make survival camping seem convivial, as Justin takes care of his daily business out in the bush with a smile. I’m looking forward to seeing more from Justin Barbour and Saku, as they inevitably become more popular and take on grander adventures.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">It’s not often for me to find a series of adventures that really captures my attention these days, as many of the popular trips we find on the internet are road trips or rather mundane adventures that never enter into truly remote territory. Recently, while playing around on Google Maps, I was thinking how it would be interesting to attempt to cross the enormous peninsula formed by Northern Québec and Labrador by kayak or canoe, thus connecting the Hudson Bay and the Atlantic Ocean. By map, we can see roughly that there are rivers which descend in both direction from the large lakes in the center of this area, and thus it should be possibile. It was thus with glee that I found that Justin Barbour had already set out on this exact adventure and had put together a compelling series of videos covering his trip.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Wonderful Wedding</title><link href="/blog/2021/09/wonderful-wedding.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Wonderful Wedding" /><published>2021-09-18T12:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-09-18T12:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/09/wonderful-wedding</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/09/wonderful-wedding.html">&lt;p&gt;The big event this summer was the August wedding ceremony for my brother Kevin, and his fiancée Emma. Kevin and Emma had met years before, but hadn’t started dating until later on. Very soon after the engagement, plans were made to have the wedding sooner rather than later. Having had a short engagement period myself, I admired the willingness to commit to marriage once the decision was made. We had our tickets to fly to the United States (along with Kevin, who came to do Mont Blanc), and were excited to be witness to this great event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, we weren’t merely witnesses. Kevin had already honored me by asking me to be the Best Man at his wedding, and I had been working on my speech, though it wasn’t finished yet. Our daughter Miriam was the flower girl, and our son Daniel was the ring bearer. Not only that, but Kevin and Emma had recently bought a house, and offered to let us stay there in the week prior to the wedding. We found their house to be wonderful, with an all-new interior and a big back yard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, we got to spend time with Emma, something we had only done via video chat in the months prior to the wedding. Even over video, we loved Emma and couldn’t wait to meet her, and that feeling was confirmed when we met in person. It was a shame that Emma had to work in the days leading up to the wedding, and of course had much to do to prepare for the big day. Thankfully, we’ll have plenty of time to spend with her and Kevin in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our part, we helped as much as we could with the physical preparations. My wife did a lot of cleaning and preparations in the house. I made myself busy setting up the tents which formed the corridor and space for the meal after the ceremony. The day of the reception, we found that Kevin’s car would not start, so I set about investigating and eventually replacing the battery. We were happy to be of some help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our children got their fair share of playtime with their grandparents. They went out to a few small parks with playgrounds, they rode a pair of bicycles which my mother thoughtfully brought down from Virginia, and my brother and I took them to a nice splashpad run by the city for a small price. It was quite hot during our stay, and perfect for the splashpad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reception was nice, as we got to meet many of Kevin’s friends and Emma’s sisters and parents. We had a nice meal and got to listen to some great toasts. My own toast as Best Man had been postponed until after the wedding due to scheduling difficulties with one of the groomsmen, who happened to be our old soccer coach from high school, and his difficulties in getting down to South Carolina for the reception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day, Kevin and I met up with other groomsmen for a round of disc golf. Kevin was the best, having practiced quite a lot, but we all had fun. I managed a couple of good shots and even a long putt or two (for me), and then we had lunch and got ready for the wedding. Kevin had graciously paid for our outfits, which were nice shirts, pants, vests, and bowties. Coach Verbrugge tied all the bowties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ceremony was beautiful. Miriam and Daniel performed their parts beautifully. It was a great feeling to be standing right next to my brother as he got married, and to have our families there as well. With the vows and rings exchanged, Kevin and Emma enjoyed a triumphant kiss and we all filed back to the house for drinks and snacks befor the final meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That evening we ate, and we got to listen to the rest of the toasts. I had worked a lot on mine, and was proud to give Kevin and Emma a memorable toast for their big day. As the evening wound down with dancing, we congratulated Kevin and Emma again as they left for a honeymoon in Iceland. For our part, we were so happy to have been there to witness their love for each other, and the beginning of a beautiful life together.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">The big event this summer was the August wedding ceremony for my brother Kevin, and his fiancée Emma. Kevin and Emma had met years before, but hadn’t started dating until later on. Very soon after the engagement, plans were made to have the wedding sooner rather than later. Having had a short engagement period myself, I admired the willingness to commit to marriage once the decision was made. We had our tickets to fly to the United States (along with Kevin, who came to do Mont Blanc), and were excited to be witness to this great event.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">9/11: 20 Years Later</title><link href="/blog/2021/09/9-11-20-years-later.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="9/11: 20 Years Later" /><published>2021-09-11T12:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-09-11T12:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/09/9-11-20-years-later</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/09/9-11-20-years-later.html">&lt;p&gt;Like most people who can remember September 11, 2001, I remember first and foremost where I was when the news broke. I was in middle school at The Covenant School, a great private Christian school in Charlottesville, Virginia. The school was finishing up a brand new campus that we would later move to for the rest of my middle and high school years, but at that time, I had just started seventh grade, which was the year I changed from the Lower School to the Upper School. The Upper School was at the old McIntire High School building, an old building with the old-style radiators, old-style lockers, and lots of other old things. I had done my Kindergarten year in that building before the Lower School was moved to the Mountainwood facility, which was previously some sort of healthcare or recovery facility. Nevertheless, the move back to the McIntire building was a complete change of style, and I was still getting used to it in mid-September.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were in chapel, a weekly timeslot on Tuesdays, when the school gathered in the gymnasium to worship. The worship was interrupted by the headmaster of the school, who made the announcement of the terrorist attack. As a seventh grader, I understood that the situation was serious, but I couldn’t really place the event in the timeline of world events, or predict the events that would follow. One girl in our class left the room in tears, as her father was a pilot who had flown to New York that morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the rest of the school day, most of our classes consisted of watching the news, talking about events with our teachers. I specifically remember the math teacher attempting to go through the lesson, but stopping soon, presumably because she was too distracted. I don’t remember too many other specific moments related to the tragedy. I remember the local paper, The Daily Progress, put out a special issue, which I had never seen before. For a seventh grader, life went on without too many changes. I was excited about my Game Boy Advance and the soon-to-be-released GameCube. I still went to soccer practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s now 2021. Twenty years have passed, and America has gone into and out of Afghanistand and Iraq. The orchestrator of the attacks has long since been found and killed, and the world has moved on to deal with a series of other similar, although smaller, attacks and attempts to terrorize. In my mind, the most impactful effects inside the United States was the passage of the Patriot Act and other similar measures, all designed to increase security and protect against threats by increasing surveillance powers. Outside the USA, the most obvious impacts were the conflicts in Afghanistan and Iraq. For me personally, the effect of the attacks has not been too dire. Mostly, it’s just an inconvenience to be in an atmosphere of increased security. There are more hoops to jump through to get things done. I can’t bring a laptop into the American Embassy in Paris, I have to deposit it at a hotel around the block. Every country has stepped up security to some extent, and most countries have followed America’s example of increased surveillance and reduced privacy rights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the abscence of serious personal links to the attacks, I look at the bigger picture. Perhaps the biggest effect on me is simply being an American. Everyone has an opinion on the wars in Afghanistan and Iraq, and some people like to tell me their opinion when they find out that I’m American. Only America’s closest allies followed its lead in responding to the terrorist threats to the extent that the United States had hoped for, and thus relations have not improved between the USA and most of Europe. In a sense, the effects of the attack have been long-lasting on the global scale, as America is only just now scaling back its involvement in the world, a process which it could have started much earlier, instead of attempting various endeavors in the Middle East which have largely not been supported by the rest of the developed world, or the nations of the Middle East.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, September 11 was a terrible tragedy, but one that was very likely to happen (although not necessarily on that scale) as globalization increased and the difference between the United States and the rest of the world became more evident. There was always going to be a conflict eventually, and the United States was very likely to respond. As a seventh grader, the attacks didn’t have a big effect on me personally, mostly because of the United States’ power to project force across the globe, and because of its strong economic, political, and governmental structures in place, which were able to respond to the attacks without seriously interrupting life for its citizens (despite increased surveillance). Mostly, 9/11 is an event to commemorate, a date to reflect on, but one on which we reflect on from a position of comfort and security.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Like most people who can remember September 11, 2001, I remember first and foremost where I was when the news broke. I was in middle school at The Covenant School, a great private Christian school in Charlottesville, Virginia. The school was finishing up a brand new campus that we would later move to for the rest of my middle and high school years, but at that time, I had just started seventh grade, which was the year I changed from the Lower School to the Upper School. The Upper School was at the old McIntire High School building, an old building with the old-style radiators, old-style lockers, and lots of other old things. I had done my Kindergarten year in that building before the Lower School was moved to the Mountainwood facility, which was previously some sort of healthcare or recovery facility. Nevertheless, the move back to the McIntire building was a complete change of style, and I was still getting used to it in mid-September.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Success on Mont Blanc: Part 3</title><link href="/blog/2021/09/success-mont-blanc-part-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Success on Mont Blanc: Part 3" /><published>2021-09-04T12:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-09-04T12:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/09/success-mont-blanc-part-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/09/success-mont-blanc-part-3.html">&lt;p&gt;In the very early hours of the morning, everyone else in the hut got up and started their ascent to the summit. I woke up later and noticed that the wind was howling outside. Refuge Goûter sits on the edge of a cliff, which makes for an incredible view, albeit in high winds. When Kevin woke up, he noticed the same thing, and we were both happy that we hadn’t attempted a summit in those conditions. Kevin was already feeling very sore, and a summit attempt at 3AM in high winds didn’t seem like a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got up and packed up my stuff. My brother got up a little later and got packed up. We both ate as much of our food as we could, as we wouldn’t need much on the descent. We finally got going around 9:30 AM, as the first people to summit that day were returning to the refuge. It was quite windy, and we were glad to be heading down, instead of being blasted on the snowy ridgelines of the upper mountain. I got our harnesses hooked up with a rope, and put everything else away in order to manage that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The descent from Goûter down to Tête Rousse was time consuming for us. We took extreme caution, and backed down most of the mountain. I used the rope to ensure that Kevin had an extra failsafe as he was still feeling sore, but he never ended up needing it. It is quite intimidating when you stare down the mountain for a distance and can barely see your destination far below. We tried not to do that, instead preferring to focus on just the next few steps, taking each problem on one at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that was a little odd for me, was that Kevin was consistently feeling a little cold on the trip, whereas I was the opposite. Even on the descent, where I wasn’t exerting myself, I immediately took off my coat and descended in just a long sleeve shirt and gloves. We encouraged each other and psyched ourselves up during the descent in order to stay sharp. The mental game was just as important as the physical aspect, which consisted just of finding the right spots for feet and hands to cling onto the mountain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon enough other groups passed us by, as they sped down the mountain. We were no longer phased by this. Our success on Mont Blanc was not determined by our speed, but by getting all the way up to Refuge Goûter with no guide and no prior mountaineering experience, and getting down the mountain safely while slightly injured, all without needing a rescue operation. We kept descending, and eventually Tête Rousse stopped being a dot in the distance, and it grew quite close. There started to be more sections which we could walk normally, without backing down the mountain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made it to Tête Rousse, and took a brief break after taking off our crampons and stowing the harnesses and rope. We were pretty much safe. The descent from there down to the Eagle’s Nest and the tramway took a long time, and I finished off a fantastic sunburn, but they were not dangerous. We took our time as my brother’s injuries were starting to aggravate him, but we did make it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally back in town, we managed to offload our gear and make it to the hotel. I could finally exhale and feel good about getting off the mountain safely. It’s true that we didn’t summit, and that is a real shame. If I had thought that there was any way to do it safely and get back down the mountain, I would have gone for it. The reality is, we made the right decision, even though it hurt. As it happens, we took so long to get down the mountain, that even leaving at 9:30 AM, we didn’t exit the rental shop until 7 PM. We would have never made it to the summit and all the way back down. I call our trip a success from an amateur’s perspective. There were very few other groups attempting the mountain without a guide, and those that were, seemed to have more experience, and certainly had lighter packs than us. We did the best we could, and we came home safe, sound, and on time for my brother Kevin’s wedding. But that is a whole ‘nother story!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">In the very early hours of the morning, everyone else in the hut got up and started their ascent to the summit. I woke up later and noticed that the wind was howling outside. Refuge Goûter sits on the edge of a cliff, which makes for an incredible view, albeit in high winds. When Kevin woke up, he noticed the same thing, and we were both happy that we hadn’t attempted a summit in those conditions. Kevin was already feeling very sore, and a summit attempt at 3AM in high winds didn’t seem like a good idea.</summary></entry></feed>