<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-12-21T22:18:26+01:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Sterling Coleman</title><subtitle>A space for my personal projects and thoughts</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Making Christmas Traditions</title><link href="/blog/2020/12/making-christmas-traditions.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Making Christmas Traditions" /><published>2020-12-20T21:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-20T21:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/12/making-christmas-traditions</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/12/making-christmas-traditions.html">&lt;p&gt;France and America have some big differences when it comes to the Christmas season. The one I think of in November is that there is no Thanksgiving holiday to provide a buffer between Halloween and Christmas. Though the French don’t typically start singing their Christmas carols in early November, they also don’t have any reason to wait until December to put up their Christmas decorations and encourage the holiday shopping season to start. So for us, the Christmas season has been building up for a while. But now, with just a few more days until Christmas Day, it really does feel like Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we are doing a smaller Christmas at home this year, just the four of us, my wife pointed out the importance of making Christmas special. I’m very happy that she wants to make this Christmas special, as Christmas is not really a big celebration back in China, so I wasn’t raelly expecting her to go all out. But she pointed out that it is important for our children to have good memories of Christmas, and for us to make Christmas special with some traditions just for us. I think that she also wants to make Christmas an enjoyable time for me, and has already proposed a big turkey dinner, with lots of stuff to eat on the side. Though I will probably need to prepare my holidays sweatpants for the aftermath, I am grateful to have a wife who is willing to put a lot of effort into making this holiday special for all of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have contributed a bit as well by bringing a Christmas tree back from our local grocery store parking lot. This is not as small a thing as it may seem since I had to bring it back on the bicycle trailer. The trees become available at the beginning of December, and though I try to wait awhile before getting ours, I’m always concerned about being left with few good options, as there is a limited selection and some are much more expensive than others. So I got the tree almost three weeks before Christmas, and it has been shedding pine needles in the corner of our living room ever since. Well, ever since I cut the top foot off of it, because I can never remember how tall our living room ceiling is when I’m buying Christmas trees, and I figure that bigger is better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And underneath our tree, the presents have been steadily multiplying. It seems that every year, I think that we’ll just have a few gifts to give out and that will be fine. After all, our children are young and we don’t need a lot of gifts to enjoy the holidays. And every year, a few gifts quickly turns into enough to fill up all the space underneath the tree. We start out with a few things that we picked up, usually toys for the kids. Pretty soon, we start getting packages in the mail every other day, and if the gifts aren’t labeled, we have a hard time keeping track of which is from whom, as we have so many. We’re blessed to have family that takes the extra effort to send gifts from overseas. That takes more time and planning, and is more of an expense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t got a concrete plan for starting a big events, but the great thing is that we are all together for the next week. School is out for two full weeks, and I’m off work for one full week. That leaves us plenty of time to hang out together and enjoy the season. We may not have a White Christmas, but on most days we have a wonderful fire going in our fireplace. My wife spent a little extra to put some basic ornaments on the tree, and of course our daughter Miriam never gets tired of making drawings to decorate the tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great traditions are often just activities that come naturally, like playing games in the house with the kids. The big planned outings and events are fun too, but they kind of are expected to be. The memories that I enjoy the most are the unexpected joys of laughing and spending time with family members, often doing nothing more than talking. Those are the types of memories that we will hopefully be making as we spend time together this Christmas, just the four of us.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">France and America have some big differences when it comes to the Christmas season. The one I think of in November is that there is no Thanksgiving holiday to provide a buffer between Halloween and Christmas. Though the French don’t typically start singing their Christmas carols in early November, they also don’t have any reason to wait until December to put up their Christmas decorations and encourage the holiday shopping season to start. So for us, the Christmas season has been building up for a while. But now, with just a few more days until Christmas Day, it really does feel like Christmas.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Frostpunk</title><link href="/blog/2020/12/frostpunk.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Frostpunk" /><published>2020-12-13T09:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-13T09:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/12/frostpunk</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/12/frostpunk.html">&lt;p&gt;I’m a little hesitant to spend time talking about a video game, but I think that given how much time I have spent playing this game recently, and the amount of time I have spent thinking about the game, it is only right that I dedicate a post to the game. The game of which I am speaking is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frostpunkgame.com/&quot;&gt;Frostpunk&lt;/a&gt;, a strategy game released in 2018 by developer &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.11bitstudios.com/&quot;&gt;11-bit studios&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frostpunk is a strategy game and a city-building game. There are already many games in this genre, and I have played some very good city-building games over the years. What drew me to this game was that it is a very different style than most city-building games. In fact, in some ways it could be classified as a survival game. In Frostpunk, the player must build a city which can survive in a frozen wasteland which becomes gradually colder over time.  As the temperature falls, the citizens of the city need to continue to stay warm at home and at work, in addition to being able to eat. In order to make that happen, resources needed to be gathered, research must be done, buildings must be built, and choices must be made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have really been enjoying this game, but that is not a surprise since I enjoy most strategy games. Strategy games give me the ability to be in control of something with a global view of the situation, instead of simply controlling one character. These games also don’t typically require expensive gaming computers, which is convenient. What’s fun about strategy games for me is being the one in charge, and making every decision. In such a position, I can put my own personal touch on new buildings and the city. I can organize the city in the way that I like. For example, in a typical city-building game, I can create a nice grid layout which satisfies me, organized by type of building. Oddly enough, organizing things is a big part of the fun for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frostpunk is different. First of all, it is set during the the late nineteenth century, in a fictional setting in which extreme climate events have entered the Earth into a period of extreme cold. There are no modern technologies, and the city-building doesn’t involve setting up a university or subway system. Next, the city is organized around a generator, in a circular shape, instead of the typical grid. That alone is a big change. Streets still need to be created, but they are simple wooden walkways. Like many strategy games, resources need to be collected, but in this scenario coal must be collected for heat, wood and steel for construction and research, and finally food to keep people alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frostpunk also mixes in exploration, by demanding the player to organize scouts to go out beyond the city and find resources or other survivors and even cities. These become a big part of the strategy as well as the story as scouts discover what is happening outside the city. Ultimately the main differene between Frostpunk and a normal city-building game is that it uses the increasing cold as the factor which drives the story and game forward. The temperature must decrease in order to continually challenge the player to keep all citizens alive and in good health, while also advancing on other frontiers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, strategy games like Frostpunk aren’t just an enjoyable way to spend time. At its most basic level, the game is a game of resource management. The player starts out with nothing but some people, and based on how the player uses their citizens’ time, the player either succeeds or fails. The order in which things are done is very important. Often, a short-term goal must be reached in order to survive, but long-term goals must also be balanced in order to be prepared for future challenges, such as a further drop in temperature, or a need for an increase in the production of a certain resource, or the need for a certain advanced type of research to be completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the same type of thinking which we employ in real life. We have short term goals, but we also have long term plans, and we have to keep those in mind as well. Based on what I’ve learned from games such as Frostpunk, I usally prioritize long-term plans, and I rarely go for the easier option which requires less effort or resources. At work, it’s important to immediately realize a new feature or fix a bug immediately, but I also highly value moving towards long-term goals such as fixes the global architecture of the application, or implementing some best practice. Achieving the long-term goals makes the short-term issues easier to resolve. Ideally all short-term goals would fit into the long-term picture, but sometimes in life, as in Frostpunk, that isn’t the case.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">I’m a little hesitant to spend time talking about a video game, but I think that given how much time I have spent playing this game recently, and the amount of time I have spent thinking about the game, it is only right that I dedicate a post to the game. The game of which I am speaking is Frostpunk, a strategy game released in 2018 by developer 11-bit studios.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What I’m Watching: Jomboy</title><link href="/blog/2020/12/watching-jomboy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What I'm Watching: Jomboy" /><published>2020-12-06T20:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-06T20:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/12/watching-jomboy</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/12/watching-jomboy.html">&lt;p&gt;Sometime during the baseball season I stumbled upon a YouTube channel called Jomboy Media. Jomboy has a fantastic channel, with many videos of just a few minutes, called “breakdowns”. Each one focuses on a single part of a game, usually a baseball game, and makes it entertaining. That in itself is a huge achievement considering that I am not a big of fan baseball, would never watch a full baseball game, and would not of my own volition seek to understand all the nuances of the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is interesting to me is that this channel has actually made me more interested in baseball than I was before, which, as stated, is no small feat. No major sports media outlet has ever interested me in how a pitcher may be tipping his pitches, or how players on different baseball teams react to one another. What sets Jomboy Media apart is that it brings me as the viewer into the baseball world and makes it more personal and human. The main way this is done is through very good lip-reading and second-by-second narration of what the players in the video are saying and thinking. Did I mention that it is done in a very humorous way? The point of the video is to entertain, but in doing so, some videos inevitable educate the viewer on the mentality of the players, the unknown rules of the game, and the minute details that I would never have picked up on if I were watching a typicall broadcast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, Jomboy doesn’t just cover baseball. The most popular video to date is a commentary on the 2012 Inuit Ear Pulling championship. If it sounds silly, just watch the video while listening to Jomboy (Jimmy O’Brien) do the commentary. Between that, Finnish Baseball, Teqball, and many other unusual sports, there is a lot of good material for Jomboy’s entertaining commentary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the channel isn’t just cheap entertainment. Jomboy was actually on the leading edge of the cheating scandal from the Houston Astros 2017 season. Just hours after The Athletic posted details of the subject for the first time, Jomboy Media had a video up breaking down exactly how the Astros were making noise in the dugout to signal certain pitches to the batter, and that the information gained at that speed could never have been done without using a camera. The breakdown format is hilarious when dubbing over a player’s thoughts in an already-entertaining situation, and it is also informative for investigating details. It’s clearly a format that is working well for Jomboy, and one that shows how online sports content is very much different than traditional cable television sports coverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Online, as a viewer I am much faster to change pages or videos, meaning that the videos of just a few minutes are perfect. I don’t really need a former player or experienced television presenter to narrate everything to me. Certainly, inside knowledge of the sport is needed for the more in-depth breakdowns, which is where Jomboy shows that he knows his stuff. I don’t want to wait until the end of the season for a well-compiled Top 10 list. I might just be interested to see something unusual that happened yesterday for a minute or two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I think that it’s better to get the information from an intelligent sports fan that to get it from a sports celebrity. When watching Jomboy, it feels like a friend is sharing something funny and interesting with me, and I don’t spend a lot of time thinking about the narrator. By comparison, I think too many of the modern commentators and personaltiies found on television seem to be injecting themselves as a type of character into the story. They do this with funny voices or fake outrage, but I would prefer to just be entertained by the sports rather than a sideshow. Jomboy’s entertainment comes directly from the baseball action itself, which (again), is quite impressive considering just how unentertaining I normally find baseball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think my interest in Jomboy’s channel and my continual visits to see what new breakdowns have been published shows an alternative to traditional television sports journalism. Whether or not that ends up being ultimately beneficial for sports business or players, or even viewers, remains to be seen. At the very least, I can affirm that Jomboy’s channel is highly entertaining, and has shed new light on baseball for me.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Sometime during the baseball season I stumbled upon a YouTube channel called Jomboy Media. Jomboy has a fantastic channel, with many videos of just a few minutes, called “breakdowns”. Each one focuses on a single part of a game, usually a baseball game, and makes it entertaining. That in itself is a huge achievement considering that I am not a big of fan baseball, would never watch a full baseball game, and would not of my own volition seek to understand all the nuances of the game.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Thanksgiving Abroad</title><link href="/blog/2020/11/thanksgiving-abroad.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thanksgiving Abroad" /><published>2020-11-29T19:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-11-29T19:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/11/thanksgiving-abroad</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/11/thanksgiving-abroad.html">&lt;p&gt;This week we celebrated Thanksgiving at our house. I feel confident in saying that we were the only participants in Thanksgiving festivities in our neighborhood, since I am the only American. We’ve done this for a couple of years, and were lucky enough to share Thanksgiving with another American family two years ago. The nature of life abroad is that holidays happen differently. And while for many aspects of living abroad, there are tricks we can use or different ways of seeing things, when it comes to holidays I find that there is no secret way to make an American holiday feel like it would back home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in America, on Thanksgiving Day I would be with my immediate family, eating a ridiculously large meal. Afterwards we would hobble to the couch and watch some Thanksgiving Day football. Probably wearing sweatpants to accept my new rotund shape after Thanksgiving dinner, I would be enjoying a day or two in the holiday routine before heading back to work or school. It’s a privilege to have a place to go for Thanksgiving, and though at the time it can feel like a bit of a hassle to travel at the busiest time of the year, it definitely feels good to be back home for the holidays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, our home is in France now, and it’s not very convenient to fly back to the United States for a few days. So we do a little Thanksgiving meal at our house. This year, my wife cooked a big chicken quite well, substituting lime for lemon in a recipe that I have come to really enjoy. I must have eaten it four or five times this year, and it has always been great. This time was no exception, and it was enjoyable to have something special for the occasion. I also put on Charlie Brown for the children, as I think it’s fun to have a little tradition for the children, and I like Charlie Brown too. But other than those things, we didn’t have much of a Thanksgiving. I went to work, Miriam went to school, and life went on as it would on any other weekday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily I’m pretty much okay with that, but it definitely is one of the downsides of living abroad. You simply can’t have a full American Thanksgiving experience abroad. If we want to celebrate our own holidays, we have to make our own atmosphere. It’s something that we are working on, as we want our children to experience these things, and to have good memories of holidays like Thanksgiving. We want our children to know the meaning of the holidays that we grew up celebrating, as well as those new ones we celebrate alongside the French.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while having American holidays abroad is different, there is also a difference in the way that we experience French holidays. We didn’t grow up in France, so we don’t have childhood memories of celebrating important French holidays in a uniquely French way. When I’m off of work for a French holiday, often it’s just a simple day off of work for me. If the holiday is for a war memorial, then I might try and watch something related to the subject to think about the sacrifice or suffering related to the holdiay, but for many other holidays, I can’t have the same connection as someone who grew up here. In my defense, I’m not sure that all French people are fervently celebrating the Catholic holidays, such as Ascension or Assomption, so there may not be much for us to do for some of these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living in France has been a wonderful experience for us, as we get to present others with something they don’t usually see, and learn from them at the same time. Unfortunately we can’t simply take all of the good and none of the bad. We don’t get to spend every holidays with our families. My longsuffering wife is especially aware of this, as recent events have made travel back to China difficult for us, and even in the best of times Chinese New Year does not align perfectly with the French school calendar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We simply do the best we can, and are grateful for those times that we are back in the USA or China with our families, just like days of our childhoods. In the meantime, we try to get into the local French holidays and try new things. We may not have a lot of experience with Bastille Day, but we can celebrate anyway. We can also try some new things at Christmas, mixing what we already love with something new. In the process, perhaps we can share a little Thanksgiving in France.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">This week we celebrated Thanksgiving at our house. I feel confident in saying that we were the only participants in Thanksgiving festivities in our neighborhood, since I am the only American. We’ve done this for a couple of years, and were lucky enough to share Thanksgiving with another American family two years ago. The nature of life abroad is that holidays happen differently. And while for many aspects of living abroad, there are tricks we can use or different ways of seeing things, when it comes to holidays I find that there is no secret way to make an American holiday feel like it would back home.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Benefits of Language</title><link href="/blog/2020/11/language-benefits.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Benefits of Language" /><published>2020-11-21T14:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-11-21T14:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/11/language-benefits</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/11/language-benefits.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s inevitable that when people get to know us, pretty early on in the conversation, they find out that we speak three different languages. Well, really my wife and children speak three. I’m still working on my Chinese, and it’s usually on hold because of other priorities. But as I speak English natively, and my wife is a native Chinese speaker, our children grow up understanding and communicating in both of those languages. And of course, as we live in France, we use French at work, school, church, with our friends, and everywhere we have to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We chose French deliberately. When I met my wife, she was doing a Master’s program in Linguistics, specifically English and French. The obvious reason that she was studying these two languages is that they are global languages, spoken by a significant portion of the Earth’s population, and certainly hold political significance as well. That was the same basic reason that I was interested in Chinese and French as an American. Obviously one of these turned out to be a bit harder for me to learn than the other, but the fact remains that both are powerful languages. Our goals are simply to expand our horizons and experience different things. French opens up a lot more opportunities for us than other languages which have fewer speakers concentrated in weaker countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of good reasons for us to live in France: as a third country it’s “neutral” ground for our family, it could allow for citizenship opportunities with significant benefits in Europe, and it offers a new language for us and our children. More significantly, this new language offers new ways of thinking. The pattern of langauge and the way we use it affects the way we think and behave, to some extent. A simple example is the formal “vous”, as opposed to the informal “tu”. This separation, common in many languages, differs from the ambiguous English “you”. The effect that I see is that a French person behaves more distant from somebody that they don’t know, whereas an English speaker, especially an American, is usually comfortable making small talk with complete strangers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Immersion is the best way to learn a new language. Though it involves a lot of sacrifice to move somewhere new where you aren’t yet comfortable with the local language, there is a lot of value in seeing native speakers in their natural habitat. Language goes hand and hand with behavior and lifestyle. We can learn grammar in a classroom in a foreign country, but it makes more sense when we see people speaking, whispering, arguing, even sending emails and text messages in the language. At that point the practical use of the language becomes apparent, which drives the will to learn. After being immersed for a while, the culture and the language become enjoyable in some way. For example, I personally am not very outgoing, and don’t really look forward to making small talk with employees at a store, or other people in a places where I’m basically just looking to get something done and leave. French is good for that, because we stay at the formal level. We say “Bonjour” or “Bonsoir” and that little communication suffices. Back in the USA “Hi” often just leads into a comment about what I’m buying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every language has its pros and cons, but some appear more advantageous than others. Just the economic opportunities offered by English make it the most desirable language to know in my mind. A language like French offers a different way of thinking, not influenced too much by English (though that may be changing), an alternative in the modern Western world. To me, Chinese (Mandarin) shows how over time a language can become less practical. In the modern world, we are looking to become more flexible, and more able to quickly adapt to a changing environment. Mandarin grammar and Chinese characters, even Simplified Chinese characters, don’t exhibit that characteristic. When a new technology comes along, we have to construct a term from existing characters. A computer is “电脑”, literally “electric brain”. And while certainly it is practical to spend less on neon lighting for the sign reading “电脑” instead of “computer”, in the age of (ironically) computers, that advantage isn’t very impressive. We aren’t carving our writing into stone, or writing on precious scrolls. Often we aren’t even printing out our language at all, meaning that the savings on length is negligible. Instead, we have to memorize thousands of characters to have a good grasp of the language, and we have much less ability to deduce the meaning of a term compared to another language, where we derive words from other words. Our behavior becomes more focused on memorization than reasoning or creativity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever language we choose to learn, we should do so knowing it will open our eyes to different ways of communicating, not just in grammar but in behavior as well. If we can recognize that and accept that the ways we knew before might not always be the best ways, that is half the battle to growing as a person. A person who understand multiple languages is one who normally has more ways of thinking, more ways of solving or avoiding problems, of being creative, and of achieving their goals.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">It’s inevitable that when people get to know us, pretty early on in the conversation, they find out that we speak three different languages. Well, really my wife and children speak three. I’m still working on my Chinese, and it’s usually on hold because of other priorities. But as I speak English natively, and my wife is a native Chinese speaker, our children grow up understanding and communicating in both of those languages. And of course, as we live in France, we use French at work, school, church, with our friends, and everywhere we have to go.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Marathon Start Theory</title><link href="/blog/2020/11/marathon-start.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Marathon Start Theory" /><published>2020-11-15T21:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-11-15T21:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/11/marathon-start</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/11/marathon-start.html">&lt;p&gt;After finishing my thru-hike of the Eastern Continental Trail in 2012, I used that accomplishment as a springboard to take on other challenges. I feel that from that point on, the thru-hike became a point of reference for the way that I see the different challenges that I take on, and an analogy in many ways. When I began to examine the ways in which thru-hikers take on a challenging trail, or how people take on different kinds of challenges, I identified the very first phase of the challenge as the most important determining factor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important challenges that I see in my life are not short affairs, but rather efforts which take a long time to accomplish. Like marathons, they require endurance and planning. Raising children, paying off a mortgage, and managing a career are all examples of big tasks which take years to tackle. As such, they are more like marathons than sprints. Treating them like sprints often leads to burning out too quickly. My theory is that the beginning of all of these things is the most important, just as was the case for my hike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started my hike, I made mistakes. I misplaced my tarp and had to order a new one. I walked out of Key West without any food and had to subsist on Gatorage for a day. My feet began to hurt, I got a couple of blisters, and then the Big Cypress National Preserve ripped those off as I waded through its swamplands for two days. After two weeks of hardship, I soaked my feet in Epsom salt and they became as hard as rock. I had stealth-camped in the woods in the Florida Keys, waded past the Alligators in the Everglades, and there was much less to be concerned about from that point on. Those two weeks were the trial period that formed the foundation of my hike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really, I should have done a better job at taking care of myself. I shouldn’t have lost my tarp, and I should have left Key West with some food. The thing working in my favor was that hiking through the Florida Keys was quite forgiving. It was beautiful, it was flat, and the weather was great. Sure, the Seven Mile Bridge was a hardship, as was the hike out of the Keys up to Florida City and the subsequent hike through Big Cypress National Preserve, but ultimately the flat terrain and good weather were a big help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I were to give tips for thru-hikers on the Appalachian Trail, I would have to suggest starting the hike somewhere easier than Northern Georgia. Why not do the Pinhoti Trail in Alabama and Georgia, covering the smaller Southern Appalachians and leading into the more daunting Appalachian Trail? Starting the Appalachian Trail in Northern Georgia is like starting a marathon at the bottom of a big hill. Ultimately, it shouldn’t matter, as Northern Georgia is but a small portion of the trail, but it requires good planning and good discipline to stick with it through the ups and downs of the steep trail through the starting portion of the trail. The high dropout numbers on the Appalachian Trail might be less if those people were able to test their legs on the smaller hills in Alabama first. It’s bad enough finding out that your pack is too heavy, but it can end your hike to find that out when you are staring at a day full of big climbs straight up big mountains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m interested in Source-to-Sea descents of rivers, which follow the same pattern. The beginning of the river is the portion with small creeks which can only be navigated with something small like a packraft. There are rapids, more turns, and faster water. This faster water then becomes slower as the river widens. At a certain point, the journey is a simple endurance test to the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More importantly, the same pattern prevails in life. I consider one of the most important parts of my career to be making a good first impression and learning the ropes at any new job. I always want to soak up as much as I can in those first days and weeks to make everything go smoother later on. The well-known statement from the Book of Proverbs states “Start children off on the way they should go, and even when they are old they will not turn from it.” This acknowledges that the formation of a person’s character happens in childhood. The turbulent waters of difficult questions and worldviews are encountered in those years, and the way that a person rides those rapids determines what sort of path they will be on later in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a father, my goal is to not start a marathon on an uphill. We’ll tackle all those difficult things, but we’ll do so in an environment where mistakes aren’t fatal. I don’t try to start a new job by changing the fundamental way in which a company operates without a good understanding of the internal functions of the company. I have started my career by working hard to do things the right way despite the extra work that may entail in the short term, in the hope that this will pave the way for future success. As a hiker, I ensure success before the hike has even begun with good planning that diminishes the impact of mistakes I make out on the trail. I set the pace for the marathon on flat ground when I can, in order to be prepared for the mountains.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">After finishing my thru-hike of the Eastern Continental Trail in 2012, I used that accomplishment as a springboard to take on other challenges. I feel that from that point on, the thru-hike became a point of reference for the way that I see the different challenges that I take on, and an analogy in many ways. When I began to examine the ways in which thru-hikers take on a challenging trail, or how people take on different kinds of challenges, I identified the very first phase of the challenge as the most important determining factor.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Raking Leaves</title><link href="/blog/2020/11/raking-leaves.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Raking Leaves" /><published>2020-11-07T17:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-11-07T17:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/11/raking-leaves</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/11/raking-leaves.html">&lt;p&gt;Fall is a great time for me, second only to Spring. The heat of Summer is over and the weather remains good. All the delays and closures caused by most of the country being on vacation for the month of August are finished, and the world is back to normal. School starts back up, a new season of sports begins, and work is less hectic because people are actually there, meaning that we don’t have to prepare for the event of an emergency when all the people meant to handle such things are on vacation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the most iconic memory I have of Fall is our arrival in France back in 2014. We had great difficulties in getting our visas sorted out back in China, but had gotten the process done and had arrived in Paris at the beginning of September. We didn’t know where we could find a place to rent, or even how to get resident cards to access the transportation system without having to buy paper tickets every time. But on that first morning waking up in France, we were just happy to be there. We left our hotel in Suresnes and walked across the Seine to the East bank in the Bois de Boulogne, which is technically Paris. Holding hands walking along the river felt very different from our lives back in China. In that atmosphere, our senses were taking it all in, and it was the atmosphere of Fall that we were taking in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The physical beauty of the fall is what comes across the most to me. I’m a person very susceptible to nostalgia, and that’s what Fall is all about. While the heat of Summer subsides and all the plant life which exploded in Spring and Summer slowly fades away, I feel a sense of emotion related to the change. I like that feeling. The feeling that I am savoring something that won’t always be there. Seeing the leaves turning bright colors on the trees is easily the best part of Fall. Especially as the leaves of different trees change colors at different times, prolonging the experience and making for views of red and green trees side-by-side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I am raking up the leaves and acorns from the large oak tree in our backyard, I have time to reflect on the whole meaning of Fall. The season itself is evidence of the Creator. All of the systems which come together to make the leaves fall, to provide acorns for squirrels, to spread seeds for more trees, and to work with many other systems, amaze me. As someone who spends a lot of time trying to create things and fix things, I can appreciate anything that works well, and when I see the changing of the seasons, I see a design put into action and working well. There is intelligence in the design, but even more importantly, there is love. Fall didn’t have to be beautiful. The way that trees survive winter didn’t have be a visual delight in the way that it is. The beauty is evidence of the intent of the Designer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other reason that I am nostalgic in Fall is that it of course signals that another year is coming to an end. At the end of each year I look back at the year and think of all the things we have accomplished, all the ways that we have grown, and the challenges we have overcome. When Fall comes around, I start that process. It’s a time for us to do things for one last time before the year is over. I try to get our family outside before the weather turns too cold. At the beginning of Fall we have one last meal outside and agree that it’s time to fold up our outdoor table and put it away until next Spring. This year, I bought firewood to prepare for the end of Fall and the beginning of Winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The obvious downside of Fall for me is that it soon leads to Winter. Fall is great for its beautiful leaves and nostalgic atmosphere. But as October arrives, we have to start turning on the heat in the bathroom unless to avoid catching a cold when we take a shower. By November, we’re burning firewood more regularly, but trying to conserve it a bit. By the end of November we’re nearing the end of Fall and approaching the much more serious subject of Winter, when a sweatshirt is no longer sufficient, and I must head into work in a full-blown overcoat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, I’m still enjoying November. Today was a great day outside, and I took the children out for a walk, albeit a brief one. I raked up a big bag of leaves and acorns, though by next weekend the backyard will be covered by red and orange once again. The weather is supposed to be great for another week, which is great. The longer Winter is delayed, the better. I’m just enjoying Fall.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Fall is a great time for me, second only to Spring. The heat of Summer is over and the weather remains good. All the delays and closures caused by most of the country being on vacation for the month of August are finished, and the world is back to normal. School starts back up, a new season of sports begins, and work is less hectic because people are actually there, meaning that we don’t have to prepare for the event of an emergency when all the people meant to handle such things are on vacation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A COVID-19 Halloween</title><link href="/blog/2020/10/covid-halloween.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A COVID-19 Halloween" /><published>2020-10-31T17:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-10-31T17:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/10/covid-halloween</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/10/covid-halloween.html">&lt;p&gt;Today is Halloween. It’s the day when we watch &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/It%27s_the_Great_Pumpkin,_Charlie_Brown&quot;&gt;It’s the Great Pumpkin, Charlie Brown&lt;/a&gt;, we set out our jack o’ lanterns for the last night, and our daughter wears her costume all day in high anticipation of trick-or-treating that night. Except that with the global events of this year, especially this month, Halloween is pretty much cancelled in France as far as I can tell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday night, President Macron announced that the nation would be under a new lockdown order until at least December 1 because of the COVID-19 pandemic. France had seen the number of new cases of the disease approach the 50,000 mark, with the total number of total active cases soaring up to and above 1 million. While the number of deaths from the disease is still relatively low, currently just under 300 for the 7-day moving average, that number would continue to increase if no measures were taken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another issue in France in recent weeks has been the rising conflict between radical Islamists and the French state, which has not backed down from its support of the guarantee of the freedom of expression, including displaying on its own initiative a caricature of Mohammed, the central figure to the Muslim religion, which has caused an outcry among the more violently-inclined elements of the Islamic world. Macron’s statement that Islam is a religion “in crisis globally” did nothing to please other Muslims, both in France and abroad. This is hardly a new subject, and surely will not be cleanly resolved by the end of the year, but the fact that the issue seems to be flaring up worse than before is in keeping with the way that 2020 has been going, and as things will be going for the foreseeable future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, the new quarantine doesn’t bother me all that much. We’ve already been subjected to a long quarantine at the beginning of the year, during which I worked from home, Miriam did not go to school, and we needed to fill out a form every time we left the house. This time, Miriam will still be in school, and I will most likely still be going into the office, though I may end up working from home for a portion of the week. The important difference is that schools will remain open, which will make this new quarantine, however long it lasts, much easier to bear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s during times like these that life in France seems pretty good. In this situation, the centralized government of France has the authority and the willingness to make the tough decisions necessary to allow people’s lives to continue on with as little disruption as possible. I feel for those in the USA or elsewhere whose children have been at home since March, or who have either lost their jobs or don’t know when they will receive another full paycheck. Generally speaking, in a crisis, central leadership has a better chance of producing a favorable result than a system in which fifty individual states decide their policies, or when each of thousands of school system governments determine how they will respond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our family has handled the events of 2020 surprisingly well. To start things off, our trip to Wuhan, China was of course cancelled. My long-suffering wife took care of two children mostly by herself for a few months while many French families pawned their children off on the grandparents full-time. COVID-19 might be the best thing that ever happened to Daniel, who enjoys having more people at the house to play with each day. Though I was initially disappointed to lose my position at a small company that could no longer pay my salary, I immedialy found another position as a CTO / Lead Developer of another small company. My commute has been reduced by about half an hour. Miriam has taken the dissapointment of not trick-or-treating in stride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though it certainly is a shame that we can’t do much for Halloween this year besides a couple of jack o’ lanterns, we count ourselves lucky that our lifestyle has not been substantially disrupted. In the future, we’ll be doing everything we can to ensure that things stay that way. COVID-19 may eventually cease to be a real concern, but based on the global trends we are seeing now, a year or two or from now, for some of us missing out on Halloween might be the least of our problems.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Today is Halloween. It’s the day when we watch It’s the Great Pumpkin, Charlie Brown, we set out our jack o’ lanterns for the last night, and our daughter wears her costume all day in high anticipation of trick-or-treating that night. Except that with the global events of this year, especially this month, Halloween is pretty much cancelled in France as far as I can tell.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My 2020 Reading List</title><link href="/blog/2020/10/2020-reading-list.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My 2020 Reading List" /><published>2020-10-24T10:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-10-24T10:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/10/2020-reading-list</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/10/2020-reading-list.html">&lt;p&gt;Every year, I come up with a list of twelve books that I want to read, which I track on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com&quot;&gt;Goodreads&lt;/a&gt;. I do this reading on my commute, as I take the train into work. I’m lucky to take a train with enough seating for everyone, which is not at all the case for some people on their commute. I find that, depending on the size of the book, I can usually read about one page every two minutes. Most books are divided into small chapters of fifteen to twenty pages, or have larger chapters divided into parts of fifteen to twenty pages, which is perfect for my thirty-five minute train ride. Reading on the commute is a good use of my time, as otherwise I would just be scrolling my phone, which ultimately doesn’t lead to anything productive. It is definitely one of the perks of using public transportation instead of driving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My arbitrarily-set goal of one book per month does not always work out perfectly, as in this year when I got a late start due to having not yet finished last year’s books, and then started my 2020 list with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/272793.Imperial_China_900_1800&quot;&gt;Imperial China 900-1800&lt;/a&gt;, which is a great book, but extremely long. I didn’t finish it until May, meaning I was already 4 books behind schedule. By now I’m starting to catch up, but I still have to double my normal pace to finish the list by the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I structure my list in a specific way to cover the subjects that interest me the most. There are two basic types of books on my list: culture or history books, and adventure books. Everything is non-fiction. I’m interested in learning reading about the culture and history of the USA, Mexico, France, Egypt, Russia, and China. As there is a lot of material out there on American history, I include two American history books in my yearly list. I read one book on each of the other countries, and I also add a book on geopolitics or anthropology. For example, in 2019 I read Jared Diamond’s well-known &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/1842.Guns_Germs_and_Steel&quot;&gt;Guns, Germs, and Steel: The Fates of Human Societies&lt;/a&gt;, and this year I am reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/475.Collapse&quot;&gt;Collapse: How Societies Choose to Fail or Succeed&lt;/a&gt; by the same author. For the remaining third of my list, I read books on true tales of adventure or nature which interest me. For example, hiking, sailing, source-to-sea descents of rivers, or tales of survival. This year I’m trying something a little different by reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/27276431-on-trails&quot;&gt;On Trails: An Exploration&lt;/a&gt;, in which I am honored to be briefly mentioned by the author, Robert Moor, because of my time on the International Appalachian Trail, as part of my Eastern Continental Trail thru-hike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally, the adventure books are much shorter, and so I finish them quickly, which is good since I typically take over a month to read some of the longer historical books. The biggest book I’ve read is probably the mammoth &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/1111.The_Power_Broker&quot;&gt;The Power Broker: Robert Moses and the Fall of New York&lt;/a&gt;, which I believe took me about ten weeks, which is not bad for twelve hundred pages. It’s inevitable that I will occasionally pick a book that is not what I thought it would be. I’ve found that there is not very much material on modern Egyptian history and culture, and that therefore I’ve picked out books that turned out to be much more academic than I am used to. I might be hard-pressed to give a good account of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/167462.Colonising_Egypt&quot;&gt;Colonising Egypt&lt;/a&gt;, and this year I am going to read the first &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/263757.Cairo_Cosmopolitan&quot;&gt;Cairo Cosmopolitan&lt;/a&gt; book, which I hope will be more accessible despite it’s academic appearance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far this year, I have nothing but good things to say about the books that I have picked out. That isn’t surprising, since I try to only pick books that are well-known, and have at least a four-star average rating on Goodreads. When finding books on Egypt, Russia, or Mexico, I sometimes have to disregard that standard. I also have to consider that some adventure books are more interesting to me than the average person, such as Colin Angus’ &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/641473.Lost_in_Mongolia&quot;&gt;Lost in Mongolia: Rafting the World’s Last Unchallenged River&lt;/a&gt;. However, in general I’ve had very little dissapointment by sticking to Goodreads ratings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m proud of myself for picking up reading, as for a long period of time I did no real reading at all. From the time I entered college until very recently, I didn’t really see the appeal of investing time into reading a large book. I don’t usually like the feeling of starting something and then feeling obligated to finish it. But I have to say that reading has been a good way to engage in critical thinking, not just about history, culture, or adventure, but about the allegories between what I am reading and the basics of life. Perhaps the only downside to reading large books is that it is simply not possible for me to remember details of these books. If asked, I could give a decent summary, and talk about the main points, but things like names and dates often are lost over time. Despite that, it’s very satisfying to look over the bookshelf and see all the good I’ve read. If you’re interested, feel free to check out my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/65744779-sterling-coleman?order=d&amp;amp;shelf=2020&quot;&gt;2020 Reading List&lt;/a&gt;, and start a reading goal of your own.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Every year, I come up with a list of twelve books that I want to read, which I track on Goodreads. I do this reading on my commute, as I take the train into work. I’m lucky to take a train with enough seating for everyone, which is not at all the case for some people on their commute. I find that, depending on the size of the book, I can usually read about one page every two minutes. Most books are divided into small chapters of fifteen to twenty pages, or have larger chapters divided into parts of fifteen to twenty pages, which is perfect for my thirty-five minute train ride. Reading on the commute is a good use of my time, as otherwise I would just be scrolling my phone, which ultimately doesn’t lead to anything productive. It is definitely one of the perks of using public transportation instead of driving.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Easy PostgreSQL Migrations with pgloader</title><link href="/blog/2020/10/pgloader-migration.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Easy PostgreSQL Migrations with pgloader" /><published>2020-10-17T12:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-10-17T12:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/10/pgloader-migration</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/10/pgloader-migration.html">&lt;p&gt;As part of a recent project, I’ve been dealing with a difficult database migration from MySQL to PostgreSQL. The migration involves moving many tables, and several Gigabytes of data, which must all be moved without any loss. With a move like this, there is a lot to do besides just transferring the data from one base to another, such as refactoring all the raw queries in the backend of the application which must now use SQL syntax compatible with PostgreSQL, changing model definitions in the backend to use PostgreSQL data types, and finding any inconsistencies in the ORM (Object-relational mapping). With all of this and more to do, it is important to find a simple and fast solution for migrating the actual data from one database to another. This is where &lt;a href=&quot;https://pgloader.readthedocs.io/&quot;&gt;pgloader&lt;/a&gt; comes in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pgloader is an open source tool, created by Dimitri Fontaine, author of “Mastering PostgreSQL in Application Development”. The tool has the ability to do migrations to and from PostgreSQL and MySQL, MSSQL, SQLite, and even Citrus databases. It can also transfer data from one PostgreSQL database to another. The tool can load data from files in CSV, DBF, and IBX format. pgloader is quite versatile, and in my opinion is the best option for any type of PostgreSQL data transfer. There are other tools out there, but most are not free, and none of the other options that I saw looked as well-developed as pgloader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ease of the learning curve for the tool is probably the reason that it has become popular. By simply installing the tool from the command line, and copying and modiying an example of a configuration file from pgloader’s documentation, we can start migrating data. This file connects to both the source and target database, and migrates the data. The file is also full of customizable choices, such as whether to drop and recreate the tables, create the schema, deal with foreign keys, index, and sequences, and most importantly, cast certain data types in a certain way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, great applications are made by great default values and choices which streamline the user’s most common navigation path. These defaults must also be easily overriden and customized to capture the portion of the user base which has a specific use case scenario. pgloader does that well. It has default casting rules for each type of database, meaning that for most users performing a migration to PostgreSQL, the tool will take care of all data type definition and conversion. In the case that specific casting rules are needed, it is easy to put those rules in the load file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pgloader is also very fast. The tool could probably migrate two or three times the amount of data that pg_restore (the native PostgreSQL command for filling a database) could upload in the same amount of time. This is because the tool is written in Common Lisp, which can be compiled to machine code and use parallel computing and threads. Related to this is perhaps the only real drawback to pgloader that I found. Because of the Common Lisp compilation needs, it is difficult to get the dependencies for pgloader to all play together nicely on a Windows environment. Most notably, Make and Steel Bank Common Lisp will have difficulty compiling. Common solutions are to use Windows Subsystem for Linux, or Docker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a side note, it is a good thing that pgloader was able to painlessly migrate the desired data from MySQL to PostgreSQL, because all the other parts of this type of migration turned out to be anything but painless. All functions for dates had to be translated from one syntax of SQL to the other. Simply concatenating strings is different, as is returning the first non-null value among several choices. References to tables names and aliases must be made differently, as are several other things. Even the ORM used for the project had different behavior in a couple of special cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most professional projects, I would recommend moving away from MySQL. Though it is an easy database to get started with, and has great supporting tools, complex projects suffer from issues with data types, and unforeseen background issues. For example, I recently ran into a problem when I loaded a backup of a database and found that the timestamp values I loaded were different from the source because of a timezone difference in my local system. This would normally be fine if timestamps were compared to other typestamps, but when the timestamp is compared to a datetime, all havoc occurs as data is misplaced and statistics are marred when one of the values is a few hours off. Instead of having to deal with that, I would recommend moving to PostgreSQL if another SQL flavor is required. PostgreSQL has useful data types such as json, which can be used to enhance performance if modeled correctly. When you make the move, I recommend pgloader as your guide.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">As part of a recent project, I’ve been dealing with a difficult database migration from MySQL to PostgreSQL. The migration involves moving many tables, and several Gigabytes of data, which must all be moved without any loss. With a move like this, there is a lot to do besides just transferring the data from one base to another, such as refactoring all the raw queries in the backend of the application which must now use SQL syntax compatible with PostgreSQL, changing model definitions in the backend to use PostgreSQL data types, and finding any inconsistencies in the ORM (Object-relational mapping). With all of this and more to do, it is important to find a simple and fast solution for migrating the actual data from one database to another. This is where pgloader comes in.</summary></entry></feed>