<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-09-04T23:43:23+02:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Sterling Coleman</title><subtitle>A space for my personal projects and thoughts</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">What I’m Watching: Disc Golf</title><link href="/blog/2020/09/watching-disc-golf.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What I'm Watching: Disc Golf" /><published>2020-09-04T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-09-04T23:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/09/watching-disc-golf</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/09/watching-disc-golf.html">&lt;p&gt;I have the type of personality that leads me to get hung up on a subject for a few weeks and dive into it for awhile, before moving on to the next thing. The things that really interest me deeply endure more than just a few weeks, and become bigger than just a passing interest. There are other things that I find interesting for awhile, but after a few weeks I feel I’ve pretty much exhausted the material available or my initial interest has not developed into anything more. With that in mind, I thought I would create a series of posts that I can come back to occasionally, highlighting my latest interest, usually marked by the kind of videos I’ve been watching lately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, it’s Disc Golf. I got into disc golf a little bit after playing a few times on vacation this summer. I don’t think I ever came close to shooting under par, but I still enjoyed it. I’m not really able to throw the disc straight. Instead, my best shot curves to the left, which is probably very common for right-handed people. Therefore, any hole that has obstacles on the right side is a big problem, since I need to throw a bit to the right to account for the left curve. I still had fun, but definitely wished I could be better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow, I ended up finding professional disc golf videos on the internet. In truth, I don’t know how lucrative playing disc golf is. I would guess that many of those who play it are not making a lot of money, but are able to make a little bit, and play just because they love the game. There are definitely a select few who are well-paid, though. The players that play in the professional tour seem to be really good. On average, I would guess that the holes demand about 150 feet per stroke on average to make it to the hole. When you consider that the limit for most players to make a putt is around 40 feet, that means that players often need to throw three hundred feet off the tee, without hitting obstacles or going out of bounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Distance isn’t the only issue. Disc golf players have a whole set of different methods of throwing the disc. These are needed to be ready for different wind conditions or terrain features. The classic frisbee throw that I know, called a backhand, is merely one way. There is also the forehand. Then there is the Hyzer, which is when the disc angles left, or Anhyzer, when it angles right. There are many other ways to throw the disc, and there are many types of disc as well. Just like golf, there are drivers, mid-range discs, putters, and many other types in between. For someone like me who basically just knows frisbees, it’s all a bit much to take in, but the pros are able to pick out the right disc for the right situation, depending on distance and risks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The videos I’ve been watching have almost all been by a channel called JomezPro. I have to give this channel a lot of credit. The production value is really high for these videos. It feels like I’m watching the sport on cable television. In a sport where it’s critical to get not only a view of the throw but also the landing spot, which is often over a hundred yards away, JomezPro manages to switch seamlessly between takes to make the experience make sense to the viewer, and keep a global view of the hole while still getting all the action in close-up shots. The rounds are well-filmed, and the graphics clearly track the players’ progress. The fact that all this content is available on the internet really highlights the advantage of internet video channels over television, where there are many more hoops to getting content to prospective viewers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think what is great about disc golf is that everyone knows about frisbees, and everyone knows about golf. But watching golf can be a bit boring, because many people like me have never hit a golf ball, and don’t really understand how difficult it is. Watching disc golf is a bit more down-to-earth, and it is much easier to understand the challenges of putting together a series of disc throws to perfectly place the disc in the basket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By now, I’ve seen a lot of rounds of disc golf, so I may dial back my time spent watching a little bit. Sadly there really isn’t much of any disc golf in France, so I can’t really play the game myself. I haven’t really lost interest, though I do think I may have outpaced the amount of disc golf being played, and may need to wait a bit for new tournaments to be played and uploaded to the channel. It isn’t often that I’m interested enough in a sport to get into it this much, so I’m just enjoying this.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">I have the type of personality that leads me to get hung up on a subject for a few weeks and dive into it for awhile, before moving on to the next thing. The things that really interest me deeply endure more than just a few weeks, and become bigger than just a passing interest. There are other things that I find interesting for awhile, but after a few weeks I feel I’ve pretty much exhausted the material available or my initial interest has not developed into anything more. With that in mind, I thought I would create a series of posts that I can come back to occasionally, highlighting my latest interest, usually marked by the kind of videos I’ve been watching lately.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Back to School</title><link href="/blog/2020/08/back-to-school.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Back to School" /><published>2020-08-29T11:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-08-29T11:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/08/back-to-school</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/08/back-to-school.html">&lt;p&gt;Now that it is the end of August, the Back to School season is upon us. We’re lucky to be in France for this period, where the COVID-19 pandemic is under control and children are able to go to school without too many disruptions. After our vacation in the United States this summer, it was obvious that this was not going to be the case there. I’ve seen images of children as young as 5 years old in front of a computer screen at their house for their first day of Kindergarten. As a parent I can’t imagine that situation, and am so happy it won’t be the case for our family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heading back to school is a fun time. It’s the moment when we get all new school supplies, with that new Back to School smell. The pencils are sharp, the folders are unblemished, and the papers are all blank, ready for work to be done. Our daughter Miriam loves getting that stuff. In addition, as fall approaches, it’s a nostalgic time when we think back to previous Back to School moments, and how much we have to look forward to this school year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The French school year starts the first week of September, and never before. In fact this year, Miriam goes to school on the 1st of September, which is a Tuesday. French children start later than many Americans, who are already in school by mid or late August, but they end much later, typically the first week of July. Even more different, this year Miriam’s school has removed those last few days in July and has replaced them with Saturday mornings. This is not completely unheard of in France. I’m not sure how well it would go over back in the States.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;French kids get a lot of vacations to keep them in school until the end of June. They get two weeks off for Halloween, Christmas, Winter, and Easter, respectively. That divides the year up into periods of about six or seven weeks, with two week vacations between them. In elementary school, and perhaps middle school, French schoolchildren also stay home on Wednesdays. As parents it’s not really ideal, and many mothers who work have either negociated a schedule on which they don’t work on Wednesdays, or have found a caretaker for Wednesdays, and often other days as well, to pick the kids up from school. It’s definitely a complaint I have with the French system, which I see as hurting the family, as well as creating a sort of underclass of immigrant or poor babysitters. We’re lucky to have my wife at home to deal with this schedule, but it definitely isn’t ideal to constantly have the schoolyear be broken up by two week periods of vacation, after which Miriam is more reluctant to go back to school, or for her to be home every Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be Miriam’s third and final year of Ecole Maternelle, which is like Preschool. This year, Grande Section, is the equivalent of Kindergarten in the USA. On the one hand, I think it’s exciting that she’s finally the same age I was when I first went to school, but on the other hand, it’s a little anticlimatic since she has already been going to school for two years, and is still in Maternelle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, we’re excited to start the school year, partly because it will mean Miriam will get back to school to interact more in French, and will leave my wife a bit more peace and quiet at the house. Obviously with the COVID-19 pandemic and schools being out for much of last year, she has dealt with two little kids at the house for months extra. This will be a nice break for her, albeit not a real break since she still has our son Daniel with her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know the first day is always difficult. No matter what Miriam says in the days leading up to the First Day of School, she is reluctant to the point of tears to leave the house on that morning. As the week progresses, she is quickly reminded of how much she enjoys school, and is okay to leave the house. We’re looking forward the most to that time.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Now that it is the end of August, the Back to School season is upon us. We’re lucky to be in France for this period, where the COVID-19 pandemic is under control and children are able to go to school without too many disruptions. After our vacation in the United States this summer, it was obvious that this was not going to be the case there. I’ve seen images of children as young as 5 years old in front of a computer screen at their house for their first day of Kindergarten. As a parent I can’t imagine that situation, and am so happy it won’t be the case for our family.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Paris Saint-Germain: First Time in the Final</title><link href="/blog/2020/08/first-time-final.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Paris Saint-Germain: First Time in the Final" /><published>2020-08-22T14:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-08-22T14:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/08/first-time-final</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/08/first-time-final.html">&lt;p&gt;When we first arrived in Paris, I was happy to support the local soccer team, Paris Saint-Germain (PSG). The team was on the upswing, having just started a streak of winning their domestic league, Ligue 1, twice in a row. Since then, the team has won every year except 2016-17, when they were runners up to Monaco. And while this was a cause for celebration, it was also a sign that perhaps the team should be looking beyond Ligue 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All those Ligue 1 results never brought a really successful result in the UEFA Champions League. The two legs of the quarterfinals proved to be the impassable stage which stopped PSG from reaching its European aspirations time and time again. Several times, the team found itself up against top teams in the Round of 16, and were stopped there before even making it to the next round. This includes the infamous two legs played in 2017 against Barcelona, in which PSG won the first match 4-0, but then lost the second 6-1. All of these performances served as fuel for critics of the French league, which they describe as a league much lower in competition or ability compared to the other top leagues in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a relative newcomer to Paris, I have to agree with the critics. Ligue 1 is not at all competitive. Each year, Paris Saint-Germain is determined as the winner well before the end of the season. This is in large part because of the new Qatari owners of the club, who are able to invest a lot of money into the team, especially in the form of world-class players, the most famous of which would be Neymar and Kylian Mbappé.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I agree that the French league is not competitive. It’s the main reason that I don’t follow PSG very closely. There isn’t really a point in watching Ligue 1 matches, because the result is a foregone conclusion. Sadly, Ligue 1 is not alone in this aspect. Juventus has won Serie A every year since 2011-12, Bayern Munich has won the Bundesliga every year since 2012-13, and La Liga has been a contest between Barcelona and Real Madrid for years. The Premier League stands out as being very competitive in comparison, with only Manchester City able to successfully defend their title in 2018-19.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution is obvious to me. Paris needs more than one big team. Of all the big leagues, most have divided their biggest cities into several clubs. Madrid has both Atletico and Real, Rome has Lazio and Roma, Berlin has Hertha and Union, and London has a plethora of teams currently in the Premier League: Arsenal, Chelsea, Crystal Palace, Fulham, Tottenham, and West Ham. If you have a country with one main city, it doesn’t make sense for that city to have just one team, eating up all that market share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;France is definitely such a country. Paris is by far the biggest city in France. More importantly, the Île-de-France region which makes up the Paris metropolitan area, is growing, and there are no big football clubs in the whole region besides Paris Saint-Germain. If I were to pick two other locations suitable for a team, I would pick the Seine-Saint-Denis department North of Paris, with a rising immigrant population. I’m not sure what ticket sales would look like in a poorer immigrant community, but the area definitely has the population to support a decent-sized fanbase. I would also propose another team in the suburbs south of Paris, a place like the Massy-Palaiseau area. There is a large population there and it is a hub. There could be even more teams, but those are some basic options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are actually a couple of smaller teams in the area. Currently, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.redstar.fr/&quot;&gt;Red Star&lt;/a&gt; plays in Saint-Ouen, but they recently moved down from Ligue 2 to the Championnat National. &lt;a href=&quot;https://parisfc.fr/&quot;&gt;Paris FC&lt;/a&gt; also narrowly avoided relegation from Ligue 2 this season, and now has the Kingdom of Bahrain as a minority shareholder, so it appears that there are investors who feel that the Paris area can handle multiple big teams. Hopefully they can use that as fuel to make a run at a top Ligue 2 finish and a move to Ligue 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At any rate, this year Paris-Saint Germain have carried the hopes of the entire city to the UEFA Champions League Final, after coming from behind to beat Borussia Dortmund as well as Atalanta. The semifinal match against Leipzig was a good showing for them, but they will have their hands full against a very powerful Bayern Munich side which is almost impossible to defend. The French will be ecstatic if they manage to win the championship, but even getting this far is a new record for the club, and Parisian fans are already happy with their club. Whatever the outcome, I hope that Ligue 1 becomes more competitive, and that the Parisian area can bring more top clubs into the mix.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">When we first arrived in Paris, I was happy to support the local soccer team, Paris Saint-Germain (PSG). The team was on the upswing, having just started a streak of winning their domestic league, Ligue 1, twice in a row. Since then, the team has won every year except 2016-17, when they were runners up to Monaco. And while this was a cause for celebration, it was also a sign that perhaps the team should be looking beyond Ligue 1.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Back to Work</title><link href="/blog/2020/08/back-to-work.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Back to Work" /><published>2020-08-15T18:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-08-15T18:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/08/back-to-work</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/08/back-to-work.html">&lt;p&gt;One thing that I’ve been putting off as much as possible is all the work that needs to be done on our house. We bought this house back in 2017 and it was in need of remodeling. Some rooms had orange paint on two walls, and purple paint on the other two. Others had old wallpaper. The kitchen still has teal paint. The whole place was a mishmash of colors and wallpapers that didn’t look good by themselves, let alone together. I was prepared to make those changes, and within a few months of our move-in date we had most walls repainted white, and a few small improvements made such as updating electrical sockets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there was still much more to do, and I didn’t feel overly confident in diving into a big project and possibly making a big mistake. Thankfully, our neighbor JB does lots of work on his house, and he came over numerous times to help me out. I’m grateful for everything he’s done for us. But this was supposed to be my work, and so I’ve taken on the vast majority of it alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main improvement that I have made is adding a small bathroom upstairs. When we moved in, there was a small space at the top of the stairs which didn’t really serve any purpose. It was merely space between bedrooms. The realtor had suggested that this could be a bathroom, and I realized that he was right. The only other bathroom was downstairs, not at all convenient for trips in the middle of the night, especially for small children. Even baths for the children would be a nuisance transferring them from the downstairs bath up to their beds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so one summer I embarked upon the upstairs bathroom project. I took hand tools and smashed a hole through a basement cement brick wall big enough for pipes to pass through, then did the same in the cement block basement ceiling, which is also the ground floor. That in itself was a big achievement for me, but just the beginning. After that, there was setting the pipes (both in and out) in place from the basement up through the ground floor to the upstairs space. There was a new ceiling window, ventilation, flooring, water-resistant walls, and tiles. The bath and shower, toilet, and sink. All measured to perfectly fit in a small space (small enough that tall men have their head in the ceiling window space in front of the toilet).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was a ton of work, but the bathroom still wasn’t quite finished. But I basically was. I was exhausted and a little burned out on doing things that I had never done before. I don’t necessarily find it as fun to learn something new as I find it scary to consider the consequences of flooding the house with a bad pipe joint, or just making something very ugly which I won’t enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so for a time I didn’t put in the finishing touches. The kids can take a bath upstairs, but I don’t shower there because there’s no rod for a curtain. There is a light, but no plug for a hair dryer. The hallway between the bedrooms has no finished floor, it’s down to the plywood. And the exterior bathroom wall is not done yet because the electric plug is not done, so I still can’t do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a nice long vacation, I’m refreshed and ready to finish the project. I’m ready to find out how to do things I don’t need to do, and try to do them without overly worrying about a bad result. That doesn’t mean that I am expecting a great result, but rather that I don’t think the quality of my work is vastly inferior to that of an average contractor. My parents have paid contractors to do work on their house, and almost without fail the contractor needs to come back and redo something. So if I have to do the same, I can live with that while I do the job for a quarter of the cost of paying someone else to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I figured out how to connect a new plug to a junction box in the attic. I doubt that whoever previously worked in that junction box organized it in a standard way, but I’m not going to let that bother me today. There will always be another project to reorganize the electrical system, but not today. Today I am finishing the bathroom.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">One thing that I’ve been putting off as much as possible is all the work that needs to be done on our house. We bought this house back in 2017 and it was in need of remodeling. Some rooms had orange paint on two walls, and purple paint on the other two. Others had old wallpaper. The kitchen still has teal paint. The whole place was a mishmash of colors and wallpapers that didn’t look good by themselves, let alone together. I was prepared to make those changes, and within a few months of our move-in date we had most walls repainted white, and a few small improvements made such as updating electrical sockets.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Back Home</title><link href="/blog/2020/08/back-home.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Back Home" /><published>2020-08-12T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-08-12T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/08/back-home</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/08/back-home.html">&lt;p&gt;After three weeks in the United States, our little family is back home. We’re happy to be back to our routine, but also sad to have finished a wonderful vacation. The saying “All good things come to an end” is very appropriate to how we feel about finishing a vacation at Higgins Lake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There aren’t many places that can hold our interest for three full weeks, but Higgins Lake does. This year, we had many of our extended family members come at the same time, which made the trip so fun. From my parents, my brother, my grandmother, and my aunt and uncle’s family of five, and even my cousin and her little family, we had so many people at the lake that there was always something happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course it is the people that really make the vacation. We had the cabin to ourselves for a few days, which was fun, but the atmosphere definitely picked up when the rest of the family showed up. We were really happy to have my grandma there, who is of course our children’s great grandmother. With my parents there, that made four generations all together! We enjoyed this opportunity for her to see our youngest child, and for our older child to form a real memory of her, as she is now old enough to recollect this event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our children of course latched on to my cousins, who are in their teenage years. It was a happy moment for me to see them grown up, as I remember when I was their age and they were just infants. Now we are the family with young children, looking forward to having children who are old enough to do more things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They were very gracious, and spent many hours playing with our children, who just wanted to do little kid things. My cousins were great with them, which made us so happy as parents. But after three weeks, it was time for us to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That moment provides a good opportunity for us to evaluate our home life, and how that compares to vacation. I love vacation, and there’s no better place I love to spend my days off than at Higgins Lake, so I had been looking forward to it for a long time. And yet, after three weeks at the lake, I was ready to go home. Higgins Lake is special because we don’t spend all our time there. If we did, over time it would just be a routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We already have a good routine in Rambouillet, and it provides the feeling of home for us. It definitely sets us apart as the family that flies back to France, while many of our extended family drives home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year I made a bit of a mistake by taking long layovers in New York City in both directions of our return trip. We were tired in both instances, and I found that when I am focused on getting to Higgins Lake or home, I can’t enjoy New York City, especially with two little children in tow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we were the only part of our extended family eligible to cross the Atlantic this summer, with the global pandemic leading European countries to ban American tourism for the time being. As French residents, we were still eligible to travel. We’re happy to be back in our residence where we belong.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">After three weeks in the United States, our little family is back home. We’re happy to be back to our routine, but also sad to have finished a wonderful vacation. The saying “All good things come to an end” is very appropriate to how we feel about finishing a vacation at Higgins Lake.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Destination: Higgins Lake</title><link href="/blog/2020/07/destination-higgins-lake.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Destination: Higgins Lake" /><published>2020-07-27T03:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-07-27T03:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/07/destination-higgins-lake</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/07/destination-higgins-lake.html">&lt;p&gt;Higgins Lake is my favorite destination for a family vacation. I’m currently looking out onto the beautiful lake right now. My family has been coming up here for generations, after an ancestor bought a plot of land up here and built a small cabin about ninety years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the lack of serious improvements made on the property in the near century which followed, I love being here with family in the summer. The most important reason is that my family is here, and that’s something that is not specific to any one place. However, the history of the family coming here almost once a year for many years has built up a lot of great memories and nostalgia in this place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next most important reason, is the water. Simply put, being on the shore of the lake makes all the difference. There is a very soothing breeze which comes right in the window. The water is clear here, and that is something specific to this lake in particular. It’s a beautifully clear lake, not clouded by mud or silt, with a sandy bottom, fed by springs. Obviously, a wonderful lake like that offers opportunities to do every kind of lake boating, fishing, and swimming. I personally love taking a Sunfish sailboat out on windy days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the thing that sets Higgins Lake apart as a top vacation destination for our family is its relative remote location. If this place were in California, Texas, or Florida, it would be swamped with visitors all summer long. The fact that it is instead in Northern Michigan means that it receives mostly weekend boaters coming up from Detroit, and that’s about it. There are plenty of tourists, but it is still a very calm location, a bit of a “hidden gem”. In addition, despite being remote, it is very accessible, right next to an Interstate and a US highway, and not far from towns for groceries or restaurants. Perhaps the only real problem is its distance from major airports: the closest options are Saginaw or Traverse City, the latter having decent seasonal options to arrive from farther away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of all the things that are great about Higgins Lake, meeting up with family is the most important. The pleasure of spending time on the lake is the thing that brings us all together here to spend time with each other. My ideal of a great family vacation is a relaxing time, not necessarily a visit to a big city with a full sight-seeing agenda. Higgins Lake perfectly matches that, which is why I had been looking forward to this trip for so long, and why I have been enjoying my time here.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Higgins Lake is my favorite destination for a family vacation. I’m currently looking out onto the beautiful lake right now. My family has been coming up here for generations, after an ancestor bought a plot of land up here and built a small cabin about ninety years ago.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Development Guide</title><link href="/blog/2020/07/development-guide.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Development Guide" /><published>2020-07-11T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-07-11T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/07/development-guide</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/07/development-guide.html">&lt;p&gt;As a software engineer, one of my pet peeves is dealing with the almighty developer guide. This document exists at almost every software company as an aid for developer writing code. Among other things, it outlines rules for the formatting of code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These guides are important, and necessary, if mainly as a learning tool for developers to recognize features of the tools and languages used. The guide also serves as a warning against potentially undesirable side effects or pitfalls which may not be obvious at first glance. Used in the right way, developers can learn and debate the merits of developing a certain way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, too often the developer guide becomes a way for one person to decide every detail of how the code should look. The guide then goes beyond merely avoiding bad code construction, and delves into enforcing the spacing of the code, the format, and many tiny details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have actually heard people defend developer guide rules such as “The code should be self-evident and have minimal comments”. The next day I’ll be attempting to understand several portions of code which appear to me to be hopelessly tangled. After 30 minutes spent analyzing 50 lines of code, I opt to ask the developer who wrote the code three months ago what it does, and he will spend another thirty minutes deciphering it all over again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The silly developer guide rules don’t help. To me, the developer guide should primarily be used to avoid problems. Very few projects suffer from too many comments in the code. This rule just served to pump our egos up in thinking we were putting out code so good it didn’t need comments, which was not true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intertwined in the developer guide are the tools which are often used to enforce good coding practices. This could be a helpful thing to have in the project, but it all depends on the tool used, and how it is used. I once worked on a project that used a project called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/standard/standard&quot;&gt;standard&lt;/a&gt;. I had a real problem with it. The philosophy behind it was that instead of debating the merits of one way of doing things over another, this tool would simply set the terms. At best, we could ignore a rule in certain cases. There was no customization beyond that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of this centralized dictatorship of code formatting, consider the well-known tool &lt;a href=&quot;https://eslint.org/&quot;&gt;ESLint&lt;/a&gt;, which allows for extensize configuration, as well as having an option to use a list of recommended rules, to facilitate a quick start when desired. I think that the time spent discussing these points is important. It gets developers in the mindset of developing in an abstract, flexible fashion that allows a team to work on the same code seamlessly. The goal shouldn’t be to remove individual creativity, but rather to encourage it when it makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the age-old debate of Tabs vs Spaces is an example of this difference of philosophy. It makes no sense to me that there seem to be more developers who prefer to indent their code using spaces as opposed to tabs. This might have made sense over ten years ago, when some text editors didn’t have proper configuration options for indentation. Now I can configure any respectable editor to display a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;TAB&lt;/code&gt; character as a certain number of columns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what is the debate? If I want my editor to use 17 columns for every &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;TAB&lt;/code&gt; character, that’s my business. When I commit the code to the repository, someone else can grab it and use their own configuration to determine how many columns a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;TAB&lt;/code&gt; character uses. That’s the flexible option. Using spaces just means that we can mandate 2-space indentation, and use that to attempt to develop code with too many nested levels of logic to be easy comprehensible. Let’s stop micromanaging developers and instead just mark the danger areas and let them be free otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">As a software engineer, one of my pet peeves is dealing with the almighty developer guide. This document exists at almost every software company as an aid for developer writing code. Among other things, it outlines rules for the formatting of code.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">End of the 2020 School Year</title><link href="/blog/2020/07/end-of-school.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="End of the 2020 School Year" /><published>2020-07-04T18:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-07-04T18:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/07/end-of-school</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/07/end-of-school.html">&lt;p&gt;Today is July 4th, Independence Day in the United States. As an American abroad, I hadn’t even realized it was Independence Day, as it is not a holiday here in France. One of the more minor problems of living abroad is that you miss out on your usual holidays, and you don’t have the same habit of celebrating new national holidays in your place of residence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before July 4th was Friday, July 3rd, the last day of the tumultuous 2019-2020 school year. When I look back on the school year, I can see that we were luckier than most, in having a mere two months (not including the French Easter holiday of two weeks) cut from the school calendar because of COVID-19. In some states in the US, schools didn’t meet at all for the remainder of the school year once initially suspended in-school classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, we stopped sending our child to school in the middle of March, but were able to send her back at the beginning of June for two days a week, and then had a full French schedule of four days a week for the final two weeks, until July 3rd. Having our four-year-old Miriam at home during that whole time probably didn’t help to foster her independence, but she grew a lot during the year nevertheless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In France, there are three years of what Americans might call preschool, which are actually part of the public school system. For the 2017-2018 school year, &lt;a href=&quot;https://fr.statista.com/statistiques/499756/taux-scolarisation-france-par-age/&quot;&gt;97.2% of 3-year-olds&lt;/a&gt; were in school in France. Since then, school has become mandatory for 3-year-olds. This first year was a difficult period for our child, as she had to learn to fully communicate in French for the first time. This past year, the second, was much easier, and turned out to be a huge period of growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of constantly being worried about school and being away from her mother, we got to see Miriam be happy to go to school in the morning, and more willing to talk about her day once she got home. This is in part thanks to two consecutive years of hard work by great teachers, who take in 30 small children and somehow develop each one during the course of the year. Our teacher was fluent in both English in French, which was a big boost for us, and helped Miriam cope with the separation of her best friend from the previous year, who was in a different class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, our decision to put Miriam in a private French Catholic school has turned out well. Though not specifically Catholic ourselves, Miriam gets the opportunity to learn about Christianity from her teachers and the school priest, and surprises us with how much she knows when she gets home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She is still a young child, but now she has left infancy behind for good. She does a great job taking care of her younger brother, and is starting to accept our authority as parents. She can understand basic logic and can see that accept that she can be wrong sometimes, and changes her attitude and apologizes accordingly. This is a big step from the stubborn behavior she naturally exhibited in the prior year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been a pleasure to watch her grow up, and we look forward to even bigger changes next year, as she starts the final year of preschool, equivalent to Kindergarten in the United States. It is difficult to believe that all the work we have put in as parents and all the growth we have seen has been in a portio of her life that she may not remember much at all as an adult. And yet, if she can do so much now as she nears her fifth birthday, we can only imagine the development that will come to pass in the years to come.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Today is July 4th, Independence Day in the United States. As an American abroad, I hadn’t even realized it was Independence Day, as it is not a holiday here in France. One of the more minor problems of living abroad is that you miss out on your usual holidays, and you don’t have the same habit of celebrating new national holidays in your place of residence.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Routing the Northern Divide Trail</title><link href="/blog/2020/06/routing-northern-divide-trail.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Routing the Northern Divide Trail" /><published>2020-06-27T13:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-06-27T13:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/06/routing-northern-divide-trail</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/06/routing-northern-divide-trail.html">&lt;p&gt;Of all the resources I have prepared for the Northern Divide Trail, the most important is probably the Keyhold Markup File (KML/KMZ) which I have created using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/earth/&quot;&gt;Google Earth&lt;/a&gt;. If an explorer were to upload this file to a GPS receiver, possibly by converting it to GPS Exchange Format (GPX), then the person would be able to follow the trail with high precision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this assumes that a person is capable of walking the line defined by this resource. Therein lies the difficulty of blazing a new trail. It is easy to create a theoretical path between two points, but much more difficult to fit that path to the constraints of thru-hiking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main difficulty posed is that of the extreme difficulty of the terrain of the Northern Rocky Mountains. Many of the mountains encountered are steep, and sometimes taking a detour would mean a large increase in the hiking distance, as well as bypassing interesting and notable features that an explorer does not want to miss. See this table for a tangible account of the total elevation change of the NDT compared to other notable trails:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Trail&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Distance (km)&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Total Elevation Change (km)&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Average Elevation Change (%)&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Appalachian&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;3530&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;312&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;8.9&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Great Divide&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;1130&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;42&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;3.7&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Northern Divide&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;1000&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;130&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Northern Divide Trail packs almost as much elevation change as the Appalachian Trail (which itself averages more change per mile than both the Pacific Crest and Continentail Divide Trails) into less than a third of the distance of the Appalachian Trail. It is a relatively short but extremely difficult trail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, I have put constraints on the Keyhole Markup File which defines the route in minute detail, in an attempt to tone down the difficulty. First, I have divided the route into days, and all days are no greater than 40 kilometers, which is less than the 50+ kilometers that I typically hiked on the AT. I also set a maximum slope of 50% on the entire route, meaning that at all times, a person will not be taking on more than a 45° angle. This is still a steep slope, and when taken for a long distance, can be quite exhausting. Switchbacks are sometimes employed to satisy this constraint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I have endeavored to reduce the total amount of elevation change by routing the trail through valleys and low elevatio areas when possible. Unfortunately, this is difficult and not possible on a large scale without taking the trail out of the mountains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Muskwa Ranges, specifically the Akie Range and the Sentinel Range, contain the most elevation change, though the area around Mount Crysdale, in the Misinchinka Ranges, is also very demanding. Beyond that, the highest point on the trail (2632 meters) is located at a pass near Ithaca Glacier and Mount Ulysses. The trail continues to approach this altitude father North. The entirety of the Sentinel Range, at the most northern section of the Rocky Mountains, poses a serious challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Northernmost portion of the trail makes routing difficult, as the mountains therein are not only steep, but appear to be barren and smooth rock. This makes the common technique of using switchbacks much less effective, and the threat of a possibly fatal slip very serious. The area around Nonda Peak continues to pose a challenge for the creation of a plausible route for the trail. The NDT aspires to explore the most prominent features of the Northern Rocky Mountains, but there must also be a consideration for safety.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Of all the resources I have prepared for the Northern Divide Trail, the most important is probably the Keyhold Markup File (KML/KMZ) which I have created using Google Earth. If an explorer were to upload this file to a GPS receiver, possibly by converting it to GPS Exchange Format (GPX), then the person would be able to follow the trail with high precision.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Trailblazing the Northern Divide</title><link href="/blog/2020/06/trailblazing-northern-divide.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Trailblazing the Northern Divide" /><published>2020-06-21T01:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-06-21T01:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/06/trailblazing-northern-divide</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/06/trailblazing-northern-divide.html">&lt;p&gt;After finishing my Eastern Continental Trail hike, I had many ideas. I wanted to hike across America, I wanted to kayak, and as I had hiked the ECT, I had fantasized about all the things I wanted to do. Finishing my hike, I decided to go in a different direction, but still had a passion for exploration. I took a step back and decided I was most interested in big mountain ranges. In North America, none is longer than the Rocky Mountains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Americans, hiking the Rocky Mountains means the &lt;a href=&quot;https://continentaldividetrail.org/&quot;&gt;Continental Divide Trail&lt;/a&gt; (CDT), one of the three trails required to attain the famed Triple Crown of North American hiking. Yet, the CDT is not a trail which spans the Rocky Mountains. It is a trail which spans the United States, with each terminus being on a border with Mexico and Canada, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://greatdividetrail.com/&quot;&gt;Great Divide Trail&lt;/a&gt; (GDT) has been revived. This is a trail touching the American border at the Northern Terminus of the CDT, and stretching North to Lake Kakwa. This is a difficult and beautiful trail. Maintainers appear to have put a lot of hard work into this trail, and it has shown in the trail’s rising popularity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yet, the GDT does not cover the entire Canadian portion of the Rocky Mountains. The Rocky Mountains are officially bounded by the Liard River to the North. The mountain ranges north of the Liard River are part of the American Cordillera, but are not part of the Rocky Mountains. The distance between the Liard River and Kakwa Lake is vast and virtually uninhabited. To cover this distance would be a real exploration. This is my idea for the &lt;a href=&quot;/exploration/northern-divide-trail&quot;&gt;Northern Divide Trail&lt;/a&gt; (NDT).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have put a lot of time into researching the route and documenting this proposed trail. As of right now, the top priority is coming up with a better strategy for resupplying in between Chetwynd and Toad River. This will probably be a long walk into Pink Mountain. The next priority is a review of the proposed trail to ensure that none of the proposed terrain is too steep or dangerous, and if there are doubts on this point, to create alternate routes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is still much work to be done, but I have created a solid base proposal. I hope that what I have started can make for a discussion among those who have more knowledge on the subject and who are in a better position to advance this proposal.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">After finishing my Eastern Continental Trail hike, I had many ideas. I wanted to hike across America, I wanted to kayak, and as I had hiked the ECT, I had fantasized about all the things I wanted to do. Finishing my hike, I decided to go in a different direction, but still had a passion for exploration. I took a step back and decided I was most interested in big mountain ranges. In North America, none is longer than the Rocky Mountains.</summary></entry></feed>