<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-09-12T21:57:19+02:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Sterling Coleman</title><subtitle>A space for my personal projects and thoughts</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Success on Mont Blanc: Part 3</title><link href="/blog/2021/09/success-mont-blanc-part-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Success on Mont Blanc: Part 3" /><published>2021-09-04T12:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-09-04T12:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/09/success-mont-blanc-part-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/09/success-mont-blanc-part-3.html">&lt;p&gt;In the very early hours of the morning, everyone else in the hut got up and started their ascent to the summit. I woke up later and noticed that the wind was howling outside. Refuge Goûter sits on the edge of a cliff, which makes for an incredible view, albeit in high winds. When Kevin woke up, he noticed the same thing, and we were both happy that we hadn’t attempted a summit in those conditions. Kevin was already feeling very sore, and a summit attempt at 3AM in high winds didn’t seem like a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got up and packed up my stuff. My brother got up a little later and got packed up. We both ate as much of our food as we could, as we wouldn’t need much on the descent. We finally got going around 9:30 AM, as the first people to summit that day were returning to the refuge. It was quite windy, and we were glad to be heading down, instead of being blasted on the snowy ridgelines of the upper mountain. I got our harnesses hooked up with a rope, and put everything else away in order to manage that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The descent from Goûter down to Tête Rousse was time consuming for us. We took extreme caution, and backed down most of the mountain. I used the rope to ensure that Kevin had an extra failsafe as he was still feeling sore, but he never ended up needing it. It is quite intimidating when you stare down the mountain for a distance and can barely see your destination far below. We tried not to do that, instead preferring to focus on just the next few steps, taking each problem on one at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that was a little odd for me, was that Kevin was consistently feeling a little cold on the trip, whereas I was the opposite. Even on the descent, where I wasn’t exerting myself, I immediately took off my coat and descended in just a long sleeve shirt and gloves. We encouraged each other and psyched ourselves up during the descent in order to stay sharp. The mental game was just as important as the physical aspect, which consisted just of finding the right spots for feet and hands to cling onto the mountain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon enough other groups passed us by, as they sped down the mountain. We were no longer phased by this. Our success on Mont Blanc was not determined by our speed, but by getting all the way up to Refuge Goûter with no guide and no prior mountaineering experience, and getting down the mountain safely while slightly injured, all without needing a rescue operation. We kept descending, and eventually Tête Rousse stopped being a dot in the distance, and it grew quite close. There started to be more sections which we could walk normally, without backing down the mountain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made it to Tête Rousse, and took a brief break after taking off our crampons and stowing the harnesses and rope. We were pretty much safe. The descent from there down to the Eagle’s Nest and the tramway took a long time, and I finished off a fantastic sunburn, but they were not dangerous. We took our time as my brother’s injuries were starting to aggravate him, but we did make it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally back in town, we managed to offload our gear and make it to the hotel. I could finally exhale and feel good about getting off the mountain safely. It’s true that we didn’t summit, and that is a real shame. If I had thought that there was any way to do it safely and get back down the mountain, I would have gone for it. The reality is, we made the right decision, even though it hurt. As it happens, we took so long to get down the mountain, that even leaving at 9:30 AM, we didn’t exit the rental shop until 7 PM. We would have never made it to the summit and all the way back down. I call our trip a success from an amateur’s perspective. There were very few other groups attempting the mountain without a guide, and those that were, seemed to have more experience, and certainly had lighter packs than us. We did the best we could, and we came home safe, sound, and on time for my brother Kevin’s wedding. But that is a whole ‘nother story!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">In the very early hours of the morning, everyone else in the hut got up and started their ascent to the summit. I woke up later and noticed that the wind was howling outside. Refuge Goûter sits on the edge of a cliff, which makes for an incredible view, albeit in high winds. When Kevin woke up, he noticed the same thing, and we were both happy that we hadn’t attempted a summit in those conditions. Kevin was already feeling very sore, and a summit attempt at 3AM in high winds didn’t seem like a good idea.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Success on Mont Blanc: Part 2</title><link href="/blog/2021/08/success-mont-blanc-part-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Success on Mont Blanc: Part 2" /><published>2021-08-28T12:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-08-28T12:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/08/success-mont-blanc-part-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/08/success-mont-blanc-part-2.html">&lt;p&gt;We were exhausted both physically and emotionnaly when we arrived at the Eagle’s Nest. We had hiked upwards for 6 hours through rain and wind to get to the point at which most climbers start their trip after taking the tramway. The staff at the Eagle’s Nest was very kind, and we dried out a lot of our clothing. There were no other hikers there. We attempted to eat some, but I couldn’t stand the smell of the food. After a long day, I was anxious about continuing the trip the next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That night, my brother and I exchanged our thoughts and fears on the trip so far, and what was to come. I explained that I wasn’t afraid to end my ascent if I felt it was risky to continue. My brother had already scared me by entering the early stages of hypothermia on the trail above Bionnassay. I wanted to climb Mont Blanc, but I also wanted to avoid an injury or a helicopter rescue, of which there are many on the mountain every summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following morning, we slowly gathered our things and set out around 8:30 AM. We timed it well, as we ended up starting our climb out of the Eagle’s Nest at the same time that others were getting off the tramway and going on ahead of us. We followed them up the mountain, passing through a section with many loose rocks. We soon passed by the first pockets of snow, and had to make a slight correction in navigation to get back onto the path as it climbed towards Tête Rousse. The other hikers went on ahead of us. It was too difficult for us to keep up, even with older hikers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though we were slow, we had the advantage of starting in the morning. This removed the concern of time, as we knew we had plenty of time to make our planned hike to Refuge Goûter. It was incredibly majestic as well as incredibly intimidating to be able to look high up and see this destination almost from the time that we left the Eagle’s Nest. The hike up to Tête Rousse was not easy, but not as difficult as the previous day. From there, we switched to crampons, put our helmets on, and stared at a long steep climb up to Refuge Goûter, towering above us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We trudged up the snow hill, and we passed through the famously dangerous Couloir de la Mort without even realizing it. The snowfall over the previous days had rendered this formidable obstacle harmless. After this, the climb was technical. We put away the hiking poles and got the ice axes out. We climbed up hand over hand, always grateful for any two consecutive steps that occurred without encountering a rock face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, the going was slow. Every group we encountered passed us, including women and older men. We had larger packs than anyone else, and we took frequent breaks. Kevin was feeling very sore from the previous day, and was actually grateful to be doing a little technical climbing which involves the arms, and not purely legs. Nevertheless, the climb was very long. We must have spent 4 hours just climbing. By the time we made it all the way up to Refuge Goûter, it was 3:30 PM. We walked through a strong wind to get there, then collapsed into bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a nap, I got up and looked around. One of the first things I noticed was that the elevation of the refuge was not what I thought it was. I had believe that we had ascended to within 500 meters of the summit. In reality, we were still a full 1000 meters away. This was a huge blow, because that elevation change represented over half of the altitude we had gained that day. The hike to the summit would be tough, and on top of that we needed to descend all the way back to the bottom of the entire mountain, turn in our gear at the rental shop, and crash at a hotel for an early morning departure the next day. We really couldn’t afford to get stuck on the mountain and possibly miss our flight back to the US to get to Kevin’s upcoming wedding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we evaluated the difficulty we had just to ascend the 1500 meters each of the previous two days, and the energy we would need as we descended steeply from Refuge Goûter back to Tête Rousse, it became obvious that the safe choice would be to put our full energy into a safe descent of the mountain. This was disappointing, but I was glad to make this decision, because I was very concerned about the descent. When you are staring up the mountain, you can at least climb facing forward, and lean into the mountain. When descending, obviously the direction you are facing becomes a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the decision made to descend directly the following day instead of attempting what would have been a dangerous summit attempt for us, I was relieved. I think Kevin was more disappointed than I was, which I understood. He had flown from America with the goal of summitting Mont Blanc, but we just weren’t in good enough physical shape, and we had brought a little too much clothing. We also had a little too much food with us, but not by a lot. In any case, we knew that we would not be getting up at 3AM to start a summit attempt with everyone else, so we relaxed in bed and prepared for a morning descent the next day.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">We were exhausted both physically and emotionnaly when we arrived at the Eagle’s Nest. We had hiked upwards for 6 hours through rain and wind to get to the point at which most climbers start their trip after taking the tramway. The staff at the Eagle’s Nest was very kind, and we dried out a lot of our clothing. There were no other hikers there. We attempted to eat some, but I couldn’t stand the smell of the food. After a long day, I was anxious about continuing the trip the next day.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Success on Mont Blanc: Part 1</title><link href="/blog/2021/08/success-mont-blanc-part-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Success on Mont Blanc: Part 1" /><published>2021-08-21T09:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-08-21T09:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/08/success-mont-blanc-part-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/08/success-mont-blanc-part-1.html">&lt;p&gt;Now that the summer is coming to an end, I’m finally getting back to my blog. Taking a break has been refreshing, and I’ve been busy with a lot of different things. Now that I have a free moment, I’d like to recount the adventure of climbing Mont Blanc with my brother Kevin at the beginning of August.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I have mentioned previously, Kevin had recruited me for this trip over a year before, and we had spent a lot of time preparing reservations and researching the logistics. On Tuesday, August 3, he flew into Paris, and we met up. First we got his American vaccine card translated into a French QR code in the TousAntiCovid app, allowing him to access any locations requiring proof of a vaccination or a negative COVID test. After getting off work, we hastily transferred everything we wouldn’t be taking to the mountain to my wife to take back to our house, and we travelled across Paris to get on our high-speed train to Lyon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We traversed Lyon on foot at midnight, still clutching our shopping bags full of gear and food, and found our hotel for the night. Up by 6AM the next morning, we took a series of regional trains to Saint-Gervais-les-Bains, one of the villages at the foot of Mont Blanc. Just getting from the train station to the rental gear shop was a challenge. I made a big mistake by following Google Maps through a park, which led us up a steep and muddy footpath. Our large bag handles were difficult to manage with pure arm strength, and by the time we made it up to the top, I was soaked in sweat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We didn’t have much time to commiserate, as we needed to get to Unlimited Sports to rent our mountaineering gear before it closed for lunch. We did finally arrive, and started the long process of getting all of our gear, and receiving instructions on every piece. The owner of the shop was helpful and took the time to make sure we understood how everything worked, and that we were prepared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time we were ready to leave the village, it was already 1PM. I called the the Eagle’s Nest hut, were we had a reservation for the night, to confirm that we could arrive after the normal 5PM limit. I was told that anything before 7PM was fine. With this taken care of, we stocked up on water and left on a long walk up to the Eagle’s Nest. I had asked my brother if we could do this instead of simply taking the tramway, as I wanted the experience of climbing the entire mountain. We had already walked from the train station up to the upper portion of the village, and now we passed though Bionnay, and then Bionnassay. Bionnassay is a group of homes way up on the side of the mountain. Wearing our slightly unweildy mountaineering boots from the rental shop, we slowly made our way to this village.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once up at the heart of Bionnassay, we saw a sign marking the Eagle’s Nest as being 3 hours and 50 minutes away by foot. It was already 4PM. We didn’t have much choice but to just continue trudging on, as we continued to climb up and up. Our packs felt heavy. At one point, I asked Kevin to take the 30-meter mountaineering rope for a time, as it was the heaviest thing I had, and I was feeling tired. The path up from Bionnassay to the Eagle’s Nest was very long. The portion just after leaving the village felt like a steep climb with our full packs. Of course, there was beauty all around us, which encouraged us to keep moving forward. As we continued on, each sign further on showed that we were reducing the gap and stood a chance of arriving at the refuge by 7PM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last portion of the day, the slight drizzle we had been experiencing all day picked up. Combined with a stronger wind, Kevin was feeling pretty cold, and put on all his gear in order to stay safe. We had to cross a series of small streams and waterfalls which slowed us down a little bit, and there was just a non-stop climb that had our spirits low. After little sleep, Kevin’s jet lag, and heavy packs, we had had enough. Thankfully, the slog did eventually end, and we made it to the Eagle’s Nest about 60 seconds before 7PM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be continued…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Now that the summer is coming to an end, I’m finally getting back to my blog. Taking a break has been refreshing, and I’ve been busy with a lot of different things. Now that I have a free moment, I’d like to recount the adventure of climbing Mont Blanc with my brother Kevin at the beginning of August.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mont Blanc Preparation</title><link href="/blog/2021/06/mont-blanc-preparation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mont Blanc Preparation" /><published>2021-06-05T09:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-06-05T09:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/06/mont-blanc-preparation</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/06/mont-blanc-preparation.html">&lt;p&gt;Months ago, my brother surprised me by proposing that we climb Mont Blanc together. Mont Blanc is the highest mountain in Western Europe, or rather, the highest mountain in Europe not including the Caucasus, which contains several mountains which reach a higher elevation. At just over 4,800 meters, Mont Blanc reaches above Mount Whitney, the highest mountain in the continental United States, by almost 400 meters. I have good experience in hiking, but mountain climbing normally involves a different set of skills. While I may be at ease walking for days on end, if I were to do Mont Blanc, I would be exerting the maximum level of energy expended during a hike, continuously for atleast two days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, I was happy to take on the proposed challenge. Right away, I dived into the research phase, which I believe is the most important phase of any adventure. I was happy to find that I could be of use for this sort of work, as I sifted through material only available in French, though there is also an abundant amount of information available in English. My brother had mentioned the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tour_du_Mont_Blanc&quot;&gt;Tour de Mont Blanc&lt;/a&gt;, but I quickly found that though that trail is very popular, it doesn’t go anywhere near the summit of the mountain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I quickly fell upon the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Go%C3%BBter_Route&quot;&gt;Goûter Route&lt;/a&gt;, which is the most popular and definitely the easiest route to the summit. The best part of the route may be that there are established shelters (refuges in French) along the route, the closest to the summit being the &lt;a href=&quot;https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Refuge_du_Go%C3%BBter&quot;&gt;Refuge du Goûter&lt;/a&gt;. Naturally, I started looking into booking a couple of spots at this shelter, and found immediately that it would not be so easy. It turns out that there are other people looking to summit Mont Blanc, and though the refuge is big considering its location, there simply aren’t enough spots for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reservation system is divided between spots saved for guides, and the general public. For the public, on certain dates and times, a limited number of spots open up. Thankfully, it’s not a complete free-for-all at those times, as the FFCAM (Fédération française des clubs alpins et de montagne) has put in place a waiting queue for those times. Unfortunately, the way in which this waiting queue works was not sufficiently clear to those of us who have never used the system, and my brother and I failed to get a spot on our first try. Thankfully, I was able to get a couple spots at Refuge du Goûter on the second and final reservation date, though the dates we got were not our first choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, the hardest and most important task in the preparation phase is complete. Since then, I have got all the train tickets and hotel rooms reserved, and the schedule is set. Now, I’m researching the difficulty of the route itself in order to prepare for eventual difficulties. I’ve seen some good videos which encapsulate the hike from Refuge Nid d’Aigle, at the end of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mont_Blanc_tramway&quot;&gt;Mont Blanc Tramway&lt;/a&gt;, up to Refuge du Goûter. Clearly the most dangerous part of this portion of the climb is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grand_Couloir_(Mont_Blanc)&quot;&gt;Grand Couloir&lt;/a&gt;, where falling and tumbling rocks are impossible to predict, and could be fatal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Refuge du Goûter, we’ll be putting on crampons and climb through the snow and ice, being careful to avoid crevasses in the ice. The key is to stay on the established path at all times, leave early, and go slowly and carefully but without stopping. The weather conditions at the summit can be quite foggy with little or no visibility, which is a major hazard when the path is on a knife’s edge, both sides of which are steep ice slopes, on which a fall could be fatal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though there are certainly dangers, the summit of a mountain as high as Mont Blanc is relatively easy, and can be done by those of us who are not technical experts in mountain climbing. Perhaps the best news for us is that there will be many other people on the mountain with us, the route is well-established, and we will be following directly in the footsteps of many other people. For now, I am concentrating on getting in good physical shape overall, to make sure that there are no issues on the summit day.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Months ago, my brother surprised me by proposing that we climb Mont Blanc together. Mont Blanc is the highest mountain in Western Europe, or rather, the highest mountain in Europe not including the Caucasus, which contains several mountains which reach a higher elevation. At just over 4,800 meters, Mont Blanc reaches above Mount Whitney, the highest mountain in the continental United States, by almost 400 meters. I have good experience in hiking, but mountain climbing normally involves a different set of skills. While I may be at ease walking for days on end, if I were to do Mont Blanc, I would be exerting the maximum level of energy expended during a hike, continuously for atleast two days.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Learning to Read, Write, and Speak</title><link href="/blog/2021/05/read-write-speak.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learning to Read, Write, and Speak" /><published>2021-05-29T08:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-05-29T08:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/05/read-write-speak</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/05/read-write-speak.html">&lt;p&gt;I typically try not to write too much about my children. Bragging about them can be good in moderate amounts, but as the Western world has seen in the past few decades, many parents think that every little thing that their kids do is a big achievement. Not everything that a child does is a sign of a big improvement or new abilities. However, recently our daughter Miriam has progressed a lot in her reading and writing abilities, and our son Daniel has been speaking in longer and more complex sentences. That type of development is indeed a big improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Miriam is not yet six years old, and in the French school system, she is in the last year of what I would call preschool. Real schoolwork doesn’t really begin until next year, when she enters the elementary school. Of course, her teachers do a lot of work with her right now too, and she has learned a lot at school. But as far as I know, she is not expected to be able to read or write full sentences on her own until next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our son Daniel is just three years old, so reading and writing is still a couple of years away. However, he has been making big improvements in his speaking ability. It used to be that he would just give a few words in response to a question or command. Now, he demonstrates an enjoyment in putting together longer statements. He’s starting to lose the baby voice and sound much more like our daughter or other children when he speaks. It’s difficult to explain the difference, but it’s obvious when we listen to him talk that he is enjoying speaking. Of course, we are a little wary that this could soon lead to the period that our daughter Miriam had at this age, at which time if she was awake, she was talking. But Daniel is a different person, and we’re happy that he is demonstrating an enjoyment of his new skills in verbal communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, what is most impressive about all of this is that both children are multilingual. In fact, the improvements which I have described in Miriam’s reading and writing are just what I have seen in English. I haven’t seen her reading in French, but I know that she can write a lot of basic French words already. Most interestingly, according to my wife her Chinese character writing has progressed a lot as well. Daniel may not be speaking a lot of French, but he does understand French, and he enjoys repeating the days of the week or counting to ten with his sister.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a parent, improvements in communication skills are improvements worth celebrating. It makes our job a lot easier when communication is better. When Daniel can express himself, he cries less, which is a big relief for our nerves. As Miriam continues to improve her reading, she is entering a new phase in which she enjoys reading, and will read things by herself, making things easier for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course, as a parent there is a simple satisfaction in seeing a change in our children, and watching them grow. Reading, writing, and speaking are all important skills on their own. Seeing improvements in those subjects in three different languages makes us very proud, and is part of the validation we feel as parents who have made an effort to provide the right learning environemnt to obtain these important skills.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">I typically try not to write too much about my children. Bragging about them can be good in moderate amounts, but as the Western world has seen in the past few decades, many parents think that every little thing that their kids do is a big achievement. Not everything that a child does is a sign of a big improvement or new abilities. However, recently our daughter Miriam has progressed a lot in her reading and writing abilities, and our son Daniel has been speaking in longer and more complex sentences. That type of development is indeed a big improvement.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Patrick Leigh Fermor</title><link href="/blog/2021/05/patrick-leigh-fermor.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Patrick Leigh Fermor" /><published>2021-05-22T08:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-05-22T08:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/05/patrick-leigh-fermor</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/05/patrick-leigh-fermor.html">&lt;p&gt;A couple of years ago, my father recommended me a book called &lt;em&gt;A Time of Gifts&lt;/em&gt; By Patrick Leigh Fermor. The book chronicles the beginning of Fermor’s travels from England across Europe to Istanbul, ending at the border between Romania and Yugoslavia. I was a bit skeptical at first, as the other books of adventure which I read are more wilderness or survival experiences, such as Joshua Slocum’s circumnavigation of the globe, or Colin Angus’ source-to-sea descent of the Yenisey River. I didn’t really think that a walk from town to town across Europe would be nearly as interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the circumstances help to make the trip more than a simple trip on foot across Europe. The setting is 1933, meaning that we’re seeing different countries in Europe as they were right before World War 2, when many of these places were changed forever. Obviously, Germany was in a state of rapid change, but in other places farther East, Fermor also delivers a snapshot of the lives of aristocrats in countries where aristocrats were completely dispossessed during, and especially after the war. Many of the people that Fermor met and stayed with along the way were persecuted because of their status as wealthy elites. This gives Fermor’s writings a historical value that isn’t found in most travel journals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two further books concerning this trip were published after &lt;em&gt;A Time of Gifts&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Between the Woods and Water&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Broken Road&lt;/em&gt;. The final book in the trilogy was started by Fermor, but only finished by others using his notes. In these works, Fermor finishes his trip to Istanbul, passing through Yugoslavia, then back to Romania, Bulgaria, and finally into Turkey. He spends a lot of time in these countries, and there is a detailed look at the lifestyles of people whose lives were to change forever during the war. Many of them died.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most obvious link between all the subjects in these travel writings is Fermor’s intelligence. He was just 18 years old when he began his journey to walk across Europe alone. Yet he was very adept at picking up languages, becoming fluent in German, and always picking up enough of each local language to get by. He studied hard during his nights and extended stays, and showed through his writing his wide range of literary knowledge at a young age. This was the main factor that set these books apart as more interesting than typical travel writings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The languages also show a time when the aristocrats of Eastern Europe were still clinging to a sort of nobility status, in which they all spoke French and often German, and lived lifestyles reminiscent of royalist societies. On the other hand, the lower classes included many communities of more isolated ethnic groups which spoke minority languages. I suspect that with the aftermath of the war and modernization that these communities have mostly dissappeared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having just finished the third and final book in this travel trilogy, I can definitely recommend it. It has value simply in the adventure of traveling on foot and seeing many different places. More significantly, it depicts adventure from a time period before the modern era as we know it, which is a type of adventure that we don’t get to see very often. The intelligence of Fermor and his incredible memory of the trip brings a bygone era to life.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">A couple of years ago, my father recommended me a book called A Time of Gifts By Patrick Leigh Fermor. The book chronicles the beginning of Fermor’s travels from England across Europe to Istanbul, ending at the border between Romania and Yugoslavia. I was a bit skeptical at first, as the other books of adventure which I read are more wilderness or survival experiences, such as Joshua Slocum’s circumnavigation of the globe, or Colin Angus’ source-to-sea descent of the Yenisey River. I didn’t really think that a walk from town to town across Europe would be nearly as interesting.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Finishing the Carpet</title><link href="/blog/2021/05/finishing-carpet.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Finishing the Carpet" /><published>2021-05-16T07:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-05-16T07:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/05/finishing-carpet</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/05/finishing-carpet.html">&lt;p&gt;For a long time, the upstairs bedrooms in our house have been unfinished. This is mostly because of a multitide of setbacks, starting with the discovery that we had water damage at two different windows. Including the time needed to find a suitable way to replace the windows as cheaply as possible, the manufacture of the windows, and the delays in the installation process, the replacement of these windows took over a year to complete. Once that was done, we were finally able to get our insurance company to send a contractor to do a little drywall underneath both windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that mess finally out of the way, I set to work looking for carpet. For some reason carpet is not very popular in France. Most homes that we have seen use parquet flooring, which can look good if a more expensive option is picked, but in our case the floor was obviously not a real hardwood floor, but rather a cheaper option. Furthermore, I don’t understand the aversion to using carpet in the bedrooms, where they add a soft touch and feel warmer than a cold wooden floor. This is a country where the weather is cold for half of the year, and for three months it’s miserably cold. What little carpet is available is mostly very thin, which feels more appropriate in a commercial setting than in the home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finally finding the carpet I wanted, I was worried about the price but finally made the decision to buy. Of course at this point the carpet was no longer available and the store had completely stopped stocking any more carpet of that particular brand. I despaired of finding something else that I actually wanted to install in my home of all the hundreds of paper-thin and rough carpets to be found on the internet. I was therefore very pleased to find a different store that had something very simiilar to my previous choice, and I bought it immediately. It’s always a bit unsettling to spend over a thousand euros on a single purchase, but after what I had been through, I was ready to pay to get what I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I still had research to do before I could install the carpet. I had considered putting a layer underneath the carpet, primarily for insulation. After searching around and reading  a lot of information on the subject, I came to the conclusion that it wasn’t really necessary, and that the type of carpet that I had chosen could be installed all by itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The installation process itself was not too difficult. The main issue was completely removing everything from each bedroom, one at a time. We removed a sublayer from one of the rooms to find it had been attached by glue, which was now a potent yellow dust that needed to be cleaned up. The other rooms didn’t have this problem, but I did have to almost completely disassemble my daughter’s IKEA bed in order to remove it from the room. The actual installation of the carpet just involved careful measurements and planning for the cuts of the carpet. I knew that I would have to join different cuts in a couple rooms, but I wanted to minimize that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that the work is pretty much done, I’m very happy with the look and feel. Most importantly, everyone is finally back in their own bedrooms for good. I still have some work to do to get a new bed installed for our son and build a wardrobe in our bedroom, but at the very least we have more breathing room now.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">For a long time, the upstairs bedrooms in our house have been unfinished. This is mostly because of a multitide of setbacks, starting with the discovery that we had water damage at two different windows. Including the time needed to find a suitable way to replace the windows as cheaply as possible, the manufacture of the windows, and the delays in the installation process, the replacement of these windows took over a year to complete. Once that was done, we were finally able to get our insurance company to send a contractor to do a little drywall underneath both windows.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Terrorism in Rambouillet</title><link href="/blog/2021/04/terrorism-rambouillet.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Terrorism in Rambouillet" /><published>2021-04-24T10:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-04-24T10:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/04/terrorism-rambouillet</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/04/terrorism-rambouillet.html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday afternoon, a man of Tunisian origin attacked and killed Stephanie, an employee at the Rambouillet police station, with a knife. He cut her throat before being killed by policemen on the scene. I found this to be much more shocking than most news of this type because I am well acquainted with the neighborhood around the police station. Our children’s school is a few hundred yards away. We’ve lived in Rambouillet for almost four years now, and for our town to be in the national spotlight and to make world news, albeit very briefly, for a story like this is actually quite surprising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rambouillet is a town that grew a lot in the twenty years preceding 1990, nearly doubling its size. In the thirty years since then, the town has increased its population by less than ten percent. As a result, the population continues to age. With an aging population comes a statistical tendency to vote for more conservative values and political representatives. As such, François Fillon, the Republican candidate, won the most votes in the first round of the 2017 presidential election, despite accusations of political nepotism, for which he was later convicted. Rambouillet is a town which in my mind aspires to be a miniature Versailles, and the comparison is easy to make. Rambouillet has a large château which was a residence for French royalty, including Marie Antoinette, who loved its large park and its creamery, gifted to her by her husband Louis XVI. In short, it’s not at all a hotspot for violence of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, events of this nature are not really surprising anymore in the Yvelines department as a whole, where the teacher Samuel Paty was infamously beheaded for showing cartoon caricatures depicting Mohammed in his class. Besides that, the town of Trappes has been known as being a hotspot for violence for decades, and is also recognized as having sent a lot of people to fight for the Islamic State relative to the rest of France. There continue to be clashes with police, often including attacks on police cars with rocks, and attacks on the police station with fireworks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a foreigner and a Christian in France, the political repercussions are at the forefront of my mind. It’s clear that President Macron has not become more popular since taking office in 2017, and his path to re-election will be a challenging one. He must convince voters that he deserves re-election in the face of discontent from the more liberal political spectrum, which supported the squashed Yellow Vest movement and strikes, as well as discontent from the more conservative political spectrum, which is not happy about continuing islamist and immigrant violence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continuing violence will probably cause Macron to either lose the election to someone who promises to impliment harsher actions, or Macron will have to implement those actions himself. When that happens, the response is likely to place more restrictions on religious activity in France as a whole, as the response to islamist attacks has been the promotion of secularism. Similarly, the response to immigrant violence is likely to inconvenience us as well, as we are non-European immigrants and France is unlikely to single out specific African and Middle Eastern immigrant groups. In summary, the situation is almost certainly going to get worse before it gets better.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Yesterday afternoon, a man of Tunisian origin attacked and killed Stephanie, an employee at the Rambouillet police station, with a knife. He cut her throat before being killed by policemen on the scene. I found this to be much more shocking than most news of this type because I am well acquainted with the neighborhood around the police station. Our children’s school is a few hundred yards away. We’ve lived in Rambouillet for almost four years now, and for our town to be in the national spotlight and to make world news, albeit very briefly, for a story like this is actually quite surprising.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Robert Massie’s Russian Rulers</title><link href="/blog/2021/03/massies-russian-rulers.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Robert Massie's Russian Rulers" /><published>2021-03-27T14:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-03-27T14:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/03/massies-russian-rulers</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/03/massies-russian-rulers.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve just finished Catherine the Great: Portrait of a Woman by Robert Massie, and since it is the third and final biography of a Russian emperor or empress that I will read, I’d like to dedicate a post to applaud these three great books. The first book written by Massie on the subject was Nicholas and Alexandra, published in 1967. Interestingly, the author became interested in this family when his son was born with hemophilia, a condition which also plagued Nicholas’ son Alexei. The next book, published over a decade later, was the Pulitzer Prize-winning Peter the Great: His Life and World. The final book, published in 2011 when Massie was over eighty years old, was the book on Catherine the Great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I happened to read the books in the order they were published. My memory from my time reading the first book was that the Romanovs were decent people, but they believed that it was their duty to be the rulers of Russia by hereditary right. Nicholas did not come across as haughty or condescending to his subjects. Basically, he was the one who lost the ultimate game of hot potato that occurs when a country does not reform itself enough to avoid a revolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second book on Peter the Great was highly interesting. I find the time period interesting all by itself. When I read a book about someone born in the seventeenth century, I can’t help but think of how much different life would have been like back then. Of course, the most interesting thing about the book was the way it described in detail Peter’s foresight in modernizing Russia, gaining access to the Baltic, creating Saint Petersburg, and reforming religion and culture in his empire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final book on Catherine the Great was great. The character of Catherine was fascinating, and it was enjoyable to read about someone who was in difficulty as a young woman rise from that to a position of power, and to reward those who helped her, and remain benevolent as an autocrat. The fact that Catherine was overwhelmingly a force for good, but that she still failed to ultimately remove serfdom, just goes to show the difficulty in getting things done politically, even as an empress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is obvious that an enormous amount of research went into each book. Each one is quite long. This most recent book took me over a month to finish. But it was worth it to read the whole thing, as Massie doesn’t skip anything. The books all cover the early childhoods of these rulers, and explain the environment at the time and why these people became the people that they became. Reading these biographies, I felt like I was in the heads of these emperors and empresses, and that I understood the various pressures they were under, and how they determined their goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that after reading these books, one of the major takeaways for me was the gladness I feel for not being in a position of power like that. Whatever power that there is to be had, whatever money is available to an emperor, wouldn’t be worth having the family be perpetually in jeopardy of being murdered by someone who wants to take the throne, or put someone else on the throne. Even if there is little danger of that, the entire family dynamic is rarely well-developed in a royal household. Catherine’s own son Paul was taken away from her after his birth, to be raised by her husband’s aunt, the Empress Elizabeth, who was the daughter of Peter the Great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a consequence, Catherine did something similar for the birth of her grandson Alexander. Massie doesn’t mince words when it comes to the things that Peter and Catherine did, despite their greatness. They were still humans, and as such Robert Massie’s books give a great insight into their personalities, and how they shaped the Russian Empire.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">I’ve just finished Catherine the Great: Portrait of a Woman by Robert Massie, and since it is the third and final biography of a Russian emperor or empress that I will read, I’d like to dedicate a post to applaud these three great books. The first book written by Massie on the subject was Nicholas and Alexandra, published in 1967. Interestingly, the author became interested in this family when his son was born with hemophilia, a condition which also plagued Nicholas’ son Alexei. The next book, published over a decade later, was the Pulitzer Prize-winning Peter the Great: His Life and World. The final book, published in 2011 when Massie was over eighty years old, was the book on Catherine the Great.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How Long is the Eastern Continental Trail?</title><link href="/blog/2021/03/ect-distance.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Long is the Eastern Continental Trail?" /><published>2021-03-21T16:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-03-21T16:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/03/ect-distance</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/03/ect-distance.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve finally gotten around to adding an important page to the Eastern Continental Trail website: the route distance &lt;a href=&quot;https://easterncontinentaltrail.com/route/distance&quot;&gt;page&lt;/a&gt;. This page responds to one of the more common questions that I received when I was hiking on the ECT: “How long is that?”. This question really deserved a page of its own, because the answer depends on several factors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, an ECT hiker has several choices to make. Besides the common choice of choosing to travel the trail going North, or to take the path less traveled and head South, there are choices which can actually affect the distance of the hike. First, the Florida Trail includes two basic East-West decisions: Lake Okeechobee and the Central Florida Corridors. Lake Okeechobee is situated in South Florida, and most hikers choose to take the slightly more direct route and travel West around this lake, rather than East, though the difference is a miniscule two miles. In Central Florida, many hikers choose to travel on the Eastern Corridor, which passes through the Northeastern suburbs of Orlando, while others choose the Western Corridor, which is 34 more miles in comparison, and includes the Green Swamp and a path much farther from Orlando.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most trails don’t contain these sorts of options. Besides these two choices, the only other real decision is to determine the Northern Terminus of the hike. The Eastern Continental Trail was originally a hike from Key West to Cap Gaspé in Québec. Since then, the International Appalachian Trail has expanded, and some hikers choose to include the provinces of Prince Edward Island, Nova Scotia, and Newfoundland in their journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So finally, the answer to the question is that the ECT is about 4800 miles (7800 kilometers) when starting or finishing at Cap Gaspé, or 5700 miles (9200 kilometers) when starting or finishing at Crow Head (or Belle Isle) in Northern Newfoundland. These distances should be accurate, as the distances of each component trail have been refined over the years to be more and more accurate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The distance of the Appalachian Trail has been well studied over the years, and is currently measured to be 2193 miles (3537 kilomets), which is almost half of the ECT as it runs between Key West and Cap Gaspé. Likewise, the distances of the other trails is continually being more accurately measured. In my mind, the real question in this area is: what is the most accurate way to measure the distance of the trail. For example, is a detailed GPS track a good source? From what I have seen, the measured distances of the files which exist on the internet are significantly different from those of the published lengths of the trails. For example, I have a Keyhole Markup file for the Appalachian Trail which measures 1970 miles, a full 220 miles of difference, or 10% of the entire trail. Meanwhile, each chapter of the International Appalachian Trail seems to have used the GPS file data as the official distance, as each file matches the reported distance to the kilometer (or mile).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether or not the reported numbers are 99% accurate or just 95% accurate, the page which I have added to the ECT website clearly shows the breakdown of the distance among the ECT’s component trails. Besides the Appalachian Trail, about 1300 miles (2100 kilometers) of distance is in the state of Florida alone. The relative distance of the IAT in proportion to the entire ECT varies greatly depending on the choice to set the Northern Terminus at Newfoundland or Québec. The extra 850 miles (1400 kilometers) makes Newfoundland the province with the most trail distance in the IAT, instead of Québec.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter what choices are made, the Eastern Continental Trail is quite a long trail. I’d pack a lunch.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">I’ve finally gotten around to adding an important page to the Eastern Continental Trail website: the route distance page. This page responds to one of the more common questions that I received when I was hiking on the ECT: “How long is that?”. This question really deserved a page of its own, because the answer depends on several factors.</summary></entry></feed>