<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-15T17:41:55+02:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Sterling Coleman</title><subtitle>A space for my personal projects and thoughts</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Back Home</title><link href="/blog/2020/08/back-home.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Back Home" /><published>2020-08-12T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-08-12T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/08/back-home</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/08/back-home.html">&lt;p&gt;After three weeks in the United States, our little family is back home. We’re happy to be back to our routine, but also sad to have finished a wonderful vacation. The saying “All good things come to an end” is very appropriate to how we feel about finishing a vacation at Higgins Lake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There aren’t many places that can hold our interest for three full weeks, but Higgins Lake does. This year, we had many of our extended family members come at the same time, which made the trip so fun. From my parents, my brother, my grandmother, and my aunt and uncle’s family of five, and even my cousin and her little family, we had so many people at the lake that there was always something happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course it is the people that really make the vacation. We had the cabin to ourselves for a few days, which was fun, but the atmosphere definitely picked up when the rest of the family showed up. We were really happy to have my grandma there, who is of course our children’s great grandmother. With my parents there, that made four generations all together! We enjoyed this opportunity for her to see our youngest child, and for our older child to form a real memory of her, as she is now old enough to recollect this event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our children of course latched on to my cousins, who are in their teenage years. It was a happy moment for me to see them grown up, as I remember when I was their age and they were just infants. Now we are the family with young children, looking forward to having children who are old enough to do more things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They were very gracious, and spent many hours playing with our children, who just wanted to do little kid things. My cousins were great with them, which made us so happy as parents. But after three weeks, it was time for us to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That moment provides a good opportunity for us to evaluate our home life, and how that compares to vacation. I love vacation, and there’s no better place I love to spend my days off than at Higgins Lake, so I had been looking forward to it for a long time. And yet, after three weeks at the lake, I was ready to go home. Higgins Lake is special because we don’t spend all our time there. If we did, over time it would just be a routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We already have a good routine in Rambouillet, and it provides the feeling of home for us. It definitely sets us apart as the family that flies back to France, while many of our extended family drives home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year I made a bit of a mistake by taking long layovers in New York City in both directions of our return trip. We were tired in both instances, and I found that when I am in the focused on Higgins Lake or getting home, I can’t enjoy New York City, especially with two little children in tow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we were the only part of our extended family eligible to cross the Atlantic this summer, with the global pandemic leading European countries to barring American tourism for the time being. As French residents, we were still eligible to travel. We’re happy to be back in our residence where we belong.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">After three weeks in the United States, our little family is back home. We’re happy to be back to our routine, but also sad to have finished a wonderful vacation. The saying “All good things come to an end” is very appropriate to how we feel about finishing a vacation at Higgins Lake.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Destination: Higgins Lake</title><link href="/blog/2020/07/destination-higgins-lake.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Destination: Higgins Lake" /><published>2020-07-27T03:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-07-27T03:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/07/destination-higgins-lake</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/07/destination-higgins-lake.html">&lt;p&gt;Higgins Lake is my favorite destination for a family vacation. I’m currently looking out onto the beautiful lake right now. My family has been coming up here for generations, after an ancestor bought a plot of land up here and built a small cabin about ninety years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the lack of serious improvements made on the property in the near century which followed, I love being here with family in the summer. The most important reason is that my family is here, and that’s something that is not specific to any one place. However, the history of the family coming here almost once a year for many years has built up a lot of great memories and nostalgia in this place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next most important reason, is the water. Simply put, being on the shore of the lake makes all the difference. There is a very soothing breeze which comes right in the window. The water is clear here, and that is something specific to this lake in particular. It’s a beautifully clear lake, not clouded by mud or silt, with a sandy bottom, fed by springs. Obviously, a wonderful lake like that offers opportunities to do every kind of lake boating, fishing, and swimming. I personally love taking a Sunfish sailboat out on windy days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the thing that sets Higgins Lake apart as a top vacation destination for our family is its relative remote location. If this place were in California, Texas, or Florida, it would be swamped with visitors all summer long. The fact that it is instead in Northern Michigan means that it receives mostly weekend boaters coming up from Detroit, and that’s about it. There are plenty of tourists, but it is still a very calm location, a bit of a “hidden gem”. In addition, despite being remote, it is very accessible, right next to an Interstate and a US highway, and not far from towns for groceries or restaurants. Perhaps the only real problem is its distance from major airports: the closest options are Saginaw or Traverse City, the latter having decent seasonal options to arrive from farther away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of all the things that are great about Higgins Lake, meeting up with family is the most important. The pleasure of spending time on the lake is the thing that brings us all together here to spend time with each other. My ideal of a great family vacation is a relaxing time, not necessarily a visit to a big city with a full sight-seeing agenda. Higgins Lake perfectly matches that, which is why I had been looking forward to this trip for so long, and why I have been enjoying my time here.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Higgins Lake is my favorite destination for a family vacation. I’m currently looking out onto the beautiful lake right now. My family has been coming up here for generations, after an ancestor bought a plot of land up here and built a small cabin about ninety years ago.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Development Guide</title><link href="/blog/2020/07/development-guide.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Development Guide" /><published>2020-07-11T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-07-11T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/07/development-guide</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/07/development-guide.html">&lt;p&gt;As a software engineer, one of my pet peeves is dealing with the almighty developer guide. This document exists at almost every software company as an aid for developer writing code. Among other things, it outlines rules for the formatting of code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These guides are important, and necessary, if mainly as a learning tool for developers to recognize features of the tools and languages used. The guide also serves as a warning against potentially undesirable side effects or pitfalls which may not be obvious at first glance. Used in the right way, developers can learn and debate the merits of developing a certain way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, too often the developer guide becomes a way for one person to decide every detail of how the code should look. The guide then goes beyond merely avoiding bad code construction, and delves into enforcing the spacing of the code, the format, and many tiny details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have actually heard people defend developer guide rules such as “The code should be self-evident and have minimal comments”. The next day I’ll be attempting to understand several portions of code which appear to me to be hopelessly tangled. After 30 minutes spent analyzing 50 lines of code, I opt to ask the developer who wrote the code three months ago what it does, and he will spend another thirty minutes deciphering it all over again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The silly developer guide rules don’t help. To me, the developer guide should primarily be used to avoid problems. Very few projects suffer from too many comments in the code. This rule just served to pump our egos up in thinking we were putting out code so good it didn’t need comments, which was not true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intertwined in the developer guide are the tools which are often used to enforce good coding practices. This could be a helpful thing to have in the project, but it all depends on the tool used, and how it is used. I once worked on a project that used a project called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/standard/standard&quot;&gt;standard&lt;/a&gt;. I had a real problem with it. The philosophy behind it was that instead of debating the merits of one way of doing things over another, this tool would simply set the terms. At best, we could ignore a rule in certain cases. There was no customization beyond that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of this centralized dictatorship of code formatting, consider the well-known tool &lt;a href=&quot;https://eslint.org/&quot;&gt;ESLint&lt;/a&gt;, which allows for extensize configuration, as well as having an option to use a list of recommended rules, to facilitate a quick start when desired. I think that the time spent discussing these points is important. It gets developers in the mindset of developing in an abstract, flexible fashion that allows a team to work on the same code seamlessly. The goal shouldn’t be to remove individual creativity, but rather to encourage it when it makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the age-old debate of Tabs vs Spaces is an example of this difference of philosophy. It makes no sense to me that there seem to be more developers who prefer to indent their code using spaces as opposed to tabs. This might have made sense over ten years ago, when some text editors didn’t have proper configuration options for indentation. Now I can configure any respectable editor to display a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;TAB&lt;/code&gt; character as a certain number of columns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what is the debate? If I want my editor to use 17 columns for every &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;TAB&lt;/code&gt; character, that’s my business. When I commit the code to the repository, someone else can grab it and use their own configuration to determine how many columns a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;TAB&lt;/code&gt; character uses. That’s the flexible option. Using spaces just means that we can mandate 2-space indentation, and use that to attempt to develop code with too many nested levels of logic to be easy comprehensible. Let’s stop micromanaging developers and instead just mark the danger areas and let them be free otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">As a software engineer, one of my pet peeves is dealing with the almighty developer guide. This document exists at almost every software company as an aid for developer writing code. Among other things, it outlines rules for the formatting of code.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">End of the 2020 School Year</title><link href="/blog/2020/07/end-of-school.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="End of the 2020 School Year" /><published>2020-07-04T18:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-07-04T18:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/07/end-of-school</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/07/end-of-school.html">&lt;p&gt;Today is July 4th, Independence Day in the United States. As an American abroad, I hadn’t even realized it was Independence Day, as it is not a holiday here in France. One of the more minor problems of living abroad is that you miss out on your usual holidays, and you don’t have the same habit of celebrating new national holidays in your place of residence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before July 4th was Friday, July 3rd, the last day of the tumultuous 2019-2020 school year. When I look back on the school year, I can see that we were luckier than most, in having a mere two months (not including the French Easter holiday of two weeks) cut from the school calendar because of COVID-19. In some states in the US, schools didn’t meet at all for the remainder of the school year once initially suspended in-school classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, we stopped sending our child to school in the middle of March, but were able to send her back at the beginning of June for two days a week, and then had a full French schedule of four days a week for the final two weeks, until July 3rd. Having our four-year-old Miriam at home during that whole time probably didn’t help to foster her independence, but she grew a lot during the year nevertheless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In France, there are three years of what Americans might call preschool, which are actually part of the public school system. For the 2017-2018 school year, &lt;a href=&quot;https://fr.statista.com/statistiques/499756/taux-scolarisation-france-par-age/&quot;&gt;97.2% of 3-year-olds&lt;/a&gt; were in school in France. Since then, school has become mandatory for 3-year-olds. This first year was a difficult period for our child, as she had to learn to fully communicate in French for the first time. This past year, the second, was much easier, and turned out to be a huge period of growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of constantly being worried about school and being away from her mother, we got to see Miriam be happy to go to school in the morning, and more willing to talk about her day once she got home. This is in part thanks to two consecutive years of hard work by great teachers, who take in 30 small children and somehow develop each one during the course of the year. Our teacher was fluent in both English in French, which was a big boost for us, and helped Miriam cope with the separation of her best friend from the previous year, who was in a different class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, our decision to put Miriam in a private French Catholic school has turned out well. Though not specifically Catholic ourselves, Miriam gets the opportunity to learn about Christianity from her teachers and the school priest, and surprises us with how much she knows when she gets home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She is still a young child, but now she has left infancy behind for good. She does a great job taking care of her younger brother, and is starting to accept our authority as parents. She can understand basic logic and can see that accept that she can be wrong sometimes, and changes her attitude and apologizes accordingly. This is a big step from the stubborn behavior she naturally exhibited in the prior year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been a pleasure to watch her grow up, and we look forward to even bigger changes next year, as she starts the final year of preschool, equivalent to Kindergarten in the United States. It is difficult to believe that all the work we have put in as parents and all the growth we have seen has been in a portio of her life that she may not remember much at all as an adult. And yet, if she can do so much now as she nears her fifth birthday, we can only imagine the development that will come to pass in the years to come.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Today is July 4th, Independence Day in the United States. As an American abroad, I hadn’t even realized it was Independence Day, as it is not a holiday here in France. One of the more minor problems of living abroad is that you miss out on your usual holidays, and you don’t have the same habit of celebrating new national holidays in your place of residence.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Routing the Northern Divide Trail</title><link href="/blog/2020/06/routing-northern-divide-trail.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Routing the Northern Divide Trail" /><published>2020-06-27T13:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-06-27T13:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/06/routing-northern-divide-trail</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/06/routing-northern-divide-trail.html">&lt;p&gt;Of all the resources I have prepared for the Northern Divide Trail, the most important is probably the Keyhold Markup File (KML/KMZ) which I have created using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/earth/&quot;&gt;Google Earth&lt;/a&gt;. If an explorer were to upload this file to a GPS receiver, possibly by converting it to GPS Exchange Format (GPX), then the person would be able to follow the trail with high precision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this assumes that a person is capable of walking the line defined by this resource. Therein lies the difficulty of blazing a new trail. It is easy to create a theoretical path between two points, but much more difficult to fit that path to the constraints of thru-hiking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main difficulty posed is that of the extreme difficulty of the terrain of the Northern Rocky Mountains. Many of the mountains encountered are steep, and sometimes taking a detour would mean a large increase in the hiking distance, as well as bypassing interesting and notable features that an explorer does not want to miss. See this table for a tangible account of the total elevation change of the NDT compared to other notable trails:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Trail&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Distance (km)&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Total Elevation Change (km)&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Average Elevation Change (%)&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Appalachian&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;3530&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;312&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;8.9&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Great Divide&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;1130&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;42&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;3.7&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Northern Divide&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;1000&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;130&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Northern Divide Trail packs almost as much elevation change as the Appalachian Trail (which itself averages more change per mile than both the Pacific Crest and Continentail Divide Trails) into less than a third of the distance of the Appalachian Trail. It is a relatively short but extremely difficult trail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, I have put constraints on the Keyhole Markup File which defines the route in minute detail, in an attempt to tone down the difficulty. First, I have divided the route into days, and all days are no greater than 40 kilometers, which is less than the 50+ kilometers that I typically hiked on the AT. I also set a maximum slope of 50% on the entire route, meaning that at all times, a person will not be taking on more than a 45° angle. This is still a steep slope, and when taken for a long distance, can be quite exhausting. Switchbacks are sometimes employed to satisy this constraint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I have endeavored to reduce the total amount of elevation change by routing the trail through valleys and low elevatio areas when possible. Unfortunately, this is difficult and not possible on a large scale without taking the trail out of the mountains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Muskwa Ranges, specifically the Akie Range and the Sentinel Range, contain the most elevation change, though the area around Mount Crysdale, in the Misinchinka Ranges, is also very demanding. Beyond that, the highest point on the trail (2632 meters) is located at a pass near Ithaca Glacier and Mount Ulysses. The trail continues to approach this altitude father North. The entirety of the Sentinel Range, at the most northern section of the Rocky Mountains, poses a serious challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Northernmost portion of the trail makes routing difficult, as the mountains therein are not only steep, but appear to be barren and smooth rock. This makes the common technique of using switchbacks much less effective, and the threat of a possibly fatal slip very serious. The area around Nonda Peak continues to pose a challenge for the creation of a plausible route for the trail. The NDT aspires to explore the most prominent features of the Northern Rocky Mountains, but there must also be a consideration for safety.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Of all the resources I have prepared for the Northern Divide Trail, the most important is probably the Keyhold Markup File (KML/KMZ) which I have created using Google Earth. If an explorer were to upload this file to a GPS receiver, possibly by converting it to GPS Exchange Format (GPX), then the person would be able to follow the trail with high precision.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Trailblazing the Northern Divide</title><link href="/blog/2020/06/trailblazing-northern-divide.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Trailblazing the Northern Divide" /><published>2020-06-21T01:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-06-21T01:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/06/trailblazing-northern-divide</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/06/trailblazing-northern-divide.html">&lt;p&gt;After finishing my Eastern Continental Trail hike, I had many ideas. I wanted to hike across America, I wanted to kayak, and as I had hiked the ECT, I had fantasized about all the things I wanted to do. Finishing my hike, I decided to go in a different direction, but still had a passion for exploration. I took a step back and decided I was most interested in big mountain ranges. In North America, none is longer than the Rocky Mountains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Americans, hiking the Rocky Mountains means the &lt;a href=&quot;https://continentaldividetrail.org/&quot;&gt;Continental Divide Trail&lt;/a&gt; (CDT), one of the three trails required to attain the famed Triple Crown of North American hiking. Yet, the CDT is not a trail which spans the Rocky Mountains. It is a trail which spans the United States, with each terminus being on a border with Mexico and Canada, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://greatdividetrail.com/&quot;&gt;Great Divide Trail&lt;/a&gt; (GDT) has been revived. This is a trail touching the American border at the Northern Terminus of the CDT, and stretching North to Lake Kakwa. This is a difficult and beautiful trail. Maintainers appear to have put a lot of hard work into this trail, and it has shown in the trail’s rising popularity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yet, the GDT does not cover the entire Canadian portion of the Rocky Mountains. The Rocky Mountains are officially bounded by the Liard River to the North. The mountain ranges north of the Liard River are part of the American Cordillera, but are not part of the Rocky Mountains. The distance between the Liard River and Kakwa Lake is vast and virtually uninhabited. To cover this distance would be a real exploration. This is my idea for the &lt;a href=&quot;/exploration/northern-divide-trail&quot;&gt;Northern Divide Trail&lt;/a&gt; (NDT).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have put a lot of time into researching the route and documenting this proposed trail. As of right now, the top priority is coming up with a better strategy for resupplying in between Chetwynd and Toad River. This will probably be a long walk into Pink Mountain. The next priority is a review of the proposed trail to ensure that none of the proposed terrain is too steep or dangerous, and if there are doubts on this point, to create alternate routes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is still much work to be done, but I have created a solid base proposal. I hope that what I have started can make for a discussion among those who have more knowledge on the subject and who are in a better position to advance this proposal.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">After finishing my Eastern Continental Trail hike, I had many ideas. I wanted to hike across America, I wanted to kayak, and as I had hiked the ECT, I had fantasized about all the things I wanted to do. Finishing my hike, I decided to go in a different direction, but still had a passion for exploration. I took a step back and decided I was most interested in big mountain ranges. In North America, none is longer than the Rocky Mountains.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Zeihan on Geopolitics</title><link href="/blog/2020/06/peter-zeihan.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Zeihan on Geopolitics" /><published>2020-06-13T18:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-06-13T18:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/06/peter-zeihan</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/06/peter-zeihan.html">&lt;p&gt;About a year ago, I somehow came across some content put out by Peter Zeihan. I believe it was a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC0vqqjAyPXP1BSvbFwZi_pA/&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; video of him talking to an audience at some sort of economic forum. His YouTube channel doesn’t have any new content, but other people have uploaded many of his appearances at various economic forums or corporate events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter Zeihan is a geopolitical analyst with decades of experience who makes his living as an author of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Peter-Zeihan/e/B00MPX86VK%3Fref=dbs_a_mng_rwt_scns_share&quot;&gt;books&lt;/a&gt;, as well as doing presentations for corporate audiences. He got my attention because of the relatively flashy nature of his presentation compared to the traditionally dry fare which seems to be a common theme in geopolitical analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Zeihan’s predictions kept my attention and impressed me. I would consider making predictions a dangerous game, as a failed prediction could disgrace an analyst. Zeihan makes many predictions. Off the top of my head, some of his more memorable ones are that the People’s Republic of China will no longer be a unified country in a matter of years (I believe 10?), that the European Union would break up in approximately the same time frame, that the Russian Federation would attempt to expand their borders to previous geographical anchors (meaning attacking Ukraine and other Eastern European countries), and just the general statement that we are currently undergoing a transition as important as the European discovery of the American continent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With so many predictions, many people have discredited Peter Zeihan as being too bold. I myself think that he goes one step too far in predicting specific wars, such as an East Asian war and an Eastern European war. I think the nature of war is too unpredictable, and despite Mr. Zeihan’s clear demonstration of the situation providing conditions for a war to be launched, it is not possible to make a prediction on that subject with any degree of certainty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think most of the other predictions that Zeihan makes are very likely to occur, and I think he has a good track record, having done basically the exact same presentation to his audience for several years. It is just now, at the end of 2019 and the beginning of 2020, that some of the chaos that he has been predicting has gotten started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an American living in France, his prediction that the United States will be sitting at the top of the world for the foreseeable future, with France perhaps in second place (though a relatively distant second), is a welcome one. But whatever a person may say about his predictions, it is impossible to my mind to argue the facts which form the basis of these conclusions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The United States is one of the only developed countries with decently young demographics (France being the other notable case)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The United States just recently became energy independent thanks to the Shale Revolution, which shows no signs of slowing down in the long term despite setbacks in the short term&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The United States is pulling back from the world stage because of its energy independence, its changing internal politics, and its realization that its foreign policy as an engaged superpower no longer serves the purpose for which it was put in place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter Zeihan’s conclusion, therefore, is that the United States is removing itself from the world stage, and all the countries (and people) who have been profiting from its protection will suffer a reset to whatever natural position those places can sustain without the Americans. For some places, this could be famine. It’s certainly a grave picture, and one which I think demands attention in order to be informed enough to atleast understand the argument behind Zeihan’s position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My final conclusion is that Zeihan is basically right, and that the USA will become isolated to the North American continent, and that the world at large will suffer. One subject that Peter Zeihan does not cover as in-depth, however, is the effect on many individuals in places like the United States or France, where the country may have high relative power, but may also receive many immigrants. That is a personal subject which I have been dwelling over for some months, and continue to do so.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">About a year ago, I somehow came across some content put out by Peter Zeihan. I believe it was a YouTube video of him talking to an audience at some sort of economic forum. His YouTube channel doesn’t have any new content, but other people have uploaded many of his appearances at various economic forums or corporate events.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to the Redesign!</title><link href="/blog/2020/05/redesign.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to the Redesign!" /><published>2020-05-02T20:18:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-05-02T20:18:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/05/redesign</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/05/redesign.html">&lt;p&gt;Recently I’ve been thinking about updating my personal site. In truth, I’ve been meaning to do something with the site on and off for a year or more, but just never got around to it. This post marks the first post of the complete redesign of the entire site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously, the site was created with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.joomla.org/&quot;&gt;Joomla&lt;/a&gt;, a Content Management System which was easy enough to use. It was never difficult to add posts, create updates, or publish in multiple languages. In fact, the ability to make different versions of the same post in different langugages and link them was one of my favorite feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When considering the redesign, I initially was thinking of a full-fledged website with either Angular or React in the front end. I quickly realized this was not necessary as I wasn’t going to need a back end at all, and therefore really just needed to serve static content. From there I started looking into &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt;, which is by far the market leader of the Content Management Systems. However, WordPress is written in PHP, which was also the case for Joomla and doesn’t hold a lot of interest for me. I found other CMSs which are written in nodeJS, but I decided that ultimately wasn’t what I wanted because most were obscure compared to WordPress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I started looking into popular static site generators. I ended up settling on &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; for a couple reasons. Most importantly, it has been created by a co-founder of Github and interfaces very well with &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;. Using Jekyll is a great opportunity for me to learn more about Github Pages, which I otherwise wouldn’t be able to do with other projects which require a backend and are thus not ideal for Github Pages. I also like being able to submit posts and pages in a simple markdown format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also allows me to learn about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruby-lang.org/&quot;&gt;Ruby&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://yaml.org/&quot;&gt;YAML&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://shopify.github.io/liquid/&quot;&gt;Liquid&lt;/a&gt;. I’m just getting into basic Jekyll subjects such as  front-matter, layouts, and themes, but I’m enjoying the relatively easy learning curve. To me it feels right as an engineer to move away from the Content Management Systems and get into something more akin to a development environment, even for creating simple blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I’m going to enjoy learning how to customize the look of the site. I’d like to explore things like integrating maps, media files, or scripted content. I may get into some Ruby for the more complicated components, and that could be fun too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that you find the new design easy to use. If you see important improvements that could be made, please do contact me. I’m always looking for another perspective in development.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">Recently I’ve been thinking about updating my personal site. In truth, I’ve been meaning to do something with the site on and off for a year or more, but just never got around to it. This post marks the first post of the complete redesign of the entire site.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Consequences of Good and Evil</title><link href="/blog/2017/03/consequences.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Consequences of Good and Evil" /><published>2017-03-18T12:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-03-18T12:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2017/03/consequences</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2017/03/consequences.html">&lt;p&gt;In a recent blog post I wrote my thoughts on the concepts of good and evil, and explained why I think it is irrefutable that these things exist, and most importantly, are not merely natural or earthly ideas, but are indeed supernatural. Having laid the foundation for a topic more relevant to my daily life and existence as a human being, I would like to discuss the consequences of good and evil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all, if good and evil have no consequences at all, then they are of little interest. If a human does nothing but good, and their results are the same as another human who does evil, then effectively good and evil have no meaning. Of course we know that this is not the case. In our natural world we know that every action has a consequence. We can see that when we push a rock, it moves, and when we chop a tree, it falls. Actions cause reactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this same vein of thought, we know that human actions have consequences as well. For example, if I do not say anything to my wife on our anniversary, the consequence is that my wife will be unhappy. And in that example the consequence of my actions would affect me as I would be forced to buy extravagant gifts in an attempt to bribe my way back into her good favor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So knowing that our actions have natural consequences, do they have supernatural consequences as well? I believe that I have something ingrained in me by my very nature as a human being which knows that there are indeed supernatural consequences for my actions. I believe that this is an important part of what we often call our “conscience”. This part of me knows that there is such a concept as justice, and that if this justice were able to be evaded, that it would not be an ultimate or perfect justice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, it is conceivable that I could tell a lie that no one else could detect. This lie could end up having absolutely no effect in the natural world, either on others or myself. If that were to happen, would I have successfully committed an action with evil intentions, and not received any form of justice? I believe that the answer must be no, and that the proof lies in my conscience, some part of me given a supernatural design which knows the meaning of good and evil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, my actions in the natural world are done with intentions, which are themselves a supernatural concept. These intentions define whether my actions are good or evil, but these intentions cannot be observed naturally, as we have only supporting evidence and logic to suggest a person’s intentions. Therefore there must be a supernatural observation of these intentions, and supernatural consequences following the result of this observation. Otherwise, justice does not exist, as justice means that every human being is observed and obtains their results equally, with no room for bribery or evasion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As is our nature as humans, we often attempt to avoid the consequences of our actions. A common tactic is to claim that our intentions were not bad. I could try to explain to my wife that I simply forgot our anniversary, and that I wasn’t trying to hurt her feelings. In that way I can hope to classify my actions as some type of benign negligence, and not something more malicious. This tactic is very prevalent because we presume that no one can know our intentions except for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the most important topic regarding the consequences of good and evil is the relation between the two. Specifically, how does good weigh against evil, or do the two concepts not balance each other in some way? Most relevantly to humans, can a human being commit an evil act, and negate the consequences with some type of good act?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a hot topic for human beings. We see that we do evil, and we don’t like it. It is in our nature to want to fix this problem on our own. The idea of being observed and judged supernaturally is uncomfortable and even frightening. From this, humans have written many theories concerning how a good action can negate an evil one. Fasting, self-flagellation, monetary payments and indulgences, specific prayers, and other similar things are all being used by various cultures and religious beliefs in an attempt to undo what we have done, or at least undo the consequences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scary truth is that we cannot undo the consequences of evil, because the consequences of good are not a bonus or some kind of extra credit. Our actions are not a mathematical equation which can be balanced, but rather markings recorded in these two simple categories. The easiest way to understand this is by examining our own laws, which we have created based off of our consciences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do not murder because we know that it is wrong. There is a punishment for murder, but there is no specific reward for not committing murder. Likewise, there is no specific reward for doing extra nice things such as helping an elderly person with their groceries. Following the law is what is expected of us. Breaking the law has consequences. If we break the speed limit, we receive a ticket. We do not receive cash in hand for following the posted speed limit. Similarly, we cannot pay for our evil deeds with our good deeds, as committing an evil deed means breaking a supernatural law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This leaves us in a frightening state. No person can rightly claim to have never committed evil. No one has always had good intentions, and therefore we all ought to be worried about the consequences of our actions. Most frighteningly, there is nothing that we can do, through bribery, evasion, or self-denial that can negate these consequences. This ought to open our eyes to our sad state of affairs, and lead us to seek more information, and hopefully find a solution to this problem.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">In a recent blog post I wrote my thoughts on the concepts of good and evil, and explained why I think it is irrefutable that these things exist, and most importantly, are not merely natural or earthly ideas, but are indeed supernatural. Having laid the foundation for a topic more relevant to my daily life and existence as a human being, I would like to discuss the consequences of good and evil.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Outside the Anglosphere</title><link href="/blog/2017/02/anglosphere.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Outside the Anglosphere" /><published>2017-02-08T12:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-02-08T12:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2017/02/anglosphere</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2017/02/anglosphere.html">&lt;p&gt;This week, I’d like to put down my opinion on the vacation and immigration habits of many of my fellow American citizens. As someone who is highly interested in learning foreign languages and living in other countries, I realize that my opinion and experience and not that of the typical American. I hope that this will bring some value to what I have to say and yet that as an American I give my opinion not to belittle or unnecessarily criticize Americans, but rather to make us better through correction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I scan my social media feeds, I see lots of great photos of beautiful places and sites from around the world. And yet, the sampling that I have comes mostly from English-speaking countries. Don’t get me wrong, I enjoy seeing photos from New York City and London, but after a while I’m hoping that we start venturing outside our comfort zones a bit more than a trip to England.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As English-speakers we have the obvious blessing of natively speaking the language used foremost in global communications. In the business world, and in tourism, and in entertainment media, English is by far the preferred language of use. However, this blessing is an obvious curse in that it gives us a sufficiently large comfort zone that many of use never attempt to break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The topic is easily seen when a large portion of the American populous entertains the idea, whether seriously or not, of immigration. This happens occasionally during crises, but most recently during the presidential election. There were many talking of immigrating, including celebrities. Of course, very few of these people would be able to successfully immigrate in the way that they imagine, but that is another subject. So, what country does the typical American think of immigrating to? Canada!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are reasons to immigrate to Canada, but the obvious reason that so many Americans pick Canada as their first choice is that they are looking for something as similar as possible to their previous experience. And Canada definitely fits that description. In behavior, accent, culture, and almost every observable way, Canadians as people and Canada as a country are very similar to Americans and the United States. And while that makes the move and assimilation process seamless, it removes one of the main benefits of immigration, or even tourism, which is that of expanding one’s horizons and experiencing new things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I consider life experience to be very important in gaining both knowledge and wisdom. Obviously, a person who spends their whole life in one village only knows how things work in their town, and has no real experience outside of it. The same can be said for someone who has spent their whole life in America.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I’m not suggesting that someone who spends their whole life in America is not smart or is somehow below-average, as this is indeed the experience of the typical American. However, if one lives their whole life in America, they are only getting the American viewpoint on everything they do. They experience education in America, an American career, an American family setting, the American healthcare system, etc. How can this person say that the way that business works in America is the best if they have never been abroad? They cannot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, Americans are very lucky because in my opinion, America does most things very well, if not the best in the world. As such, Americans do not need to travel abroad to experience many great things. However, we shouldn’t take this for granted, as nothing is permanent, and the process of globalization has allowed much of the world to catch up in many areas of development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just want to encourage Americans and other English-speakers to realize that the English-speaking world is not the whole world, and the rest of the world is worth a trip at least as a tourist, if you are not interested in immigration. Taking a trip from America to Canada is like switching from CranApple to CranGrape juice, and going to the United Kingdom is very similar. Yes, there are differences between these places, but there is a whole world of options outside of these places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The worst thing that can happen is that you go abroad and realize that you love America the most for what it is. At least at that point, you will know why America is great for you, and you will not take for granted things that you missed in other places. And that is fine. But we can’t say that America is best for us when we haven’t tried anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But you may in fact find that there are things that you appreciate about other countries that America is lacking. Personally, I have really come to appreciate the manner of dress and level of fitness that the French maintain. I don’t feel good wearing sweatpants outside of the house here in France, whereas in America I remember occasionally seeing people out on the town in their pajamas. And for the other point, really it is just more uplifting to be around other people who have no obvious weight issues and seem to be taking care of their health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I should add that I understand that learning another language is hard, and takes dedication. The good news is that for most places, a phrasebook, a good attitude, and sometimes a lot of non-verbal communication are enough. But certainly, for immigration, you have to learn the native language. Don’t be fooled by the fact that many European countries have good levels of English. If you want to assimilate, make friends, understand the humor, and be more like the natives, you need to speak their language. And when you do, you will be very proud of yourself, and will have brightened your own future and perhaps that of your family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that this has not been too discouraging to any Americans getting ready to go abroad to other English-speaking countries. There are a lot of great things to see and do in the English-speaking world, but it has also all been done before by every other English-speaking tourist. Immigration to Australia has been very high lately, as it is a warm Anglophonic country. Enjoy your trip to New Zealand, but do realize that it is not that far off the beaten path, and that that there are other places just as exciting and beautiful out in the non-English speaking world. So let go of your comfort zone and experience something really new.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;&quot;Follower, Husband, Father, Explorer&quot;, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;&quot;Paris&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;contact@sterlingcoleman.com&quot;, &quot;links&quot;=&gt;[{&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;GitHub&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-github&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://github.com/Belteshazzar89&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;LinkedIn&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-linkedin&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://linkedin.com/in/sterlingcoleman&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Reddit&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-reddit&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://reddit.com/user/Belteshazzar89/&quot;}, {&quot;label&quot;=&gt;&quot;Steam&quot;, &quot;icon&quot;=&gt;&quot;fab fa-fw fa-steam&quot;, &quot;url&quot;=&gt;&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/id/belteshazzar89&quot;}]}</name><email>contact@sterlingcoleman.com</email></author><summary type="html">This week, I’d like to put down my opinion on the vacation and immigration habits of many of my fellow American citizens. As someone who is highly interested in learning foreign languages and living in other countries, I realize that my opinion and experience and not that of the typical American. I hope that this will bring some value to what I have to say and yet that as an American I give my opinion not to belittle or unnecessarily criticize Americans, but rather to make us better through correction.</summary></entry></feed>